I'M A
17-YEAR-OLD
STUDENT WHO
RECENTLY MOVED
FROM ABROAD TO
ATTEND HIGH SCHOOL
IN THE U .S.
AND FROM
DAY ONE MY
NAME BECAME AN
ISSUE.
WHEN I INTRODUCED
MYSELF, CLASSMATES
IMMEDIATELY STRUGGLED
WITH IT AND DECIDED
IT WAS TOO
COMPLICATED.
WITHOUT ASKING,
THEY PICKED A
SIMPLER, MORE
AMERICAN-SOUNDING
NAME AND STARTED
USING THAT
INSTEAD.
WHAT SURPRISED
ME MOST
IS HOW FAST
IT STUCK. NOW
ALMOST EVERYONE,
INCLUDING A
COUPLE OF TEACHERS,
CALLS ME
THIS SUBSTITUTE NAME
AS IF IT WERE MINE.
I'VE TRIED
HANDLING IT
CALMLY.
I'VE
EXPLAINED MORE
THAN ONCE THAT
I DON'T CARE IF
PEOPLE MISPRONOUNCE
MY NAME OR
SPELL IT WRONG.
AS LONG
AS THEY ACTUALLY
USE IT. I'VE
SAID THIS POLITELY.
WITHOUT SNAPPING
OR EMBARRASSING
ANYONE.
INSTEAD OF
ADJUSTING.
A LOT OF
PEOPLE REACTED
WITH EYE ROLLS
AND SARCASM.
AND SOME EVEN
ESCALATED
IT BY DELIBERATELY
CALLING ME
OTHER RANDOM NAMES
JUST TO GET
UNDER MY SKIN.
THE FRUSTRATING
PART IS
THAT.
ASIDE FROM
THIS.
I GENUINELY
GET ALONG WITH
MY CLASSMATES. THEY'RE
FRIENDLY.
THEY JOKE
WITH ME. AND
THEY DON'T SEEM
HOSTILE.
BUT THIS ONE
ISSUE KEEPS
COMING UP
AND MAKES ME FEEL
DISMISSED.
IT'S NO LONGER
ABOUT PRONUNCIATION
OR CONVENIENCE.
IT FEELS
LIKE MY IDENTITY
IS BEING TREATED
AS OPTIONAL.
LIKE SOMETHING
THAT CAN BE RENAMED
FOR OTHER PEOPLE'S
COMFORT.
AM I OVERREACTING
FOR WANTING MY
ACTUAL NAME
TO BE RESPECTED?
OR IS IT
REASONABLE TO
EXPECT PEOPLE
TO CALL ME WHAT
I'M ACTUALLY CALLED?