I, 20M,
HAVE A FRIEND,
24M,
WHO STREAMS ON
TWITCH.
HE'S BEEN TRYING
TO TURN STREAMING
INTO A CAREER,
AND WE'VE
BEEN FRIENDS FOR
ALMOST THREE YEARS.
WE MET
THROUGH GAMING, AND
EVEN THOUGH WE LIVE
IN DIFFERENT COUNTRIES,
WE'VE ONLY
SEEN EACH OTHER
TWICE IN PERSON.
GAMING HAS
ALWAYS BEEN OUR
BOND.
TODAY, HE
WAS LIVESTREAMING
WHILE PLAYING APEX
LEGENDS, ONE
OF HIS FAVORITE
COMPETITIVE SHOOTERS.
AND I COULD
TELL HE WAS STRESSED
FROM ALL THE
CHAOS IN GAME.
GAME.
AFTER A
WHILE, HE
SAID HE WANTED
A BREAK FROM
MULTIPLAYER MADNESS
AND WANTED
TO PLAY SOMETHING SINGLE
PLAYER.
I SUGGESTED
STARDEW
VALLEY, A
CHILL, RELAXING
GAME I
THOUGHT HE'D ENJOY.
HE RELUCTANTLY
AGREED, CLEARLY
ANNOYED, SAYING,
FINE, I'LL
TRY IT. BUT
FROM THE MOMENT
HE LAUNCHED THE
GAME, IT
BECAME A NIGHTMARE.
HE STARTED
TRASHING IT
TO HUNDREDS OF
VIEWERS.
LOOK HOW
FUN THIS IS.
NAH, BRO,
HOW DO PEOPLE
EVEN ENJOY
THIS?
AND, I
SWEAR, I'D
RATHER GRIND FORTNITE
ALL DAY THEN
DO THIS. HIS
CHAT PILED
ON, MAKING
JOKES ABOUT
HIM BEING BORED
AND AGREEING WITH
EVERY SARCASTIC
COMMENT.
THEN HE
WENT AFTER ME
PERSONALLY.
HE SAID
THINGS LIKE, I'M
STUCK PLAYING THIS
GARBAGE BECAUSE
OF MY FRIEND
AND, I
DON'T KNOW WHAT KIND
OF WEIRDOS
LIKE THIS GAME,
CLEARLY REFERENCING
ME WITHOUT NAMING
ME.
I FELT
HUMILIATED,
I HAD INVITED
HIM TO PLAY
A GAME I GENUINELY
THOUGHT WE
COULD ENJOY TOGETHER.
AND INSTEAD,
HE WAS PUBLICLY
BLAMING ME
TO HUNDREDS OF
PEOPLE.
AFTER THE
TUTORIAL, I
STAYED SILENT
FOR A FEW MINUTES.
BUT I COULDN'T
TAKE IT ANYMORE.
I TYPED INTO
HIS CHAT. THANKS
FOR HUMILIATING
ME AND MAKING
ME FEEL BAD
FOR INVITING YOU
TO PLAY. REALLY
APPRECIATE IT.
THE CHAT WENT
COMPLETELY SILENT.
HE MUTTERED.
I DON'T WANT
TO DEAL WITH THIS
RIGHT NOW. I'M
SHUTTING THE STREAM
OFF AND CLOSE
THE STREAM MID
PLAY.
LATER HE
MESSAGED ME
ANGRILY SAYING
I RUINED
THE STREAM
AND THAT I
NEEDED TO LEARN
TO TAKE A JOKE
BECAUSE IT'S JUST
A GAME. I
DON'T SEE IT THAT
WAY.
I DIDN'T
INSULT HIM
OR THE GAME. I
ONLY CALLED OUT
HOW I WAS BEING
TREATED.
I FEEL
LIKE I DEFENDED
MYSELF IN
FRONT OF HUNDREDS
OF VIEWERS WHO
HAD BEEN WATCHING
ME BE BLAMED
UNFAIRLY
BUT NOW I'M
LEFT WONDERING
DID
I OVERREACT
AND RUIN HIS
STREAM OR
WAS I JUSTIFIED
IN STANDING
UP FOR MYSELF
IN FRONT OF
EVERYONE