I'M 21
AND MY YOUNGER
BROTHER IS
19.
HE'S ALWAYS
BEEN A VERY
HEAVY
SLEEPER.
EVEN AS
A KID, OUR
PARENTS HAD
TO PRACTICALLY
DRAG HIM
OUT OF
BED.
LATELY,
HE'S BEEN
WORKING AT
A RETAIL JOB
HE REALLY
LIKES.
BUT HE
STARTED FALLING
BACK ASLEEP
AFTER HIS
ALARM.
WHICH
HAS CAUSED
HIM TO BE LATE
A FEW
TIMES.
EVEN
THOUGH WE SLEEP
IN SEPARATE ROOMS,
I CAN
USUALLY HEAR
HIS
ALARM.
AND IN THE
PAST I'VE
HAD TO GO INTO
HIS ROOM
TO GET HIM
MOVING.
A WHILE
BACK, HE
ASKED ME
IF I COULD START
CHECKING ON
HIM TO MAKE SURE
HE ACTUALLY
GETS UP FOR
WORK.
I
TOLD HIM
NO I
FEEL LIKE
ONCE HIS ALARM
GOES OFF
IT'S
HIS RESPONSIBILITY
I
ALSO DON'T
WANT TO TAKE ON
THAT RESPONSIBILITY
IF
I AGREED AND
HE WAS STILL LATE
HE
MIGHT BLAME
ME I
WANT HIM TO
LEARN TO MANAGE
HIS OWN SCHEDULE
I
MENTIONED IT
TO MY MOM
AND
SHE SAID IT
WOULD BE A KIND
GESTURE TO
CHECK ON HIM
IF I'M ALREADY
AWAKE I
USUALLY TRY
TO GO BACK
TO SLEEP WHEN
HIS ALARM RINGS
BUT I
CAN SEE HER
POINT STILL
I
FEEL LIKE
I'M SETTING A
REASONABLE BOUNDARY
BECAUSE HE'S
AN ADULT NOW
AND NEEDS TO
TAKE OWNERSHIP
OF
GETTING UP ON
TIME