I'M
23 AND
SHARE A HOUSE
WITH FOUR GUYS
I'VE KNOWN SINCE
OUR UNIVERSITY
DAYS.
FOR TWO
YEARS WE'VE
LIVED TOGETHER
WITHOUT MAJOR
ISSUES.
MOSTLY
BECAUSE WE
RUN THE PLACE
ON A SIMPLE
SYSTEM.
MAJORITY
VOTE SETTLES
EVERYTHING.
CLEANING
SCHEDULES.
NOISE
RULES.
CHORE
ROTATIONS.
IF THREE OF
US AGREE, THAT
BECOMES THE
HOUSE
STANDARD.
IT'S WORKED
FLAWLESSLY.
LAST
MONTH, ONE
OF THE ORIGINAL
FIVE MOVED
OUT TO LIVE
WITH HIS
GIRLFRIEND.
HE
BROUGHT IN A
REPLACEMENT.
LYLE.
A FRIEND
OF A FRIEND
TYPE.
QUIET, POLITE,
NOT SOMEONE
WE WERE WORRIED
ABOUT.
FOR THE FIRST
WEEK, HE
SEEMED FINE,
UNTIL HE
CALLED A HOUSE
MEETING.
THAT SHOULD'VE
BEEN THE FIRST
RED
FLAG.
HE STOOD
IN THE LIVING
ROOM AND
ANNOUNCED HE
WAS UNCOMFORTABLE WITH
THE FACT THAT
SOME OF US
DON'T ALWAYS
WALK AROUND
FULLY DRESSED
INSIDE THE
HOUSE.
NONE OF
US ARE NUDISTS
OR ANYTHING LIKE
THAT, BUT
WE'RE FORMER ATHLETES,
PRETTY COMFORTABLE
AROUND EACH
OTHER, AND
DON'T ALWAYS
BOTHER WITH
SHIRTS OR
FULL
OUTFITS.
I TEND
TO LOUNGE AROUND
IN BOXERS
WHEN I'M RELAXING
OR HEADING TO
THE KITCHEN HALF
ASLEEP.
IT'S
NEVER BEEN A
PROBLEM.
HIM.
LYLE
WANTED A
STRICT CLOTHES
ON
RULE.
AS ALWAYS,
WE PUT
IT TO A VOTE,
AND HE
WAS THE ONLY
ONE WHO WANTED
IT.
THE RULE
DIDN'T
PASS.
STILL,
I TRIED
TO BE CONSIDERATE
AND STARTED WEARING
MORE CLOTHES
MOST OF THE
TIME.
EXCEPT
FOR THE OCCASIONAL
MORNING STUMBLE
OR POST
SHOWER SPRINT
TO MY
ROOM.
NOTHING
WILD,
APPARENTLY.
THAT WASN'T
ENOUGH FOR
HIM.
HE STARTED
BRINGING GUESTS
OVER WITHOUT
ANY
WARNING.
EVEN
THOUGH HOUSE
PROTOCOL HAS
ALWAYS BEEN
TO TEXT FIRST
A FEW
TIMES.
I
WALKED INTO THE
LIVING ROOM
IN MY UNDERWEAR
ONLY TO
FIND HIM AND
A HANDFUL OF
PEOPLE STARING
AT ME
LIKE THEY'D HAD
WALKED INTO THE
WRONG
REALITY.
I SHRUG,
HEAD BACK,
AND GET
DRESSED.
I EVEN
TOLD HIM ONCE
THAT ALL HE
HAD TO DO
WAS GIVE ME
A HEADS
UP.
HE
ROLLED HIS EYES
LIKE I INCONVENIENCED
HIM.
IT WASN'T
JUST
ME.
ANOTHER HOUSEMATE
GOT CAUGHT IN
THE SAME SITUATION
MULTIPLE
TIMES.
THEN,
TWO DAYS
AGO, HE
CORNERED
ME AND ONE OF
THE GUYS IN
THE
KITCHEN.
HE ASKED,
WITH THIS
SMUG,
SELF
-SATISFIED
TONE, WHETHER
HIS PLAN
HAD
WORKED.
WE ASKED
WHAT HE WAS TALKING
ABOUT.
HE GRINNED
AND SAID HE'D
INTENTIONALLY BEEN
BRINGING PEOPLE
OVER UNANNOUNCED
TO TEACH US
TO
STOP.
LOUNGING
AROUND IN
UNDERWEAR.
HE ACTUALLY
SAID HE WAS
TRYING TO EMBARRASS
US INTO
CHANGING.
WE TOLD
HIM WE WEREN'T
EMBARRASSED.
HONESTLY,
WE SPENT
ENOUGH TIME
IN THE GYM
THAT BEING SEEN
IN BOXERS
ISN'T EXACTLY
DRAMATIC.
HE
GOT FURIOUS,
SAID WE
WERE BEING INCONSIDERATE,
AND THEN
SNORED OFF
TO COMPLAIN TO
THE REST OF
THE
HOUSE.
WHO
ALREADY KNEW
ABOUT THE VOTE
AND SIDED WITH
US?
NOW
HE'S SULKING,
ACTING
LIKE WE'VE
WRONGED HIM,
AND STOMPING
AROUND LIKE
HE'S STAGING
A ONE -MAN
PROTEST.