I'M
A 19 -YEAR
-OLD COLLEGE STUDENT
STUDYING FOOD
SCIENCE, AND
I'M CURRENTLY BURNED
OUT FROM NON
-STOP EXAMS
AND
STUDYING.
BECAUSE
OF MY MAJOR,
I'VE LEARNED
EXACTLY HOW
FOODBORNE
ILLNESSES HAPPEN
AND HOW QUICKLY
UNSAFE KITCHEN
HABITS CAN
MAKE PEOPLE
SERIOUSLY
SICK.
I'VE TRIED
EXPLAINING THIS
AT HOME
IN A CALM WAY,
POINTING
OUT SMALL
THINGS LIKE
WASHING BOARDS
OR NOT LEAVING
FOOD OUT
TOO
LONG.
BUT
MY FAMILY
ALWAYS LAUGHS
IT OFF AND
SAYS I'M BEING
DRAMATIC OR
SHOWING OFF
BECAUSE I'M
IN
COLLEGE.
EVERYTHING
FINALLY BOILED
OVER ONE
NIGHT WHILE
DINNER WAS BEING
PREPARED.
I WATCHED
A FAMILY MEMBER
CUT RAW
POULTRY AND
THEN IMMEDIATELY USE
THE SAME BOARD
FOR FRESH
VEGETABLES
WITHOUT CLEANING
IT.
WHEN I SPOKE
UP, I
WAS TOLD TO
STOP OVERTHINKING
AND JUST TRUST
THAT EVERYTHING WOULD
BE
FINE.
THE
IDEA THAT
PRAYER MATTERED
MORE THAN BASIC
HYGIENE MADE
MY STOMACH
DROP.
AND
I REALIZED
NO ONE
WAS TAKING THE
RISK
SERIOUSLY.
I
REFUSED TO
EAT THE
MEAL.
THAT DECISION
INSTANTLY
TURNED THE
SITUATION
HOSTILE.
I WAS
ACCUSED OF
ACTING
SUPERIOR.
OF THINKING
I WAS SMARTER
THAN EVERYONE
ONE ELSE JUST
BECAUSE OF MY
DEGREE.
LATER,
I NOTICED
A LARGE BATCH
OF FOOD THAT
HAD BEEN SITTING
OUT AT ROOM
TEMPERATURE ALL
NIGHT.
KNOWING
IT HAD BEEN IN
UNSAFE CONDITIONS
FOR HOURS,
I THREW
IT AWAY DESPITE
HOW EXPENSIVE
IT
WAS.
BECAUSE
THE THOUGHT OF
SOMEONE GETTING
SICK FELT
WORSE THAN
WASTING
MONEY.
SINCE THEN,
THE HOUSE
HAS GONE QUIET
AND
TENSE.
ONE
PARENT FEELS
PERSONALLY
INSULTED,
AS IF
MY REFUSAL
TO EAT
MEANS I'M
REDACTING THEM
RATHER THAN
PROTECTING
MYSELF.
ANOTHER
IS FURIOUS,
SAYING
I EMBARRASSED
THEM AND
WASTED FOOD
BY ACTING
LIKE AN EXPERT
INSTEAD OF
A FAMILY
MEMBER.
I
NEVER WANTED
TO FIGHT, I
JUST DIDN'T
WANT TO GAMBLE WITH
MY HEALTH
WHILE BEING TREATED
LIKE THE PROBLEM
FOR
CARING.
NOW
I'M STUCK WONDERING
IF SETTING A
BOUNDARY BASED
ON WHAT I'VE
LEARNED REALLY MAKES
ME UNREASONABLE,
OR IF
I'M BEING PUNISHED
FOR NOT PRETENDING
EVERYTHING WAS
FINE.