I,
34F,
SPENT WEEKS
PLANNING WHAT
I THOUGHT WOULD BE
MY SON'S MOST
MEMORABLE BIRTHDAY
YET.
HE'S
TURNING 13,
A BIG
MILESTONE, AND
MONEY IS TIGHT,
SO I
STRETCHED MYSELF
TO MAKE
IT
SPECIAL.
I RENTED
BATTING CAGES
FOR THE KIDS,
ORDERED
A CAKE,
PLANNED SNACKS
AND GAMES,
AND EVEN
ORGANIZED A
SCAVENGER
HUNT OUTSIDE
WITH A SMALL
CASH PRIZE
TO MAKE IT
EXCITING.
I
WANTED THIS
BIRTHDAY TO
FEEL MAGICAL,
EVEN THOUGH
WE'RE NOT
WEALTHY.
A FEW
DAYS BEFORE
THE PARTY
I
PULLED OUT
THE TWENTY DOLLARS
I HAD SET
ASIDE FOR
THE SCAVENGER
HUNT PRIZE
AND SEPARATED
IT INTO FOUR
FIVE DOLLARS
BILLS
LATER
THAT DAY
ONLY
MY SON
AND ONE OF HIS
FRIENDS WERE
IN THE APARTMENT
WHILE I
WAS BRIEFLY WORKING
IN MY ROOM
WHEN
I RETURNED
I
NOTICED MY
WALLET AND
PURSE WERE OPEN
IN A WAY THAT'S
NOT NORMAL
FOR ME THAT'S
WHEN I SAW
IT TEN
DOLLARS MISSING
I
IMMEDIATELY CONFRONTED
MY SON
HE
SWORE HE
DIDN'T TAKE
IT I
ASKED ABOUT
HIS FRIEND
SAME
ANSWER.
HERE'S
THE
THING.
MY SON
HAS NEVER
STOLEN
ANYTHING.
BUT
HE HAS LIED
ABOUT SMALL
THINGS
BEFORE.
I'VE CAUGHT
HIM SNEAKING SNACKS
AND TELLING
LITTLE
FIBS.
AND IT'S
BEEN A RECURRING
ISSUE.
I WANTED
TO GIVE HIM
THE BENEFIT OF
THE
DOUBT.
BUT EVERYTHING
POINTED TO
HIM KNOWING WHAT
HAD
HAPPENED.
I COULDN'T
IGNORE
IT.
THIS WASN'T
JUST TEN
DOLLARS.
IT WAS
A LESSON IN
TRUST AND
HONESTY.
AFTER
ARGUING, DISCUSSING,
AND TRYING
TO GET TO THE
TRUTH, I
REALIZED I
COULDN'T IN GOOD
CONSCIENCE
LET HIM HAVE
THE
PARTY.
IF
HE DID TAKE
THE MONEY AND
I LET THE CELEBRATION
GO
ON.
I'D
BE REWARDING DISHONESTY
AND SENDING
THE MESSAGE
THAT LYING
HAS NO
CONSEQUENCES.
SO
I MADE THE
GUT -WRENCHING
DECISION TO
CANCEL THE
PARTY
ENTIRELY.
NOW
MY SON IS
DEVASTATED.
HE'S
HEARTBROKEN
THAT HIS MILESTONE
BIRTHDAY IS
RUINED.
AND I
CAN'T STOP FEELING
GUILTY.
PART OF
ME WONDERS
IF I OVERREACTED
OVER
$10.
BUT
ANOTHER PART
OF ME KNOWS
I HAD TO
STAND
FIRM.
I WANTED
TO TEACH HIM
A LESSON HE'D
REMEMBER.
BUT AT
WHAT
COST?