I
WORK FULL
-TIME IN AN
OFFICE JOB
AND RECENTLY
FOUND MYSELF
DRIVING
MY YOUNGER COUSIN
MAYA, HER
TEENAGE SON,
AND A COUPLE
OF HIS TEAMMATES
ACROSS STATE
LINES TO
ATTEND A WEEKEND
SOCCER
TOURNAMENT.
AND
WHILE SHE GENEROUSLY
PAID FOR
MEALS FOR
THE OTHER KIDS
EVEN AFTER
THEIR PARENTS
OFFERED TO
REIMBURSE
HER,
SHE ACTED
OFFENDED WHEN
I ASKED HER
TO CHIP IN
FOR FUEL
DESPITE THE
FACT THAT HER
OWN CAR IS
BARELY FUNCTIONAL
AND CAN'T
HANDLE LONG TRIPS,
SOMETHING
I BRUSHED OFF
UNTIL A SECOND
INCIDENT A
FEW WEEKS LATER
WHEN I DROVE
HER AND HER SON
TO A SPECIALIST
APPOINTMENT
SEVERAL
HOURS AWAY
KNOWING
AHEAD OF TIME
THAT PARKING
AT THE CLINIC
WASN'T FREE
ONLY
FOR HER TO
CASUALLY ANNOUNCE
AS I PULLED
INTO THE GARAGE
THAT SHE
HADN'T BROUGHT ANY
MONEY YET
ALL
AND EXPECTED
ME TO COVER
IT WHICH
TURNED INTO
A TENSE EXCHANGE
WHERE
I POINTED OUT
HOW UNREASONABLE
IT
WAS TO SHOW UP
TO AN APPOINTMENT
COMPLETELY
UNPREPARED
AND INSISTED
SHE FIGURE
IT OUT HERSELF
SOMETHING
SHE EVENTUALLY
DID
WHILE MAKING IT
VERY CLEAR
HOW STRESSFUL
I
WAS BEING AND
THIS PATTERN
HAS STARTED
TO FEEL DELIBERATE
GIVEN THAT
SHE DOESN'T
WORK BY CHOICE
DESPITE BEING
FULLY
CAPABLE OF
TAKING A PART
-TIME RETAIL
JOB THAT
WOULDN'T AFFECT
HER GOVERNMENT
ASSISTANCE LEADING
ME TO WONDER
IF MY STABLE
INCOME AND
LACK OF CHILDREN
HAS QUIETLY
TURNED ME
INTO HER DEFAULT
FINANCIAL
SAFETY
NET ESPECIALLY
AFTER
YEARS OF
COVERING EMERGENCIES
REPAIRS
AND
TRAVEL COSTS
THAT NEVER SEEM
TO END