I JUST
TURNED 18
AND LIVE
IN A NORTHERN
STATE WHERE
RESIDENTS RECEIVE
ANNUAL DIVIDEND
PAYMENTS
FROM
NATURAL RESOURCE
REVENUE.
THOSE PAYMENTS
START WHEN
YOU'RE A BABY
AND ADD UP
OVER
TIME.
ONCE
I BECAME AN
ADULT, I
DID WHAT MOST
PEOPLE MY
AGE WOULD
DO.
I ASKED
WHAT HAD HAPPENED
TO
MINE.
BY MY
MATH, EVEN
WITHOUT INTEREST
OR INVESTMENTS,
IT SHOULD
HAVE TOTALED
CLOSE TO $30
,000.
THAT'S
WHEN EVERYTHING
CRACKED
OPEN.
WHEN
I ASKED MY
PARENT ABOUT
THE MONEY,
SHE
BRUSHED IT
OFF AT FIRST
SAYING
IT WENT TOWARD
MEDICAL EXPENSES
AND NECESSITIES
THAT
EXPLANATION IMMEDIATELY
FELT
WRONG I
WAS DOUBLE
INSURED MY
ENTIRE CHILDHOOD
AND RARELY
HAD OUT -OF
-POCKET MEDICAL
BILLS WHEN
I PUSHED BACK
HER
STORY SHIFTED
SHE
ADMITTED SOME
OF THE MONEY
WAS USED ON
HOUSEHOLD EXPENSES
BUT
INSISTED SHE
WOULD NEVER SPEND
IT ON ANYTHING
THAT DIDN'T
SOMEHOW INVOLVE
ME THEN
THINGS GOT UGLY
INSTEAD
OF GIVING
ME CLEAR ANSWERS
SHE
ACCUSED MY
OTHER PARENT
OF PUTTING PUTTING
IDEAS IN
MY HEAD, AND
TRYING TO TURN
ME AGAINST
HER.
THAT
WASN'T
TRUE.
NO ONE
INFLUENCED
ME.
I WAS
SIMPLY ASKING
WHERE MY
MONEY
WENT.
THAT COULD HAVE
HELPED ME WITH
SCHOOL, HOUSING,
OR JUST
SURVIVING EARLY
ADULTHOOD.
SHE THEN
TOLD ME
SHE STRUGGLED
FINANCIALLY
FOR YEARS
AND HAD NO
CHOICE BUT
TO DIP INTO
IT.
HERE'S THE PART
THAT SHATTERED
WHATEVER TRUST
I HAD
LEFT.
ACCORDING
TO THE DIVORCE
AGREEMENT BETWEEN
MY PARENTS,
ANY
MONEY TAKEN
FROM MY
DIVIDEND ACCOUNT
WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE
REPAID.
DESPITE
THAT LEGAL
REQUIREMENT,
WHEN I FINALLY
LEARNED THE
BALANCE, THERE
WAS BARELY
$500
LEFT.
WHAT SHOULD HAVE BEEN
A SAFETY NET
FOR MY FUTURE
IS
GONE.
A
CONVERSATION
SPIRALED
AFTER
THAT.
DEFENSIVENESS.
GUILT
-TRIPPING.
EMOTIONAL
BLOW
-UPS.
NOTHING
WAS
RESOLVED.
AND NOW,
WITH THE HOLIDAYS
COMING UP,
I'M EXPECTED
TO SHOW UP
FOR CHRISTMAS
LIKE EVERYTHING
IS
NORMAL.
LIKE I
DIDN'T JUST FIND
OUT THAT TENS
OF THOUSANDS
OF DOLLARS
LEGALLY MEANT
FOR ME VANISHED
WITHOUT
ACCOUNTABILITY.
I'M
SITTING HERE
TRYING TO
PROCESS BETRAYAL,
FINANCIAL
LOSS,
AND THE WEIGHT
OF STARTING ADULTHOOD
WITH NOTHING,
WHILE
BEING TOLD
I'M DRAMATIC
FOR BEING
UPSET AND
SELFISH FOR
NOT WANTING TO
CELEBRATE.
AND
HONESTLY, I
DON'T KNOW HOW
I'M SUPPOSED TO
PRETEND THIS
DIDN'T
HAPPEN.