NOW I'M
SUPPOSED TO
TAKE IT ALL
HOME?
I'M
IN MY EARLY
30S.
MARRIED,
AND USUALLY
GET ALONG
WELL WITH
MY HUSBAND'S
MOTHER.
THOUGH SHE
HAS A LONG
HISTORY OF
PUSHING PAST
BOUNDARIES
WHILE SMILING
THROUGH
IT.
THIS
YEAR WE'RE SPENDING
THE HOLIDAYS
WITH MY HUSBAND'S
SIDE OF THE
FAMILY.
AND
WELL AHEAD
OF TIME WE
WERE VERY CLEAR
ABOUT ONE
THING.
FOR
OUR TODDLER,
WHO'S JUST
UNDER 2,
WE WANTED
EXPERIENCES INSTEAD
OF PHYSICAL
GIFTS.
THINGS
LIKE PASSES
TO THE AQUARIUM,
A ZOO
VISIT, OR
MAYBE A SINGLE
BOOK TO
UNWRAP.
HE ALREADY
HAS MORE
TOYS AND
CLOTHES THAN
WE CAN
MANAGE.
AND AT
HIS AGE HE
DOESN'T EVEN
UNDERSTAND
GIFT OPENING
YET.
SHE WAS
VISIBLY UNHAPPY
ABOUT
THIS AND KEPT
INSISTING
SHE WANTED TO
BUY REAL
PRESENTS.
EVENTUALLY,
SHE ASKED
FOR AN ONLINE
WISH LIST
OF PRACTICAL
THINGS WE
COULD USE
LATER.
EVEN
THOUGH WE TRULY
DIDN'T NEED
MUCH, MY
HUSBAND AND
I CAREFULLY PUT
TOGETHER A
SMALL LIST
AND SENT IT
TO
HER.
EXPLAINING
SHE COULD PICK
ANYTHING FROM
THERE IF SHE
REALLY WANTED
TO GIVE
SOMETHING.
THEN
THIS MORNING
EVERYTHING BLEW
UP.
MY HUSBAND
CASUALLY
ASKED WHAT
SHE DECIDED
ON.
SINCE
MY OWN
MOTHER WANTED
THE LIST TO
GRAB A COUPLE
OF ITEMS
TOO.
INSTEAD
OF ANSWERING
DIRECTLY,
HIS MOM
REPLIED WITH
A JOKING MESSAGE
ABOUT BEING
IN TROUBLE,
FOLLOWED BY
A
VIDEO.
THE
VIDEO SHOWED
A MASSIVE
PILE OF
GIFTS SHE'D
ALREADY
BOUGHT.
NONE OF
THEM WERE FROM
THE LIST, NOT
A SINGLE
ONE.
IT WAS
ALL OVERSIZED,
NOISY, SPACE
-HOGGING ITEMS
SHE KNOWS
WE HAVE NO ROOM
FOR, PLUS
A KID'S TABLET
EVEN THOUGH
WE'VE BEEN VERY
CLEAR WE
DON'T DO SCREENS
AT
ALL.
I
IMMEDIATELY TOLD
MY HUSBAND
THAT IF SHE
WANTS THOSE THINGS,
THEY CAN
STAY AT HER
HOUSE.
WE'RE
NOT HAULING
THEM BACK WITH
US.
TO
ME, IT
FELT INCREDIBLY
DISRESPECTFUL
TO
IGNORE OUR
WISHES ENTIRELY,
ESPECIALLY
AFTER
ASKING FOR
A LIST AND
THEN DELIBERATELY
GOING AGAINST
IT.
IT
FELT LESS
LIKE GENEROSITY
AND MORE
LIKE A POWER
MOVE.
MY HUSBAND
THINKS WE
SHOULD TAKE AT
LEAST SOME
OF IT HOME SO
HIS MOTHER DOESN'T
FEEL
HURT.
BUT
ALL I CAN THINK
IS THAT DOING
SO JUST TEACHES
HER THAT OUR
BOUNDARIES DON'T
MATTER AND
THAT SHE CAN
OVERRIDE US
WHENEVER SHE
WANTS.
ON
TOP OF THAT,
WE GENUINELY
DON'T
HAVE THE SPACE FOR
ANY OF
IT.
SO NOW
I'M STUCK
BETWEEN KEEPING
THE PEACE AND
FINALLY STANDING
FIRM.
AND
I CAN'T
SHAKE THE FEELING
THAT IF I GIVE
IN THIS TIME,
I'LL BE
FIGHTING THE
SAME BATTLE
EVERY HOLIDAY
FOR YEARS TO
COME.