DURING
THE HOLIDAYS,
A SIMPLE
GIFT EXCHANGE TURNED
INTO UNEXPECTED
FAMILY
TENSION.
MY DAUGHTER,
ALARA,
11, AND
HER YOUNGER COUSIN,
BRIELLE, 7,
WERE EACH GIVEN
A BLIND BOX
COLLECTIBLE
CALLED A MOON
MALLOW SPRITE,
A
POPULAR VINYL
TOY SIMILAR
TO LABUBU
WHERE SOME DESIGNS
ARE PRODUCED IN
SMALLER NUMBERS.
WHEN
THEY OPENED THEIR
BOXES, BRIELLE
RECEIVED A
BEIGE FOREST SPRITE,
WHILE ALARA
OPENED A CORAL
STAR SPRITE.
BRIELLE
IMMEDIATELY BECAME
UPSET BECAUSE
SHE SHE WANTED THE
CORAL ONE. AND
ALARA, WHO
ALREADY OWNED
THAT VERSION, OFFERED
TO TRADE BECAUSE
SHE LIKED THE
BEIGE DESIGN BETTER.
THE SWAP HAPPENED
QUICKLY, NO
ADULTS INTERVENED,
AND BOTH
KIDS WERE HAPPY
AFTERWARD.
A DAY LATER,
BRIELLE'S PARENTS
FOUND OUT
THROUGH AN ONLINE
GROUP THAT
THE BEIGE FOREST
SPRITE WAS
A SECRET RUN
FIGURE
AND COULD RESELL
FOR AROUND $190.
ONCE THEY
LEARNED THAT, THEY
CONTACTED ME
AND DEMANDED
THE KIDS SWITCH
TOYS BACK,
EVEN ASKING
ME TO DRIVE
NEARLY AN HOUR
LATE AT NIGHT
TO RETURN IT.
WHEN I
ASKED IF BRIELLE
ACTUALLY WANTED
THE BEIGE FIGURE
AGAIN, THEY
SAID THAT WASN'T
RELEVANT.
AFTER MORE
DISCUSSION, HER
FATHER ADMITTED
SOMEONE HAD
ALREADY OFFERED
HIM $170
FOR
IT.
AND HE
PLANNED TO SELL
IT AND THEN BUY
BRIELLE A DIFFERENT
CORAL ONE.
I REFUSED
TO FORCE MY
DAUGHTER TO GIVE
IT BACK. FROM
MY PERSPECTIVE,
THE TRADE WAS
FAIR AT THE TIME.
BOTH CHILDREN
AGREED.
ALARA DIDN'T
PRESSURE BRIELLE.
AND WHILE ALARA
KNEW THE FOREST
SPRITE WAS HARDER
TO PULL, SHE
DIDN'T KNOW IT
HAD RESALE VALUE
OR THAT IT COULD
BE SOLD FOR
REAL MONEY. BRIELLE
ORIGINALLY DIDN'T
WANT THAT FIGURE
AT ALL AND
ONLY CHANGED
HER PARENTS' MINDS
ONCE MONEY
ENTERED
THE PICTURE.
NOW BRIELLE'S
PARENTS ARE UPSET.
ACCUSING ME
OF TAKING ADVANTAGE
OF A CHILD.
AND ONE
OF THEM EVEN SAID
SOMETHING EXTREMELY
HARSH ABOUT
MY DAUGHTER THAT
I FELL ACROSS THE
LINE.
THE RELATIVE
WHO GAVE THE TOY
SAYS THIS IS
UNNECESSARY ADULT
DRAMA AND
HAS STEPPED AWAY
FROM THE. SITUATION.
LEAVING THE
CONFLICT UNRESOLVED.
SO WAS I
WRONG FOR STANDING
FIRM AND
LETTING MY DAUGHTER
KEEP THE TOY
SHE FAIRLY TRADED
FOR?