LAST
WEEKEND IN
MAPLE RIDGE,
I AGREED,
AT THE VERY
LAST MINUTE,
TO DRIVE
A TEAMMATE OF
MY SON TO
THEIR LATE AFTERNOON
MATCH.
MY
WIFE HAD ALREADY
ARRANGED THE
RIDE WITH THE
BOY'S MOTHER,
LILA,
WHO'S A
SINGLE PARENT
AND USUALLY
SWAPS
DRIVING DUTIES
WITH MY WIFE
EVERY THURSDAY
EVENING.
SINCE
MY WIFE WAS
TRAVELING FOR
WORK, I
STEPPED IN
WITHOUT
HESITATION.
I'VE
HELPED BEFORE,
AND EVERY
OTHER TIME,
THE ROUTINE
WAS
SIMPLE.
I'D BRING
THE BOY BACK
TO OUR HOUSE
AFTERWARD, AND
LILA WOULD
COLLECT HIM
FROM
THERE.
BUT
THIS TIME
UNFOLDED
DIFFERENTLY.
NEAR THE
END OF THE GAME,
LILA'S
EX -HUSBAND,
MARCUS, SHOWED
UP.
I KNEW HIM
CASUALLY FROM
YEARS
AGO.
ENOUGH
TO SAY HELLO
TO.
AND WHILE
I'D HEARD PLENTY
THROUGH MY WIFE
ABOUT HOW TENSE
THEIR RELATIONSHIP
HAD ONCE
BEEN, NONE
OF IT HAD EVER
INVOLVED ANYTHING
THAT AFFECTED
ME
DIRECTLY.
WHEN I
SAW HIM CHATTING
WITH LILA'S
MOTHER BESIDE
THE BLEACHERS,
I STEPPED
OVER AND
ASKED, ARE
YOU TAKING ROWAN
HOME
TONIGHT?
MARCUS
NODDED
AND SAID
YES.
LILA'S
MOTHER DIDN'T
OBJECT OR
EXPRESS
WORRY.
SHE SIMPLY
ASKED ME
TO LET HER DAUGHTER
KNOW HER PHONE
HAD RUN OUT
OF POWER SO
I LEFT THE
FIELD ASSUMING
ALL WAS
WELL THE
MOMENT I
WALKED THROUGH
HER FRONT DOOR
MY
WIFE LIT
INTO ME
FURIOUS
SHAKING
DEMANDING
TO KNOW
WHY I HAD
ALLOWED MARCUS
TO LEAVE WITH
HIS OWN SON
SHE
SAID I HAD
HANDED THE BOY
OVER TO SOMEONE
SHE BELIEVED
WAS VOLATILE
SOMEONE
SHE HAD
LONG WARNED
ME ABOUT SHE
INSISTED I
SHOULD HAVE WAITED
REFUSED
THE HANDOFF
OR
AT THE VERY
LEAST CONTACTED
HER BEFORE
LEAVING
LEAVING.
SHE
SAID I'D PUT
THE CHILD AT
RISK WITHOUT
EVEN REALIZING
IT.
I
WAS
STUNNED.
FROM MY
PERSPECTIVE, THE
BOY'S GRANDMOTHER
APPROVED.
HIS FATHER
CONFIRMED HE
WAS TAKING HIM
HOME.
AND NOTHING
SEEMED
UNUSUAL.
BUT MY WIFE
MAINTAINS THAT
I SHOULD HAVE KNOWN
BETTER AND
THAT I OVERLOOKED
SOMETHING
SERIOUS.
DID
I GENUINELY
MISHANDLE
THE
SITUATION?
OR DID
I SIMPLY TRUST
A PARENT
TO TAKE HIS
OWN CHILD
WHEN EVERYONE
PRESENT SEEMED
TO
AGREE?