I'M A 27-YEAR-OLD
WOMAN WHO RECENTLY
MOVED INTO
MY FIRST HOUSE
WITH MY HUSBAND.
AND I'M
4 MONTHS PREGNANT
WITH OUR FIRST
CHILD.
THIS PREGNANCY
HAS BEEN BRUTAL.
I'VE HAD
SEVERE NAUSEA
AND VOMITING TO
THE POINT WHERE I
FAINTED, HIT
MY HEAD, AND
ENDED UP HOSPITALIZED
FOR NEARLY
A WEEK.
WHEN I WAS
FINALLY DISCHARGED,
I WAS WEAK,
EXHAUSTED, AND
BARELY FUNCTIONING,
BUT I WAS
RELIEVED TO BE
GOING HOME TO
RECOVER.
THAT RELIEF
LASTED ABOUT
5 MINUTES.
WHEN
I WALKED INTO
THE HOUSE, I
FOUND OUT MY
HUSBAND HAD
MOVED HIS BROTHER,
HIS BROTHER'S
WIFE, AND
THEIR KIDS INTO
TWO OF OUR THREE
BEDROOMS WHILE
I WAS HOSPITALIZED.
ONE OF
THOSE ROOMS HAD
BEEN MY HOME OFFICE,
AND ALL
MY WORK PAPERS
WERE DUMPED INTO
OUR BEDROOM.
THE HOUSE
ITSELF WAS
CHAOS.
OVERFLOWING TRASH.
DIRTY LAUNDRY
EVERYWHERE.
USED DIAPERS
LEFT OUT.
DISHES STACKED
AND SCATTERED.
I STOOD THERE
AND JUST STARTED
CRYING.
MY HUSBAND
BRUSHED IT OFF
AND SAID IT WASN'T
THAT BAD. I
TOLD HIM IF
THAT WAS TRUE,
THEN YOU
SHOULD HAVE THE HOUSE
CLEANED BEFORE
I WOKE UP.
I WAS
SO SICK AND
DRAINED THAT I PASSED
OUT FOR HOURS.
WHEN I
WOKE UP, I
COULDN'T EVEN FIND
A CLEAN GLASS
TO GET WATER
BECAUSE EVERY
SINGLE ONE
WAS DIRTY AND
SPREAD.
AROUND THE
HOUSE, NOTHING
HAD BEEN CLEANED,
FIGHTING TEARS.
I STARTED
WASHING DISHES
MYSELF, EVEN
THOUGH I FELT AWFUL
PHYSICALLY.
THE NEXT MORNING,
I TRIED TO
WORK FROM HOME
WHILE THEIR KIDS
SCREAMED, BANGED
ON WALLS, AND
RAN THROUGH THE
HOUSE.
THEIR MOTHER
STAYED LOCKED
IN HER ROOM
MOST OF THE DAY,
IGNORING THEM
COMPLETELY.
THAT EVENING,
MY HUSBAND
CAME HOME
AND DIDN'T ASK
HOW I WAS FEELING.
FEELING INSTEAD
HE
SCOLDED ME
FOR NOT HELPING
HIS SISTER-IN-LAW
WITH THE KIDS
AND FOR NOT GETTING
ANYTHING DONE
AROUND
THE HOUSE
APPARENTLY
FORGETTING HE
HADN'T CLEANED A
THING EITHER THAT
TURNED INTO
A FULL-BLOWN
ARGUMENT I
TOLD HIM I
WAS TOO SICK
TO HOST ANYONE
AND THAT HIS BROTHER'S
FAMILY NEEDED
TO LEAVE HE
FLAT OUT REFUSED
SAYING
THEY WERE HIS FAMILY
AND YOU WOULDN'T
KICK THEM OUT
I BROKE
DOWN I
FELT TRAPPED
IGNORED
AND
PHYSICALLY INCAPABLE
OF HANDLING
ANY OF THIS
RIGHT
IN FRONT OF HIM
I CALLED
MY MOM AND
ASKED IF I
COULD COME STAY WITH
HER EXPLAINING
CLEANING EVERYTHING, SHE
SHOWED UP SHORTLY
AFTER WITH
MY OLDER BROTHERS.
MY MOM
WAS FURIOUS
AND TOLD MY
HUSBAND THAT
IF HIS FAMILY
COULD TAKE OVER THE
HOUSE, THEN
SO COULD MINE.
SHE SENT
ME STRAIGHT TO
BED WHILE MY
BROTHERS LOUDLY
CLEANED THE
HOUSE, OPENLY
CRITICIZING HOW
FILTHY IT
WAS AND HOW WRONG
IT WAS FOR MY HUSBAND
TO PUT A SICK
PREGNANT
WIFE THROUGH
THIS.
LATER, I
RECEIVED A
MESSAGE FROM MY
MOTHER-IN-LAW
ACCUSING ME
OF BEING SELFISH
FOR NOT HELPING
CLEAN AND FOR
EMBARRASSING MY
BROTHER-IN-LAW
BY LETTING MY
MOM BOSS
HIM AROUND. NOW
I'M BEING
PAINTED AS
THE
PROBLEM FOR
CALLING FOR HELP
WHEN I FELT COMPLETELY
IGNORED AND
OVERWHELMED.
SO WAS
I WRONG FOR
INVOLVING MY
FAMILY WHEN
MY HUSBAND REFUSED
TO LISTEN?