I'M 23
AND WAS INVITED
BY MY BEST
FRIEND.
LET'S CALL
HER
LILA.
SHE'S
25.
TO SPEND A
FALL HOLIDAY
WITH HER FAMILY
AT THEIR
HOME.
WE'VE KNOWN
EACH OTHER FOR
ABOUT 10
YEARS.
SHE WORKS
A COUPLE OF
LOW -PAYING JOBS
TO SAVE FOR
GRAD
SCHOOL.
AND I'M
IN GRAD SCHOOL
MYSELF WITH
NO INCOME AND
A PILE OF STUDENT
LOANS.
NEITHER OF
US HAS MUCH
EXTRA
MONEY.
I'VE SPENT
THIS HOLIDAY WITH
HER FAMILY
BEFORE.
EVERY
TIME.
I HELP SHOP,
PREP, OR
COOK BECAUSE
THINGS GET
HECTIC.
AND HER
PARENTS HAVE ALWAYS
COVERED THE
GROCERIES.
LAST YEAR,
LILA AND
I MADE A CHARCUTERIE
BOARD AND
A SALAD WHILE
HER PARENTS HANDLED
THE MAIN
DISHES.
THEY PAID
FOR EVERYTHING,
THANK YOU
S FOR THE HELP
AND EVEN
COMPLIMENTED
WHAT WE
MADE.
ON OTHER
VISITS, I'VE
RUN ERRANDS
SO R HELPED
MAKE MEALS AND
NEVER PAID FOR
GROCERIES.
THEY'VE ALWAYS
HANDLED THE
COST.
THIS YEAR,
WE REPEATED
THE SAME
PLAN.
LILA AND
I WOULD TACKLE
THE CHARCUTERIE
BOARD AND SALAD
AFTER
THE
HOLIDAY.
THOUGH, HER
MOM TOLD LILA
SHE HAD ASSUMED
I WAS GOING TO
PAY FOR THOSE INGREDIENTS
AND WAS UPSET
THAT I
DIDN'T.
WHEN LILA
TOLD ME, I
WAS
SURPRISED.
THIS HAD NEVER
BEEN EXPECTED
BEFORE.
SHE SAID
NOT TO WORRY
AND THAT IN THE FUTURE
WE'D JUST SHOP
FOR THE THINGS HER
PARENT WERE
COOKING.
BUT THE
NEXT MORNING,
WHILE LILA
WAS STILL ASLEEP,
HER MOM
CORNERED ME
IN THE LIVING ROOM
AND STARTED SCOLDING
ME ABOUT NOT
PAYING.
SHE KEPT
REPEATING THAT
I WAS AN ADULT
NOW AND SHOULD
CONTRIBUTE TO
WHAT SHE CALLED THE
POTLUCK.
I HAD
NO IDEA
IT WAS MEANT TO
BE
ONE.
NO ONE
EVER MENTIONED
THAT.
I NOTICED
SOME RELATIVES
BROUGHT
DISHES.
BUT I
ASSUMED THOSE
WERE LIKE HOST
GIFTS.
I HAD
ALREADY BROUGHT A
PRETTY PRICEY
BOX OF CHOCOLATES
AS MY OWN
GIFT.
I APOLOGIZED
AND EVEN
OFFERED TO REPAY
HER FOR THE
GROCERIES.
BUT SHE REFUSED
THE MONEY WHILE
STILL LECTURING
ME.
LATER.
SHE BROUGHT
IT UP AGAIN IN
FRONT OF
LILA.
WHICH MADE
EVERYTHING EVEN
MORE
UNCOMFORTABLE.
IF SHE HAD
TOLD LILA
AHEAD OF TIME
THAT WE WERE EXPECTED
TO PAY THIS
YEAR.
I WOULD
HAVE PLANNED FOR
IT.
AND PROBABLY
WOULDN'T HAVE BOUGHT
THE EXPENSIVE
CHOCOLATES.
NOW I'M
FEELING AWKWARD
ABOUT EVER VISITING
AGAIN.
IN MY
CULTURE.
HER CALLING
OUT A GUEST
LIKE THAT ESPECIALLY
PRIVATELY
WHILE HER DAUGHTER
WAS ASLEEP IS
CONSIDERED INCREDIBLY
RUDE IF
SHE HAD A CONCERN
SHE
COULD HAVE ADDRESSED IT
WITH LILA SINCE
SHE'S THE ONE
WHO USED
THE CARD AND
FOLLOW THEIR USUAL
ROUTINE I'M
STILL STUNNED THAT
I WAS EXPECTED TO
KNOW ABOUT AN
UNSPOKEN RULE
THAT HAD NEVER
APPLIED BEFORE