FOR THE
HOLIDAYS, I
BOOKED A LUXURY
SUITE AT
THE HILTON GRAND
RESORT IN
ORLANDO.
IT WAS
A RARE PROMOTIONAL
DEAL.
TWO CONNECTED
ROOMS, ENOUGH
SPACE FOR
EIGHT PEOPLE, AND
MY SPOUSE AND
I RESERVED IT
FOR OURSELVES, OUR
TWO KIDS,
AND A CLOSE
FAMILY FRIEND
WITH THEIR CHILDREN.
WE WERE
GENUINELY EXCITED
BECAUSE THIS
TRIP FELT LIKE
A SMALL ESCAPE
WE'D ALL BEEN
LOOKING FORWARD
TO
FOR MONTHS. OUT
OF NOWHERE, MY
SPOUSE MENTIONED
THAT HER BROTHER
AND HIS PARTNER
HAD BOOKED A
SEPARATE ROOM
AT THE SAME HILTON.
IN.
USING THE
SAME PROMOTION
THE NIGHT BEFORE
WE ARRIVED.
I DIDN'T
THINK MUCH OF IT
UNTIL LATER THAT
EVENING.
WHEN MY
SPOUSE CASUALLY
TOLD ME
SHE HAD ALREADY
TOLD THEM. AND
ANOTHER FAMILY
THEY WERE TRAVELING
WITH.
THAT THEY COULD
COME INTO OUR
SUITE AND USE
OUR BATHROOMS
AFTER CHECKING
OUT.
THIS OTHER
FAMILY ISN'T
CLOSE TO US AT
ALL.
I'VE ONLY MET
THEM BRIEFLY AT
A COUPLE OF KIDS
BIRTHDAY PARTIES.
AND THEIR
CHILD HAS
A REPUTATION FOR
BEING UNRULY.
I TRIED
TO CALMLY EXPLAIN
WHY THIS BOTHERED
ME.
I WASN'T
UPSET ABOUT
MY IN-LAWS. I
ACTUALLY ENJOY
THEM AND WOULDN'T
MIND THEM USING
OUR SPACE AT
ALL.
WHAT MADE
ME UNCOMFORTABLE
WAS HAVING
NEAR STRANGERS
AND THEIR KIDS
ROAMING THROUGH
A SUITE WE WERE
SHARING
WITH OUR OWN
GUESTS WITHOUT
ANY DISCUSSION
OR CONSENT.
IT FELT
INVASIVE,
UNFAIR TO
OUR FRIENDS,
AND STRESSFUL
BEFORE A
TRIP THAT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE RELAXING.
WHEN I
SAID I WISHED SHE
HAD TALKED TO
ME FIRST, THE
CONVERSATION IMMEDIATELY
TURNED COLD,
AND SHE ACCUSED
ME OF BEING CONTROLLING
BEFORE HANGING
UP.
NOW I'M
LEFT WONDERING IF
I'M REALLY BEING
UNREASONABLE FOR
WANTING BOUNDARIES
RESPECTED, ESPECIALLY
WHEN IT
COMES TO SHARED
SPACE AND PEOPLE
I BARELY KNOW.
OR IF
IT'S FAIR TO EXPECT
A CONVERSATION
BEFORE OPENING
OUR HOTEL ROOM
TO EXTRA GUESTS.
IS IT
WRONG TO SAY NO
TO STRANGERS USING
OUR HILTON SUITE?