A
FEW MONTHS AGO,
MY 20
-YEAR -OLD COUSIN
CALLED ME
IN A
PANIC.
THEY'D BEEN
KICKED OUT OF
THEIR PARENTS'
HOUSE AFTER
AN ARGUMENT
AND WERE BEING
FORCED TO
PAY EVER
-INCREASING
FEES JUST
TO STAY THERE,
WHILE THEIR
SIBLINGS WERE
CHARGED
NOTHING.
THEIR PARENTS
BLAMED THEM
FOR MINOR THINGS,
INCLUDING
A TINY
CAR SCRATCH,
IGNORING
FAR BIGGER
ISSUES CAUSED
BY THEIR
SIBLINGS.
I
OFFERED THEM
A PLACE TO
STAY.
WE PACKED
THEIR THINGS,
GOT THEIR
IMPORTANT DOCUMENTS,
RETURNED
THEIR CAR,
AND STARTED
FRESH.
I
HELPED THEM
OPEN A PERSONAL
BANK ACCOUNT,
LOANED
THEM MONEY FOR
A RELIABLE CAR,
AND HELPED
THEM ENROLL IN
COMMUNITY
COLLEGE.
THEY NOW
WORK PART
-TIME, BABYSIT,
AND TEACH
A SMALL
CLASS.
BEFORE
THEY MOVED
IN, WE
AGREED THEY'D
CONTRIBUTE TO
HOUSEHOLD COSTS,
BUT IN
A WAY THAT ACTUALLY
BENEFITS
THEM.
THEY PAY
A MODEST RENT
THAT GOES STRAIGHT
INTO SAVINGS
UNDER THEIR
NAME, CONTRIBUTE
TO GROCERIES,
SHARE INSURANCE
COSTS,
AND SLOWLY
REPAY THE
CAR
LOAN.
WE CALCULATED
THEIR BUDGET
TOGETHER SO
THEY COULD LEARN
INDEPENDENCE
WITHOUT BEING
OVERWHELMED.
THEIR PARENTS
FOUND OUT
AND WENT
BALLISTIC.
THEY ACCUSED
ME OF CONVINCING
MY COUSIN
TO LEAVE, OF
TAKING ADVANTAGE
OF THEM,
AND OF
BEING A VILLAIN
FOR MAKING THEM
CONTRIBUTE AT
ALL.
MEANWHILE,
MY COUSIN
IS THRIVING,
LEARNING TO
MANAGE MONEY,
AND FINALLY
HAS SOME CONTROL
OVER THEIR
OWN
LIFE.
I
FEEL LIKE I
DID THE RIGHT THING
FOR THEIR FUTURE,
BUT
NOW MY COUSIN'S
PARENTS ARE
ANGRY AND
FRAMING ME
AS A BAD
GUY.
DID
I OVERSTEP
BY HELPING
THEM AND HAVING
THEM PAY THEIR
OWN
WAY?