I GREW
UP AS THE OVERLOOKED
MIDDLE CHILD
IN A STRUGGLING
RURAL FAMILY
WHERE FAVORITISM
WAS OBVIOUS.
AND OPPORTUNITY
WAS SCARCE.
WHEN A CHANCE
CAME FOR ONE
SON TO WORK
ABROAD, MY
MOTHER PUSHED
ME OUT THE DOOR.
NOT BECAUSE
SHE BELIEVED
IN ME, BUT
BECAUSE SHE WANTED
MY OLDER BROTHER
CLOSE TO HER.
I LEFT
BEHIND MY
NEWLY MARRIED WIFE,
MISSED THE
BIRTH OF MY CHILD,
AND SPENT YEARS
GRINDING THROUGH
EXHAUSTING WORK
IN A FOREIGN COUNTRY,
SENDING NEARLY
EVERYTHING I
EARNED BACK HOME
JUST TO KEEP
THE FAMILY AFLOAT.
WHILE
I WAS GONE, I
LIVED IN CONSTANT
GUILT AND LONELINESS,
TELLING
MYSELF THE
SACRIFICE WOULD
MEAN SOMETHING ONE
DAY.
AFTER YEARS
OF THIS, I
TOOK A RISK
NO ONE SUPPORTED.
I SOLD
PART OF THE LAND
THAT LEGALLY BELONGED
TO ME AND
POURED EVERYTHING
INTO STARTING
A BUSINESS. MY
FAMILY MOCKED
THE IDEA AND
WARNED I WAS THROWING
MY LIFE AWAY.
INSTEAD, THE
BUSINESS SUCCEEDED
BEYOND ANYTHING
I IMAGINED.
I FINALLY
MOVED MY WIFE
AND CHILD TO
THE CITY, BOUGHT
A HOME, AND
GAVE THEM STABILITY
I NEVER
HAD.
THAT'S WHEN
MY FAMILY TURNED
ON ME. MY
MOTHER AND SIBLINGS
CLAIMED MY
SUCCESS WASN'T
REALLY MINE
THAT BECAUSE
MY BROTHER STAYED
BEHIND HE
DESERVED HALF
OF EVERYTHING I
BUILT THEY
SAID I ONLY
SUCCEEDED BECAUSE
HE HELD THINGS
TOGETHER IGNORING
THE FACT
THAT I FUNDED THE
HOUSEHOLD
FOR YEARS
MISSED
IRREPLACEABLE
MOMENTS WITH
MY CHILD AND
EVEN ALLOWED HIM
TO PROFIT FROM
MY LAND WHILE
I WAS GONE NOW
MY EXTENDED FAMILY
AND COMMUNITY
CALL ME SELFISH
FOR REFUSING
TO HAND OVER
HALF MY FUTURE
AFTER A
LIFETIME OF
BEING PUSHED ASIDE
THIS
IS THE FIRST THING
THAT HAS EVER
TRULY BEEN MINE
AND
I'M BEING TOLD
I DON'T DESERVE
TO KEEP IT
THANK YOU.