MY
SON MARRIED
VERY YOUNG,
BARELY
A YEAR AFTER
FINISHING SCHOOL,
AND WHILE
MY HUSBAND
AND I HAD
CONCERNS,
HE WAS
DETERMINED AND
SO WAS HIS
SPOUSE.
SOON AFTER
THE WEDDING,
THEY DECIDED
SHE WOULD STAY
HOME WHILE
HE WORKED,
AND NOT
LONG AFTER
THAT, THEY
WELCOMED A
BABY
BOY.
DURING THE
PREGNANCY, MY
DAUGHTER -IN
-LAW SPENT A
LOT OF TIME
AT MY HOUSE,
WHICH
I DIDN'T MIND
AT FIRST AFTER
MY GRANDSON
WAS
BORN.
THE VISITS
CONTINUED,
AND AGAIN,
I DIDN'T
THINK MUCH OF
IT.
I LOVE
MY GRANDCHILDREN,
AND I'VE
RAISED CHILDREN
BEFORE.
BUT
SLOWLY, WITHOUT
ANY REAL
CONVERSATION,
THOSE VISITS
STOPPED BEING
VISITS AND
STARTED TURNING
INTO FULL
DAYS OF
CHILDCARE.
SHE
BEGAN LEAVING
THE BABY
WITH ME FOR
LONGER AND
LONGER
STRETCHES.
AND
WHEN I SAID
I COULDN'T MANAGE
CERTAIN DAYS,
SHE WOULD
GET UPSET
OR ACT
HURT.
EVENTUALLY,
SHE STARTED
ASKING EVERY
WEEKEND IF
MY HUSBAND
AND I COULD WATCH
THE BABY SO
SHE AND MY SON
COULD GO
OUT.
I AGREED
FOR A FEW
WEEKS, UNTIL
WE ALREADY
HAD PLANS
OF OUR
OWN.
WHEN
I SAID NO,
SHE EXPLODED,
TELLING ME
I WAS SELFISH
AND LACKED
EMPATHY BECAUSE
SHE WAS STUCK
AT HOME ALL
WEEK AS
A
PARENT.
I
FELT GUILTY,
SO MY
HUSBAND AND
I REARRANGED
OUR LIVES
AND STARTED
WATCHING THE
BABY REGULARLY
ON
WEEKENDS.
EVEN
POSTPONING
A TRIP WE
HAD BEEN PLANNING
FOR
MONTHS.
THE TRUTH
IS, WE'RE
EXHAUSTED, WE
LOVE OUR FAMILY
DEEPLY, BUT
AT THIS STAGE
OF OUR LIVES,
WE WERE
LOOKING FORWARD
TO BEING PARTNERS
AGAIN.
NOT
FULL -TIME
CAREGIVERS.
ON TOP
OF THAT, MY
GRANDSON IS
NO LONGER
A
NEWBORN.
BORN.
HE'S
CRAWLING EVERYWHERE,
GETTING INTO
EVERYTHING, AND
IT'S PHYSICALLY
DIFFICULT
FOR US TO
KEEP
UP.
MY HUSBAND
WALKS WITH
A LIMP, AND
I STRUGGLE TO
BEND AND
LIFT.
WHAT USED
TO BE MANAGEABLE
HAS BECOME
PAINFUL
AND
OVERWHELMING.
WHEN I
FINALLY EXPLAINED
THIS TO MY
DAUGHTER -IN
-LAW, SHE
BRUSHED IT
OFF, SAYING
IT WAS ONLY
A COUPLE OF
DAYS A
WEEK.
THAT'S
WHEN I CALMLY
SAID THAT
IF IT WAS SO
SMALL, THEN
SHE COULD PAY
US THE SAME
WAY SHE PAYS
THE SITTER SHE
RECENTLY
HIRED.
AROUND
$40
A
DAY.
I ADMITTED
THAT LATELY IT
FEELS LIKE SHE
ONLY COMES
AROUND WHEN
SHE NEEDS FREE
FREE
CHILDCARE.
NOT
TO VISIT, NOT
TO SHARE A
MEAL, NOT
TO SPEND TIME
AS
FAMILY.
THAT'S
WHEN SHE COMPLETELY
LOST IT,
ACCUSING
ME OF
BEING CRUEL
FOR EVEN
SUGGESTING
PAYMENT
FOR CARING
FOR MY OWN
GRANDCHILD.
NOW
SHE'S TELLING
RELATIVES
THAT I'M HEARTLESS
AND GREEDY, AND
I'VE BEEN LEFT
QUESTIONING
MYSELF.
I ADORE
MY GRANDSON,
BUT I DIDN'T
AGREE TO RAISE
ANOTHER CHILD,
ESPECIALLY
AT A POINT
IN MY LIFE
WHEN MY BODY
SIMPLY CAN'T
HANDLE
IT.
I
CAN'T TELL
IF I'M STANDING
UP FOR MYSELF,
OR IF
I'VE CROSSED A
LINE BY
FINALLY SAYING
OUT LOUD
WHAT I'VE
BEEN QUIETLY
FEELING FOR
MONTHS.