I COMMUTE
TO WORK EACH
DAY WITH A
SMALL GROUP
OF COLLEAGUES
SINCE WE
ALL LIVE FAR
FROM THE
OFFICE.
AND SPLITTING
THE LONG
DRIVE HELPS
WITH FUEL
AND HIGHWAY
COSTS.
ONE CO
-WORKER, I'LL
CALL HER MARA,
HAS A
YOUNG SON
WHO'S BEEN DEALING
WITH SEVERE NOSEBLEEDS
THAT SOAK
THROUGH ANYTHING
SHE TRIES
TO
USE.
OVER THE
WEEKEND HIS
SYMPTOMS GOT
SO INTENSE
THAT HER FAMILY
RUSHED HIM
TO URGENT
CARE.
THE NEXT
MORNING SHE
STILL SHOWED UP
AT WORK AND
DIDN'T MENTION
ANYTHING UNTIL
WE WERE ALL
READY.
DRIVING
HOME.
THAT'S WHEN
SHE EXPLAINED
THAT SHE NEVER
ASKED HER
SUPERVISOR
FOR TIME
OFF BECAUSE SHE
ASSUMED THE
ANSWER
WOULD BE
NO.
SHE ALSO
SAID THAT IF
HE DIDN'T GET MEDICAL
ATTENTION SOON,
IT COULD
BECOME LIFE
-THREATENING.
THEN SHE
ASKED ALL
OF US TO SWITCH
TO HER CAR
FOR THE NEXT
DAY'S COMMUTE
AND LEAVE
WORK ALMOST
AN HOUR
EARLIER THAN
OUR SCHEDULED
SHIFT.
TWO OF
US FINISHED AT
THE LATEST TIME
SLOT, SO
THIS WASN'T
SOMETHING WE
COULD JUST DO
WITHOUT
APPROVAL.
WE TOLD
HER WE NEEDED
TO CHECK WITH
OUR SUPERVISORS
FIRST.
AFTER TALKING
IT OVER, THE
OTHER LATE
SHIFT CO
-WORKER HER AND
I AGREE THAT
SHE SHOULD SIMPLY
BRING HER OWN
CAR SO SHE
COULD LEAVE
WHENEVER SHE
NEEDED AND
WE'D ARRANGE A
DIFFERENT RIDE
HOME.
THAT WAY
SHE COULD RUSH
STRAIGHT BACK
TO HER SON
WITHOUT WAITING
FOR THE REST
OF
US.
IT
SEEMED LIKE
THE EASIEST
AND FASTEST
SOLUTION FOR
HER.
BUT WHEN
SHE HEARD THIS
PLAN, SHE
GOT
UPSET.
SHE SAID
WE DIDN'T CARE
ABOUT HER
SON, MADE
A POINTED COMMENT
ABOUT PEOPLE
GETTING WHAT THEY
DESERVE, AND
INSISTED SHE
CANCELED THE
APPOINTMENT SO
SHE WOULDN'T
INTERRUPT OUR
SCHEDULE, EVEN
THOUGH SHE
WAS
THE ONE WHO
FIRST SUGGESTED
TAKING HER
OWN CAR
AND WE NEVER
ASKED HER TO
CHANGE
ANYTHING.
I
CAN'T UNDERSTAND
WHY SHE
SAID THE SITUATION
MIGHT BE
LIFE -THREATENING
BUT THEN CHOSE
TO QUIETLY GO
TO WORK ALL
DAY OR
WHY SHE EXPECTED
THE ENTIRE
CARPOOL
TO LEAVE EARLY
WITHOUT CLEARING
IT
BEFOREHAND.
IF
I BELIEVED MY
CHILD WAS
IN DANGER,
I'D
HAVE LEFT WORK
IMMEDIATELY, NOT
WAITED UNTIL
A GROUP RIDE
COULD BE
ARRANGED.
SO
NOW I'M WONDERING,
AM I
WRONG FOR NOT
CLOCKING
OUT EARLY WHEN
WE OFFERED A
PLAN THAT LET
HER LEAVE SOONER
ANYWAY?