IT WAS
A QUIET SATURDAY
NIGHT, EDGING
TOWARD MIDNIGHT,
AND I WAS FINALLY
RELAXING AFTER
A LONG, DRAINING
WEEK.
I WAS IN
BED WITH MY LAPTOP
RESTING ON
MY KNEES, THE
SCREEN DIMMED
LOW, VOLUME
MUTED, AND
THE APARTMENT COMPLETELY
STILL.
NO TV,
NO MUSIC,
NO PHONE
CALLS, JUST
ME, MY
SLEEPING PETS,
AND A SINGLE
CALMING GAME
OF SOLITAIRE,
THE KIND
WHERE YOU SLOWLY
MATCH TILES
AND CLICK YOUR
WAY THROUGH PATTERNS.
I LIVE
IN AN ANCIENT,
THREE-STORY
HOUSE THAT'S
BEEN CHOPPED INTO
SEPARATE APARTMENTS
SOMETIME BEFORE
SOUNDPROOFING
WAS EVER
INVENTED EVERY
CREAK ECHOES
EVERY
PIPE SIZE DRAMATICALLY
I'M
IN THE MIDDLE UNIT
SANDWICHED
BETWEEN NEIGHBORS
ABOVE AND
BELOW SO
I'M ALWAYS HYPER
AWARE OF NOISE
THAT'S
WHY WHAT HAPPENED
NEXT FELT UNREAL
OUT
OF NOWHERE ANGRY
SHOUTING BLASTED
UP THROUGH THE FLOOR
SOMEONE
BELOW ME
YELLED CAN
YOU DO THIS TOMORROW
FOLLOWED
BY YOU'VE
HAD ALL DAY WHY
NOW THEN
IT ESCALATED
INTO FULL-ON
SWEARING BEFORE
I I COULD EVEN
PROCESS WHAT
WAS HAPPENING. THEY
STARTED SLAMMING
ON THE CEILING. HARD.
LIKE I WAS
THROWING A MIDNIGHT
RAVE INSTEAD
OF QUIETLY CLICKING
CARTS.
MY HEART
STARTED POUNDING.
I FELT
EMBARRASSED, RATTLED,
AND HONESTLY
A LITTLE SCARED.
I IMMEDIATELY
CLOSED MY
LAPTOP, ABANDONING
MY UNFINISHED GAME,
AND SAT THERE
IN THE DARK LISTENING
TO THE SILENCE
SETTLE BACK IN.
I HADN'T
EVEN FINISHED MATCHING
THE DRAGON TILES.
WHAT MAKES
THIS WORSE IS
THAT I'VE NEVER SPOKEN
TO THESE DOWNSTAIRS
NEIGHBORS IN
REAL LIFE. NOT
ONCE.
THE ONLY
INTERACTION WE'VE
EVER HAD IS THEM
YELLING THROUGH THE
CEILING.
MEANWHILE, THE
NEIGHBORS ABOVE
ME, WHO
LIVE DIRECTLY
OVER MY BEDROOM
AND WHOM I'VE
TALKED TO BEFORE,
HAVE
NEVER COMPLAINED
OR HINTED THAT
I'M NOISY. NOT
EVEN ONCE.
NOW I'M
STUCK WONDERING
IF THE GENTLE
CLICKING OF A
TRACKPAD WHILE
PLAYING SOLITAIRE
REALLY COUNTS
AS
UNACCEPTABLE NOISE,
OR IF I
WAS JUST AGGRESSIVELY
SHUT DOWN
FOR DARING TO
EXIST QUIETLY
AFTER 11PM.
WAS I
ACTUALLY BEING
INCONSIDERATE,
OR DID I
GET BULLIED INTO
SILENCE FOR
PLAYING A COMPUZZLE
GAME IN MY OWN
BED?