I'M
A 20 -YEAR
-OLD STUDENT LIVING
IN A SHARED
TOWNHOUSE IN
HALIFAX.
AND
I KEEP A
SPECIAL DEVICE
IN MY BACKPACK
THAT LOOKS
LIKE A SIMPLE
THUMB DRIVE
THAT
ISN'T.
IT'S
A VOLTAGE DISCHARGE
STICK DISGUISED
AS A
USB.
SOMETHING
I CARRY BECAUSE
MY FAMILY
HAS A LONG
HISTORY OF
PRYING INTO
ANYTHING LEFT
UNATTENDED.
TO
MAKE SURE I
NEVER CONFUSE
IT WITH MY
NORMAL STORAGE
DRIVES.
I
MARKED IT WITH
A TINY RED
MASK
STICKER.
IT'S
HARMLESS AS
LONG AS NO
ONE PLUGS
IT
IN.
THAT'S
THE ENTIRE
POINT.
POINT YESTERDAY
I
HAD TO LEAVE
CAMPUS SUDDENLY
SO
I ASKED A
FRIEND OF MINE
SHE'S
21 TO
KEEP AN EYE
ON MY BAG
UNTIL I COULD
PICK IT UP LATER
WHEN
I REALIZED
I WASN'T
MAKING IT BACK
BEFORE THE
BUILDINGS CLOSED
I
ASKED HER TO
TAKE IT TO HER
PLACE FOR THE
NIGHT SHE
AGREED WITHOUT
HESITATION
WHAT
SHE DIDN'T MENTION
UNTIL THIS MORNING
WAS THAT ONCE
SHE GOT HOME
SHE
DECIDED TO
EXPLORE MY
BAG SHE
FOUND THE RED
MASK DRIVE
ASSUMED
IT WAS MY
REGULAR ONE
AND
OUT OF PURE
CURIOSITY
PLUGGED IT
DIRECTLY INTO
HER CUSTOM
GAMING
SETUP.
THE
DEVICE DID
EXACTLY WHAT
IT'S ENGINEERED TO
DO.
IT DISCHARGED
INSTANTLY,
AND HER
COMPUTER WENT
SILENT.
BY THE TIME
SHE HAD IT INSPECTED,
THE POWER
UNIT AND
MOTHERBOARD WERE
BOTH BEYOND
REPAIR.
NOW
SHE'S FURIOUS
WITH ME,
SAYING
I'M IRRESPONSIBLE
FOR
CARRYING SOMETHING
SO DANGEROUS
AROUND AND
INSISTING
I NEED TO REPLACE
HER
EQUIPMENT.
BUT SHE ALSO
OPENLY ADMITTED
SHE WAS
RUMMAGING THROUGH
MY THINGS WITHOUT
PERMISSION,
AND
THAT SHE PLUGGED
IN A DEVICE
SHE KNEW DIDN'T
BELONG TO HER
SIMPLY TO
SEE WHAT I
HAD ON
IT.
I
FEEL AWFUL
THAT HER COMPUTER
IS RUINED
BUT I
CAN'T SHAKE
THE FACT THAT
SHE HANDLED SOMETHING
SHE WASN'T
MEANT TO TOUCH
AND USED IT
IN THE ONE
WAY IT'S
DESIGNED NEVER
TO BE USED
SO
I'M LEFT WONDERING
WAS
I GENUINELY
AT FAULT
FOR KEEPING
THE DEVICE
IN MY OWN
BAG OR
IS SHE UPSET
BECAUSE SHE
IGNORED EVERY
BOUNDARY AND
PAID THE PRICE
FOR HER OWN
CURIOSITY