I'M A
WOMAN IN MY
MID-TWENTIES
WHO SPLIT FROM
MY EX YEARS AGO
AFTER A LONG,
EXHAUSTING RELATIONSHIP
THAT LEFT
ME DOING MOST
OF THE PARENTING
ALONE.
WE SHARE
A YOUNG DAUGHTER,
AND WHILE
WE'VE MANAGED
A SERVICE-LEVEL
CO-PARENTING
ARRANGEMENT, OUR
COMMUNICATION HAS
ALWAYS BEEN STRICTLY
LIMITED TO
NECESSITIES.
I DON'T
PRY INTO HIS LIFE,
AND HE RARELY
VOLUNTEERS INFORMATION,
SOMETHING I
TOLERATED
UNTIL IT STARTED
AFFECTING OUR
CHILD.
HE'S BEEN
WITH HIS NOW-FIANCÉ
FOR YEARS,
AND I
DIDN'T EVEN LEARN
SHE EXISTED THROUGH
HIM.
OUR DAUGHTER,
BARELY OUT
OF TODDLERHOOD
AT THE TIME,
CASUALLY
MENTIONED DADDY'S
NEW FRIEND AND
THAT WAS MY INTRODUCTION.
I
SWALLOWED MY
DISCOMFORT AND
STAYED CIVIL.
THEN ONE
DAY, WHILE
SCROLLING THROUGH
SOCIAL MEDIA,
I WAS BLINDSIDED
BY GLOSSY
PHOTOS OF
AN ENGAGEMENT RING
AND CAPTION CELEBRATING
FOREVER.
THAT'S
HOW I LEARNED MY
CHILD'S FATHER
WAS GETTING MARRIED,
THROUGH SOMEONE
ELSE'S POST
DAYS EARLIER.
HE HAD
TOLD ME HE
COULDN'T FINANCIALLY
SUPPORT OUR
DAUGHTER FOR A
WHILE BECAUSE HE
WAS SWITCHING CAREERS.
I
AGREED, TRYING
TO BE UNDERSTANDING,
ONLY TO
REALIZE SOON
AFTER THAT MONEY
WASN'T TOO TIGHT
FOR LUXURY TRIPS
AND DIAMOND RINGS.
THE
PATTERN CONTINUED,
LESS THAN A
DAY BEFORE HE
WAS SUPPOSED TO
HAVE OUR DAUGHTER. HIS
MOTHER MESSAGED
ME SAYING SHE
WOULD COVER SOME
OF HIS PARENTING
TIME.
HE
LATER TEXTED
THAT HE WAS
BUSY.
I REARRANGED
MY ENTIRE SCHEDULE
TO STAY HOME,
ASSUMING
SOMETHING URGENT
HAD COME UP.
A FEW DAYS
LATER, VACATION
PHOTOS FLOODED
SOCIAL MEDIA.
BEACHES,
COCKTAILS,
SMILING
COUPLE SHOTS,
NO WARNING,
NO CONVERSATION,
JUST SILENCE
AND A MESS LEFT
FOR ME TO CLEAN
UP.
WHEN IT
WAS FINALLY HIS
TURN TO TAKE
OUR DAUGHTER AGAIN
I
CONFRONTED HIM
I TOLD
HIM IT WASN'T
ABOUT JEALOUSY
OR CONTROL
IT
WAS ABOUT RESPECT
AND COMMUNICATION
BIG
LIFE CHANGES
AFFECT OUR
CHILD AND
I DESERVED TO
HEAR ABOUT THEM DIRECTLY
HIS
RESPONSE WAS
COLD AND DISMISSIVE
HE SAID
HIS FIANCEE
WOULDN'T HAVE ANY
LEGAL RIGHTS
OVER OUR DAUGHTER
SO
IT WASN'T MY CONCERN
WHEN
I ASKED WHETHER
IT MATTERED THAT
OUR DAUGHTER WAS
GAINING A STEP-PARENT
OR
THAT THESE MILESTONES
SHAPE HER
EMOTIONAL WORLD
HE
SHUT DOWN SHORTLY
AFTER HIS
FIANCEE
BLOCKED ME ENTIRELY
WHICH
FELT LIKE A
A VERY LOUD STATEMENT.
I WASN'T
SUPPOSED TO KNOW.
AND I DEFINITELY
WASN'T SUPPOSED
TO QUESTION IT.
THAT WAS
WHEN I MADE A
DECISION I
NEVER THOUGHT I'D
HAVE TO MAKE. I
TOLD HIM OUR DAUGHTER
WOULD NOT ATTEND
THE WEDDING. AS
FAR AS SHE KNOWS.
WE ALREADY
HAVE PLANS THAT
DAY.
THERE ISN'T
EVEN A CONFIRMED
WEDDING DATE
ANYMORE.
THEY'RE NOW EXPECTING
ANOTHER CHILD.
BUT THE DAMAGE
WAS ALREADY DONE.
I'VE BEEN THE
ONE AT EVERY
SCHOOL EVENT.
EVERY APPOINTMENT.
EVERY HARD
NIGHT.
THE THOUGHT OF
WATCHING MY DAUGHTER
WALK DOWN AN
AISLE FOR THE FIRST
TIME WITHOUT ME
THERE.
HAIR.
HAVING HER
HAIR DONE BY
SOMEONE ELSE.
BEING DRESSED
BY SOMEONE ELSE.
WHILE I
FIND OUT AFTERWARD.
FELT UNBEARABLE.
NOW I'M BEING
TOLD I'M SELFISH.
THAT I'M PUNISHING
THEM.
THAT I'VE RUINED
THEIR PLANS. HIS
FAMILY SAYS
I FORCED THEM
TO DELAY EVERYTHING.
MY FRIENDS
SAY I FINALLY
SET A BOUNDARY
THAT SHOULD'VE
EXISTED YEARS
AGO.
I FEEL
GUILTY, BUT
I ALSO FEEL
INVISIBLE IN
A SITUATION
WHERE I'VE ALWAYS
CARRIED THE MOST
WEIGHT.
I'M STANDING
FIRM, EVEN
THOUGH IT HURTS.
BECAUSE THIS
ISN'T ABOUT A
WEDDING.
IT'S ABOUT
BEING SHUT OUT
OF MY OWN CHILD'S
LIFE.