MY
ADULT SON
AND HIS WIFE
HAVE TWO SMALL
CHILDREN, BOTH
UNDER
SEVEN.
I HELP
WITH CHILDCARE
OCCASIONALLY,
AND WE
USUALLY GET
ALONG WELL
ENOUGH.
THE PLAN
THIS YEAR WAS
SIMPLE AND
ALREADY
SET.
THEY WERE
SUPPOSED TO
COME OVER FOR
CHRISTMAS
DINNER.
A
FEW DAYS BEFORE
CHRISTMAS,
I GOT
A SUDDEN CALL
ASKING ME
TO WATCH THE
KIDS FOR MOST
OF THE
DAY.
WHEN
I ASKED WHY,
I FOUND
OUT THEY HAD BOUGHT
EXPENSIVE TICKETS
TO A PROFESSIONAL
FOOTBALL GAME
SCHEDULED ON
CHRISTMAS
DAY.
THEIR
ORIGINAL BACKUP
BABYSITTER
MY
DAUGHTER -IN
-LAW'S MOTHER
HAD
CANCELLED BECAUSE
THE DRIVE
WAS TOO LONG
SO
I BECAME THE
LAST MINUTE
SOLUTION I
SAID NO
I TOLD
THEM CHRISTMAS
SHOULDN'T HINGE
ON ME SACRIFICING
MY DAYS
SO THEY COULD ATTEND
A GAME AND
THAT MAYBE THE
HOLIDAYS SHOULD
BE SPENT WITH
THEIR CHILDREN INSTEAD
OF AT A STADIUM
THAT
WAS APPARENTLY
THE WRONG
ANSWER THEY
IMMEDIATELY TOLD
ME NOT TO
EXPECT THEM
AT CHRISTMAS
DINNER AT ALL
NOW
THEY'RE ANGRY
I'M
BEING TREATED
LIKE THE VILLAIN
AND
ALL BECAUSE I
REFUSE TO
REARRANGE MY
HOLIDAY SO
THEY WOULDN'T
LOSE MONEY ON
TICKETS THEY
CHOSE TO
BUY.
SO, DID
I REALLY DESTROY
CHRISTMAS
BY NOT STEPPING
IN, OR
AM I BEING PUNISHED
FOR SETTING A
BOUNDARY?