AFTER RETURNING
FROM A TRIP
TO PORTUGAL A
COUPLE OF MONTHS AGO,
I
BROUGHT HOME A
CAREFULLY CHOSEN
BOTTLE OF
AGED PORT THAT
I'D SELECTED DURING
A GUIDED TASTING.
IT WAS
PRICEY,
MEANINGFUL, AND
MEANT TO BE SOMETHING
MY WIFE
AND I WOULD EVENTUALLY
ENJOY TOGETHER.
I'M NOT
SOMEONE WHO DRINKS
OFTEN, WHICH
MADE THE CHOICE
FEEL EVEN
MORE PERSONAL.
AROUND THE
SAME TIME,
I'D ALSO
BEEN GIVEN A
SEALED BOTTLE OF
SPANISH RED
BY A CLOSE
CO-WORKER.
FROM THE
MOMENT I UNPACKED,
MY WIFE
REPEATEDLY ASKED
IF SHE COULD GIFT
THE PORT TO HER
BROTHER.
HER UNCLE,
ARE FRIENDS,
AND EVERY SINGLE
TIME I GAVE
A FIRM, UNMISTAKABLE
NO, EXPLAINING
IT WAS SENTIMENTAL
AND TIED
TO THE TRIP,
I EVEN REMINDED
HER AFTER SHE
DECLINED TO
TRY IT ONCE
BECAUSE SHE WASN'T
FEELING WELL. LEAVING
NEARLY THE ENTIRE
BOTTLE UNTOUCHED,
WHILE I
WAS OUT OF TOWN
LAST WEEK,
SHE HAD FRIENDS
OVER AFTER
A NIGHT OUT,
AND WITHOUT
TELLING ME,
SHE SERVED
THEM BOTH THE
PORT AND THE UNOPENED
WINE UNTIL
NOTHING WAS LEFT.
WHEN I
NOTICED THEY WERE
GONE AND ASKED
ABOUT IT, SHE
SHRUGGED AND SAID
SHE'D SHARE THEM,
CLAIMING SHE
FORGOT MY
BOUNDARY AND
ADDING THAT SHE
DOESN'T KEEP TRACK
OF THINGS SHE
CONSIDERS UNIMPORTANT.
WHAT HURT
MOST WAS THAT
I HAD ALREADY
BROUGHT BACK A
SEPARATE BOTTLE
OF RUM SPECIFICALLY
FOR HER
TO SHARE
WITH FRIENDS,
YET SHE
CHOSE THE TWO
THINGS I EXPLICITLY
PROTECTED.
WHEN I
TRIED TO EXPLAIN
HOW DEEPLY
UPSETTING THIS
WAS, SHE
BRUSHED IT OFF,
TOLD ME NOT
TO DAMAGE THE
MARRIAGE OVER ALCOHOL,
AND SUGGESTED
I WAS THE ONE
WHO NEEDED PROFESSIONAL
HELP.
NOW I'M LEFT
REELING, NOT
OVER THE DRINKS
THEMSELVES, BUT
OVER HOW EASILY
MY CLEARLY STATED
BOUNDARY WAS
IGNORED AND
THEN DISMISSED
AS MEANINGLESS.