MY
MANAGER IS
BRAND NEW,
BARELY
A FEW MONTHS
INTO THE ROLE,
AND EVER
SINCE SHE
TOOK OVER,
THE VIBE
AT WORK HAS
SHIFTED FROM
PROFESSIONAL
TO STRANGELY
PERFORMATIVE.
A COUPLE
OF WEEKS AGO,
SHE ANNOUNCED
WHAT SHE CALLED
MANDATORY
OVERTIME
AND
CORRALLED OUR
ENTIRE REMOTE
TEAM INTO
A TWO
-HOUR VIDEO
CALL AT
THE END OF THE
DAY.
BY THE TIME
I LOGGED OFF,
I'D
WORKED NEARLY 13
HOURS
STRAIGHT.
THE FOLLOWING
WEEK,
WE QUIETLY
LEARNED THE
TRUTH.
THE OVERTIME
HAD NEVER
BEEN REQUIRED
AT
ALL.
IT WASN'T
POLICY.
IT WAS
PRESSURE.
THAT ALONE
LEFT ME
EXHAUSTED
AND
WARY.
THEN
CAME THE HOLIDAY,
TEAM BONDING,
IDEA.
SHE ASKED
EVERYONE TO
SEND IN PHOTOS
OF THEIR HOME
DECORATIONS
SO SHE
COULD TURN IT
INTO A GUESSING
GAME
DURING YET
ANOTHER
MEETING.
THERE WAS AN
UNSPOKEN
EXPECTATION THAT
EVERYONE WOULD
PLAY ALONG, SMILE,
AND PERFORM
ENTHUSIASM.
THE PROBLEM
IS, I
DON'T DECORATE,
I NEVER
HAVE, I
DON'T ENJOY IT,
I DON'T SEE
THE POINT,
AND I
DON'T WANT TO BUY
THINGS JUST
TO PHOTOGRAPH
THEM AND THROW
THEM AWAY LATER
MY
HOME IS MY
SPACE NOT
A PROP FOR
WORKPLACE MORALE
INSTEAD
OF FAKING
IT I
ANSWERED HONESTLY
I
TOLD HER I
DON'T DECORATE AND
LEFT IT AT THAT
I DIDN'T
CRITICIZE THE
IDEA DIDN'T
MAKE A SCENE
DIDN'T
DEMAND SPECIAL
TREATMENT
I
JUST STATED
A FACT
HER
REACTION WAS
IMMEDIATE AND
SHARP SHE
TOLD ME I
WAS RUINING THE
GAME AS
IF MY REFUSAL
TO STAGE
A FESTIVE
BACKDROP HAD
SINGLE
-HANDEDLY
DERAILED
TEAM SPIRIT
THE
MESSAGE WAS
CLEAR I
SHOULD HAVE PRETENDED
LIED
OR
GONE OUT OF
MY WAY TO
PERFORM JOY
FOR THE SAKE
OF
APPEARANCES.
THAT'S
WHEN IT REALLY
HIT
ME.
AFTER
BEING MANIPULATED
INTO UNPAID
OVERTIME, NOW
I WAS BEING
GUILTED
FOR NOT DECORATING
MY PRIVATE
LIVING SPACE
TO SUPPORT
A MANAGER'S
IDEA OF
FUN.
I WORK
REMOTELY.
MY JOB
PERFORMANCE HAS
NOTHING TO DO
WITH HOW MY HOME
LOOKS.
I'M
NOT WILLING TO
BUY DECORATIONS,
BORROW
THEM, OR
PULL A RANDOM
IMAGE OFF
THE INTERNET JUST
TO KEEP THE
PEACE.
NOW
I'M SITTING WITH
THIS UNCOMFORTABLE
FEELING
THAT HONESTY
MADE ME A
PROBLEM.
AND
THAT NOT PLAYING
ALONG TURNED
ME INTO THE
VILLAIN.
ALL I
DID WAS DRAW
A LINE AROUND
MY OWN HOME
AND MY OWN
TIME.
YET
SOMEHOW THAT
WAS FRAMED
AS SELFISH
AND
DISRUPTIVE.
IT MAKES
ME WONDER
HOW QUICKLY BOUNDARIES
BECOME
OFFENSES WHEN
PEOPLE EXPECT
COMPLIANCE
INSTEAD OF
CONSENT.