I'M A
WOMAN IN MY LATE
30S,
CURRENTLY
IN THE MIDDLE
OF AGGRESSIVE MEDICAL
TREATMENT, AND
TODAY WAS ONE
OF MY HOSPITAL
DAYS, BECAUSE
I PHYSICALLY
COULDN'T MANAGE
CHILDCARE.
MY MOM
CAME OVER TO
WATCH MY TWO
YOUNG KIDS WHILE
I WAS GONE. SHE
ARRIVED, STAYED
JUST LONG ENOUGH
FOR ME TO LEAVE,
AND THEN LEFT
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY
AFTER I
RETURNED HOME.
I WAS DISAPPOINTED
BUT TOO
DRAINED TO ARGUE,
AND I FOCUSED
ON GETTING THROUGH
THE AFTERNOON. NOT
LONG AFTER SHE
LEFT, MY
YOUNGEST KEPT
OPENING THE
REFRIGERATOR, SAYING
SHE WAS HUNGRY.
I ASSUMED
SHE JUST WANTED
A SNACK. SO
I WENT TO HELP
HER AND IMMEDIATELY REALIZED
SOMETHING WAS
WRONG.
THE FRIDGE
WAS ALMOST COMPLETELY
EMPTY.
THE DAY BEFORE,
I HAD DONE
A FULL GROCERY
RUN AND STOPPED
UP FOR THE ENTIRE
WEEK.
MILK, JUICE,
FRUIT, EASY
MEALS, SNACKS,
AND THINGS
I COULD MANAGE
WHILE SICK. EVERY
SINGLE ITEM
WAS GONE. NO
MILK, NO
JUICE, NOTHING
I COULD QUICKLY
GIVE MY KIDS.
IT SLOWLY
DAWNED
ON ME THAT MY MOM
MUST HAVE PACKED
UP THE GROCERIES
AND TAKEN THEM
WITH HER WHEN SHE
LEFT.
I TRIED
CALLING HER
OVER AND OVER,
BUT SHE
WOULDN'T ANSWER.
I THEN CALLED
MY BROTHER, WHO
LIVES ACROSS TOWN,
AND WHEN I
EXPLAINED WHAT
HAD HAPPENED, HE
WAS FURIOUS
AND SAID HE
WOULD CONFRONT HER
DIRECTLY.
MEANWHILE, I
WAS SITTING AT
HOME, WEAK
FROM TREATMENT,
DAYS BEFORE
CHRISTMAS, STARING
AT AN EMPTY
FRIDGE, KNOWING
I COULDN'T EASILY
REPLACE SEVERAL
HUNDRED DOLLARS WORTH
OF FOOD THAT
MY CHILDREN AND
I NEEDED
TO GET THROUGH THE
WEEK.
I FEEL
SICK OVER IT
IN MORE WAYS
THAN ONE. I'M
HURT, ANGRY,
AND HONESTLY
SCARED ABOUT
HOW I'M SUPPOSED
TO MANAGE RIGHT
NOW.
NOW, PART
OF ME IS SERIOUSLY
CONSIDERING TAKING
FORMAL ACTION,
NOT OUT
OF REVENGE, BUT
BECAUSE I DON'T
KNOW HOW ELSE TO
RECOVER WHAT
WAS TAKEN OR
MAKE SURE MY KIDS
ARE FED WHEN
I'M ALREADY
STRETCHED TO
MY LIMIT.