I'M A
29 -YEAR
-OLD BLACK WOMAN
WORKING AS
A TECHNICAL
ASSISTANT.
I EARN
ENOUGH TO LIVE
STEADILY ON
MY OWN, BUT
I'M FAR FROM
WEALTHY.
EVER SINCE
I FINISHED SCHOOL
AND GOT MY FIRST
REAL PAYCHECK,
MY RELATIVES
HAVE EXPECTED
ME TO STEP
IN FINANCIALLY,
PAYING FOR
HOUSEHOLD EXPENSES,
HELPING NIECES
AND NEPHEWS
WITH SUPPLIES, SENDING
MONEY TO
MY FATHER EVERY
MONTH, AND
HANDLING SUDDEN
EXPENSES WHENEVER
THEY POPPED
UP.
IN MY
COMMUNITY, THIS
KIND OF ONGOING
SUPPORT, OFTEN
REFERRED TO
AS BLACK TAX,
IS CONSIDERED
NORMAL
AND EVEN
HONORABLE.
I UNDERSTOOD
THAT GROWING UP,
AND FOR
A LONG TIME
I DIDN'T QUESTION
IT, BUT
OVER THE LAST
YEAR, EVERYTHING
INTENSIFIED,
SUDDENLY I
WAS RESPONSIBLE
FOR COVERING
UTILITY BILLS,
TAKING CARE
OF MY COUSIN'S
MEDICAL COPAY,
AND EVEN
CONTRIBUTING TOWARD
A FAMILY FRIEND'S
ENGAGEMENT
CEREMONY.
MEANWHILE, I'VE
BEEN PUTTING MY
OWN LIFE ON
HOLD, I
WANT TO SAVE FOR
MY OWN HOME,
INVEST IN
MY CAREER, AND
AFFORD COUNSELING,
I TOLD MY
FAMILY THAT
I WOULD STILL HELP
WITH TRUE
NECESSITIES.
BUT I
COULDN'T KEEP FINANCING
EVERYONE'S
LIFESTYLE.
MY FATHER
INSISTED I
WAS TURNING MY
BACK ON MY
DUTIES.
AN AUNT
ACCUSED ME OF
TRYING TO ACT
TOO
INDEPENDENT.
MY YOUNGER
COUSIN SAID
I WAS SELFISH
BECAUSE I
MAKE THE MOST
MONEY.
BUT THE
TRUTH IS,
THEY'VE BEEN ABLE
TO SPLURGE
ON NEW CLOTHES
AND WEEKEND TRIPS
WHILE I WAS
DRAINING MY SAVINGS
TO BAIL
THEM
OUT.
I LOVE THEM
DEEPLY, YET
I'M EXHAUSTED AND
FEEL LIKE I'VE
BEEN EXPECTED TO
SACRIFICE MY
ENTIRE ADULTHOOD
FOR EVERYONE
ELSE'S
COMFORT.
NOW I'M
QUESTIONING WHETHER
FINALLY CHOOSING
TO PRIORITIZE
MY OWN
STABILITY MAKES
ME WRONG OR
WHETHER MY FAMILY
IS SIMPLY UPSET
THAT I'M NO
LONGER WILLING TO
CARRY THE ENTIRE
LOAD
ALONE.