OR ARE
THEY
OVERREACTING?
TODAY, OUR
HOMEROOM
DID A HOLIDAY
GIFT
EXCHANGE.
A CLASSMATE
NAMED LILA
WAS IN CHARGE
OF HANDING OUT
THE SLIPS WITH
EVERYONE'S
ASSIGNED
PERSON.
SHE LET
ME PICK MINE
FROM THE LITTLE
BASKET, AND
I STEPPED OUT
INTO THE HALLWAY
WHERE EVERYONE
ELSE WAS
WAITING.
ALMOST
IMMEDIATELY,
ANOTHER GIRL,
ARIA, ASKED,
DID YOU GET
YOURS
YET?
I NODDED,
AND THEN
SHE FOLLOWED
UP WITH, SO,
WHO'D YOU
PULL?
QUOTE
I
HONESTLY THOUGHT
THIS WAS JUST
A NORMAL QUESTION
NOTHING
ABOUT HER
TONE SOUNDED
LIKE A TRICK
AND
NO ONE REMINDED
ME THAT WE
WEREN'T SUPPOSED TO
SAY ANYTHING
SO
I TOLD HER
THE NAME ON
MY SLIP
THE
SECOND THE
WORDS LEFT
MY MOUTH
THE
ENTIRE HALLWAY
FROZE THEN
THE COMPLAINT
STARTED
LILA
GRABBED ALL
THE PAPERS BACK
ANNOUNCED
WE HAD
TO RESTART THE
WHOLE THING
AND
TOLD ME TO
STEP OUTSIDE
WHILE THEY
FIX THE PROBLEM
WHILE
I WAITED IN
THE CORRIDOR I
COULD CLEARLY
HEAR THEM
TALKING ABOUT
ME CALLING
ME CLUELESS
SAYING
I RUINED THE
FUN AND
ARGUING ABOUT
WHO WOULD GET
STUCK WITH MY
NAME NOW THAT
EVERYTHING HAD
TO BE SHUFFLED
AGAIN.
IT FELT
LIKE THEY WERE
HAPPIER TO
BLAME ME
THAN ADMIT THE
QUESTION SHOULDN'T
HAVE BEEN ASKED
IN THE FIRST
PLACE.
I DIDN'T
MEAN TO SPOIL
ANYTHING.
I GENUINELY
MISUNDERSTOOD,
BUT NOW I
FEEL EMBARRASSED,
UNWANTED,
AND LIKE
EVERYONE THINKS
I SABOTAGED
THE WHOLE EVENT
ON
PURPOSE.
I CAN'T
TELL IF I SHOULD
FEEL GUILTY,
OR IF
THE GIRL WHO
ASKED ME PUT
ME IN AN UNFAIR
SITUATION
TO BEGIN
WITH.