I'M A SENIOR
MANAGER AT
A MID-SIZED TECH
COMPANY, AND
EARLIER THIS YEAR
ONE OF OUR JUNIOR
TEAM MEMBERS
EXPERIENCED A
DEVASTATING LOSS.
HE'S
A 23-YEAR-OLD
ANALYST WHO
HAD BEEN WITH THE COMPANY
FOR JUST UNDER
A YEAR. AND
HIS PERFORMANCE
BEFORE EVERYTHING
HAPPENED WAS
EXCELLENT.
HE WAS
WELL-LIKED,
CONSISTENTLY HIT
HIS TARGETS,
AND THERE HAD
ALREADY BEEN
INTERNAL CONVERSATIONS
ABOUT FAST-TRACKING
HIM INTO A
HIGHER ROLE WITHIN
THE
NEXT SEVERAL
MONTHS.
HIS POSITION
PAYS WELL
FOR SOMEONE EARLY
IN THEIR CAREER,
JUST UNDER
SIX FIGURES
WITH BONUSES
INCLUDED, AND
THE EXPECTATIONS
ATTACHED TO
IT ARE HIGH. IN
EARLY SPRING,
BOTH OF HIS
PARENTS WERE KILLED
IN A SUDDEN ACCIDENT.
IT WAS SHOCKING
AND AWFUL, AND
AS A COMPANY
WE TRIED TO
RESPOND WITH COMPASSION.
WE IMMEDIATELY
APPROVED SEVERAL
WEEKS OF FULLY
PAID LEAVE
AND TOLD HIM
TO TAKE THE TIME
HE NEEDED. AFTER
ABOUT A MONTH
AWAY, HE
RETURNED TO WORK.
UNFORTUNATELY, ONCE
HE WAS BACK,
HIS PERFORMANCE
DROPPED SHARPLY.
HE WAS DISENGAGED,
MISSING DEADLINES,
AND NO LONGER
COMPLETING THE
CORE PARTS OF
HIS ROLE. THIS
WENT ON FOR
A FEW WEEKS,
AND IT
BECAME A CONSISTENT
CONCERN ACROSS
THE LEADERSHIP TEAM.
AFTER MULTIPLE
INTERNAL DISCUSSIONS,
MANAGEMENT DECIDED
THAT THE ROLE
SIMPLY COULDN'T
REMAIN UNFILLED
OR UNDERPERFORMING
FOR AN EXTENDED
PERIOD.
WE FELT
THAT REALISTICALLY,
HE WOULD NEED
A LONG TIME
TO RECOVER EMOTIONALLY,
AND THE
BUSINESS COULDN'T
ABSORB THAT GAP.
WE CALLED
HIM INTO A MEETING
AT THE END OF
THE WEEK AND TOLD
HIM WE WERE LETTING
HIM GO. HE
REACTED VERY
CALMLY AT
FIRST, THEN
LASHED OUT VERBALLY,
TOLD US OFF,
GATHERED HIS
THINGS, AND
LEFT WITHOUT
ANOTHER WORD.
I WAS
TAKEN ABACK
BY HIS REACTION
AND FELT ACROSS
THE LINE.
EVEN GIVEN
THE CIRCUMSTANCES,
WHEN I LATER
EXPLAINED THE
SITUATION TO
MY PARTNER, THEY
WERE FURIOUS ON
HIS BEHALF AND
TOLD ME THAT WHAT
WE DID WAS CRUEL
AND HEARTLESS.
REGARDLESS OF
BUSINESS NEEDS,
I UNDERSTAND
THAT THE LOSS
HE EXPERIENCED
WAS UNIMAGINABLE,
BUT I ALSO
FEEL RESPONSIBLE
FOR THE HEALTH
AND PERFORMANCE OF
THE TEAM AS A
WHOLE.
SO I'M
LEFT WONDERING
IF WE TRULY
HANDLED THIS
WRONG OR IF
THIS WAS AN UNFORTUNATE
BUT NECESSARY
DECISION?