I
WORK AS A
LICENSED ELECTRICIAN
AND I'M PART
OF A
UNION.
SOMETHING
I'VE SPENT
YEARS BUILDING
MY CAREER
AROUND.
MY FORMER
SPOUSE AND
I SHARE CUSTODY
OF OUR THREE
CHILDREN.
AND WHILE
THINGS ARE
CIVIL NOW,
OUR SPLIT
LAST YEAR
WAS ANYTHING BUT
EASY.
NOT
LONG AFTER
THE DIVORCE
WAS FINALIZED,
SHE REMARRIED
A MAN SHE'D
BEEN SEEING FOR
LESS THAN A
YEAR.
I'LL CALL
HIM
DEREK.
THE TENSION
REALLY STARTED
BUBBLING UP
A FEW WEEKS
AGO AT
MY DAUGHTER'S
VOLLEYBALL
GAME.
DEREK
DECIDED
IT WAS THE
PERFECT SETTING
TO LOUDLY
SHARE HIS
OPINIONS ABOUT
HOW REAL
TRADESMEN
DON'T
NEED UNIONS
AND HOW
UNION WORKERS
ARE JUST OVERPAID
AND
LAZY.
HE
SAID THIS
WHILE STANDING
A FEW FEET
FROM ME, FULLY
AWARE THAT
I WAS WEARING
A SHIRT WITH
MY UNION'S
LOGO ACROSS
THE
CHEST.
I DIDN'T
RESPOND.
I
JUST SWALLOWED
IT FOR THE SAKE
OF MY
KID.
DEREK
WORKS IN
A LOOSELY RELATED
FIELD,
DOING SMALL
FREELANCE
TECH AND
NETWORKING JOBS,
BUT HE'S
NOT LICENSED
AT THE LEVEL
1M AND
STRUGGLES TO
KEEP STEADY
INCOME.
COME.
IRONICALLY,
MY CERTIFICATION
ALLOWS
ME TO LEGALLY
PERFORM EVERY
KIND OF JOB
HE DOES
AND
AT A SIGNIFICANTLY
HIGHER
PROFESSIONAL
STANDARD.
THEN, OUT
OF NOWHERE,
MY EX
CALLED ME EARLY
ONE
MORNING.
SHE EXPLAINED
THAT THERE WAS AN
ISSUE WITH
AN ELECTRICAL
PANEL
AT ONE OF
DEREK'S JOB
SITES AND
ASKED
IF I COULD
JUST SWING
BY AND
TAKE A
LOOK.
SHE
FRAMED IT AS
A TINY FAVOR,
SOMETHING
THAT WOULD ONLY
TAKE A FEW
MINUTES, INSISTING
IT WASN'T A
REAL JOB
AND THAT I'D TECHNICALLY
BE HELPING
DEREK
OUT.
SHE
EMPHASIZED HOW
EASY IT
WOULD BE, HOW
LITTLE EFFORT
IT WOULD TAKE
AND
HOW MUCH
IT WOULD MEAN TO
THEM.
I TOLD
HER CALMLY
THAT I DON'T
DO UNPAID WORK,
ESPECIALLY
NOT SIDE
JOBS, AND
THAT UNION RULES
REQUIRE ANY
WORK I
DO TO GO THROUGH
MY SHOP
AT A STANDARD
RATE.
I
SAID DEREK
WAS WELCOME
TO HIRE ME
LIKE ANY OTHER
CLIENT.
THAT'S WHEN
HER TONE
CHANGED.
SHE ACCUSED
ME OF MAKING
THINGS DIFFICULT
ON PURPOSE
AND ASKED
IF I WAS REALLY
GOING TO CAUSE
PROBLEMS
WITH HER
HUSBAND OVER
SOMETHING SO
SMALL.
I REPLIED
THAT DEREK
COULD HIRE HIS
OWN SUBCONTRACTOR
OR PAY ME FAIRLY
LIKE EVERYONE
ELSE
DOES.
I
ALSO MADE
IT CLEAR THAT
I DON'T OFFER
FREE LABOR
TO SOMEONE
WHO OPENLY
DISRESPECTS
MY
PROFESSION.
NOW
I'M BEING TOLD
I'M PETTY,
VINDICTIVE,
AND INTENTIONALLY
CREATING
TENSION, ESPECIALLY
BECAUSE
DEREK LIVES
WITH MY
KIDS.
APPARENTLY,
SETTING
BOUNDARIES
AND EXPECTING
PROFESSIONAL
RESPECT
IS SOMEHOW
ME, STARTING
DRAMA.
MEANWHILE,
I'M LEFT
WONDERING WHEN
BASIC SELF
-RESPECT BECAME
SOMETHING
I WAS SUPPOSED
TO SACRIFICE
JUST TO
KEEP
THE
PEACE.