A
CLOSE FRIEND
OF MINE RECENTLY
JOINED A
FEW DATING APPS
FOR THE FIRST
TIME.
AND
SHE'S BEEN VENTING
NON -STOP ABOUT
HOW DISAPPOINTING
THE EXPERIENCE
HAS
BEEN.
SHE'S IN
HER LATE TEENS
AND OFTEN TALKS
ABOUT WANTING A
RELATIONSHIP.
FEELING
LONELY BEING
SINGLE, AND
HOPING TO FIND
SOMEONE
SOON.
IN TERMS
OF APPEARANCE, SHE'S
PRETTY
AVERAGE.
NOTHING EXTREME
IN EITHER
DIRECTION.
JUST A
NORMAL LOOKING
PERSON.
WITHIN A FEW
DAYS, SHE
STARTED COMPLAINING
THAT NEARLY EVERY
GUY WHO LIKED
HER WAS UNATTRACTIVE,
TOO SHORT,
OR OR
SIMPLY NOT
HER TYPE AND
THAT SHE WASN'T
MATCHING WITH ANY
OF THE PEOPLE SHE
CONSIDERED.
GOOD
LOOKING.
OUT OF CURIOSITY,
I ASKED
HER TO SHOW ME
WHO SHE
MEANT.
WHEN SHE SCROLLED
THROUGH HER
LIKES.
THE GUYS
THERE SEEMED TOTALLY
REASONABLE.
REGULAR.
DECENT LOOKING
PEOPLE WHO
LOOKED ABOUT ON
THE SAME OVERALL
LEVEL AS
HER.
I GENTLY
SUGGESTED
SHE CONSIDER
GIVING SOME
OF THEM A
CHANCE.
ESPECIALLY SINCE
SHE FREQUENTLY
TALKS ABOUT
WANTING A SERIOUS
RELATIONSHIP.
SHE IMMEDIATELY
SHUT THAT
DOWN AND INSISTED
SHE WAS FAR
MORE ATTRACTIVE
THAN THE MEN
LIKING
HER.
I
POINTED OUT
THAT THE PEOPLE SHE
CONSIDERS VERY
ATTRACTIVE AREN'T
MATCHING HER BACK
WHICH
PROBABLY MEANS
THE MATCH IS
UNEVEN THAT
SET HER OFF
AND SHE
SNAPPED THAT I
WAS BEING RUDE
AND INSULTING NOW
SHE SAYS I
CROSSED A LINE
BY TELLING HER
SHE'S NOT ABOVE
THE GUYS SHE'S
DISMISSING I'M
WONDERING IF BEING
STRAIGHTFORWARD ABOUT
THE MISMATCH
BETWEEN HER EXPECTATIONS
AND HER
ACTUAL MATCHES
WAS OUT OF
LINE