A
FEW MONTHS AGO,
I MOVED
IN WITH MY
PARTNER AFTER
WE GOT
MARRIED.
WE'RE BOTH
IN OUR MID
-TWENTIES,
AND WE
DECIDED TO
LIVE WITH HIS
RELATIVES TEMPORARILY
SO
WE COULD SAVE
FOR OUR OWN
PLACE WHILE
I FINISHED
SCHOOL.
BEFORE MOVING
IN, WE
ALL SAT DOWN
TOGETHER, HIS
MOTHER AND
HIS TWO ADULT
SIBLINGS INCLUDED,
AND AGREED
THIS WOULD
BE A SHORT
-TERM ARRANGEMENT
WITH A CLEAR
EXIT
PLAN.
EVEN
IF BUYING A
HOME TOOK
LONGER THAN
EXPECTED, AT
THE TIME,
EVERYONE SEEMED
ON BOARD,
AND I
HAD A GENUINELY
GOOD RELATIONSHIP
WITH HIS
MOTHER.
WHEN
I MOVED IN,
WE AGREED
TO SPLIT HOUSEHOLD
EXPENSES
EVENLY.
EACH MONTH,
HIS MOTHER
WOULD SEND OUT
A MESSAGE WITH
A TOTAL, AND
EVERYONE WOULD
SEND THEIR
SHARE.
FOR THE
FIRST FEW MONTHS,
THIS WORKED
SMOOTHLY.
THEN,
WITHOUT ANY
FAMILY DISCUSSION,
SHE DECIDED
TO BUY SEVERAL
NEW APPLIANCES
FOR THE
HOUSE.
NONE OF
THE EXISTING ONES
WERE BROKEN
OR UNUSABLE,
AND MOST
OF US DIDN'T
EVEN KNOW ABOUT
THE PURCHASES
UNTIL SHORTLY
BEFORE THEY
ARRIVED.
MY
PARTNER AND
ONE OF HIS SIBLINGS
SEPARATELY CHECKED
WITH HER TO CONFIRM
WHETHER THIS
WAS A PERSONAL
UPGRADE OR
SOMETHING SHE
EXPECTED EVERYONE
TO CHIP IN
FOR.
AND BOTH
TIMES SHE
SAID IT WAS HER
DECISION AND
LEFT IT AT
THAT.
THE
FOLLOWING MONTH,
WHEN THE BILL
TOTAL CAME
THROUGH, ONE
OF THE SIBLINGS
NOTICED THE
APPLIANCE COSTS
HAD BEEN QUIETLY
ADDED
IN.
HE
QUESTIONED IT
IN A GROUP CHAT,
POINTING
OUT THAT
THIS HADN'T
BEEN
DISCUSSED.
HER RESPONSE
WAS SIMPLY
THAT SINCE EVERYONE
USES THE
APPLIANCES, EVERYONE
SHOULD PAY
FOR
THEM.
THE THREE
OF US WHO HAD
ALREADY CLARIFIED
THIS WASN'T
A SHARED PURCHASE
TALKED IT
THROUGH AND SENT
OUR
PORTIONS
MINUS THE
APPLIANCE
COSTS.
ANOTHER
SIBLING,
WHO USUALLY
AVOIDS
CONFLICT, ATE
THE FULL
AMOUNT.
THAT EVENING,
SHE CAME
HOME EXTREMELY
UPSET.
A TENSE
CONVERSATION
FOLLOWED,
WHERE WE
CALMLY REITERATED
THAT WE WEREN'T
REFUSING TO
CONTRIBUTE OUT
OF SPITE, BUT
BECAUSE WE
HAD EXPLICITLY
CHECKED
BEFOREHAND
AND WERE
TOLD THIS WASN'T
A SHARED
EXPENSE.
I
TRIED TO SPEAK
AS LITTLE AS
POSSIBLE, LETTING
MY PARTNER
HANDLE MOST
OF IT, BUT
I DID EXPLAIN
THAT WHAT HURT
WAS THE LACK
OF
TRANSPARENCY.
ESPECIALLY
SINCE
WE TRUSTED HER
ENOUGH TO NEVER
QUESTION THE
TOTALS SHE
SENT
BEFORE.
SHE
ACCUSED US
OF BEING UNGRATEFUL
AND REMINDED
US THAT
LIVING ELSEWHERE
WOULD COST
FAR
MORE.
A
FEW DAYS LATER,
SHE BEGAN
ASKING POINTED
QUESTIONS ABOUT
WHEN WE PLANNED
TO LEAVE AND
STARTED SENDING
PASSIVE
-AGGRESSIVE
MESSAGES WITH
RENTAL LISTINGS
AND COMMENTS
ABOUT HOW EXPENSIVE
LIFE OUTSIDE
HER HOUSE
REALLY
IS.
NOW THE
ATMOSPHERE
FEELS TENSE,
AND
I CAN'T TELL
IF STANDING OUR
GROUND WAS
REASONABLE OR
IF WE DAMAGED
THE RELATIONSHIP
BY REFUSING
TO QUIETLY
GO ALONG
WITH
IT.