I, 25M,
HAVE BEEN BAKING
AS A HOBBY
FOR A FEW YEARS
AND HAVE GOTTEN PRETTY
GOOD AT IT.
SOMETIMES PEOPLE
EVEN PAY
ME UNDER THE TABLE
FOR BIRTHDAYS
OR SHOWERS.
SO WHEN
MY SISTER, MIA,
ASKED ME
TO MAKE THE CAKE
FOR HER GENDER
REVEAL, I
WAS EXCITED. I
ASKED HER TO
TELL ME THE BABY'S
GENDER SO I
COULD PLAN THE FILLING.
CLASSIC PINK
OR BLUE, BUT
SHE JUST SMILED
AND SAID SHE WANTED
TO BE SURPRISED
TOO.
JUST MAKE
IT NEUTRAL, SHE
SAID, AND
WE'LL ALL SEE
TOGETHER.
I
WAS A LITTLE
CONFUSED.
SO SHE WANTED
A REVEAL CAKE
THAT DIDN'T REVEAL
ANYTHING?
SHE PROMISED
HER FRIEND WOULD
EMAIL ME THE
INFO.
BUT THE EMAIL
NEVER CAME.
THE DEADLINE
CAME AND
WENT.
AND I STILL
DIDN'T KNOW THE
GENDER.
I DIDN'T
WANT TO GUESS AND
RISK MESSING IT
UP.
SO I MADE
THE CAKE ENTIRELY
GRAY.
GRAY INSIDE,
GRAY OUTSIDE,
WITH LITTLE FONDANT
CLOUDS AND
SILVER SPRINKLES.
IT TASTED
FINE, BUT
VISUALLY IT
LOOKED LIKE A STORM
CLOUD.
ON THE REVEAL
DAY, THE
FAMILY GATHERED
AROUND.
THEY CUT THE
CAKE.
SILENCE.
MIA LOOKED
FURIOUS.
HER HUSBAND,
AND CONNOR
STARED
AT THE GRAY CAKE
LIKE I HAD
PERSONALLY RUINED
THE MOMENT. COUSINS
WHISPERED
BEHIND HANDS.
MY MOTHER
PIPED UP,
WHY WOULD YOU
MAKE IT GRAY? IT
LOOKS PASSIVE-AGGRESSIVE.
I CALMLY
EXPLAINED THAT
NO ONE HAD GIVEN
ME THE GENDER
AND I WASN'T
GOING TO GAMBLE ON
A CAKE. MIA
STORMED OUT,
MUTTERING ABOUT
HOW I HAD
RUINED EVERYTHING.
MY MOM
SAID I EMBARRASSED
THE FAMILY
AND SHOULD
HAVE TRIED HARDER.
TRIED HARDER
AT WHAT, EXACTLY?
DIVINING THE
BABY'S GENDER
THROUGH VIBES?
THE CAKE BECAME
A LEGEND. DRAMATIC,
MOODY, COMPLETELY
NEUTRAL, AND
HONESTLY, COULD
ANYONE ELSE
HAVE HANDLED THIS
SITUATION BETTER?