WHAT SHOULD
HAVE BEEN A ROUTINE
HOLIDAY ROAD
TRIP HAS TURNED
INTO A LINGERING
ARGUMENT THAT
STILL HASN'T
COOLED DOWN WEEKS
LATER.
EVERY WINTER,
OUR FAMILY
PILES INTO
THE CAR TO VISIT
MY PARTNER'S
PARENTS.
IT'S A LONG
DRIVE, HOURS
ON THE ROAD,
CUTTING THROUGH
DENSE TRAFFIC,
UNPREDICTABLE WEATHER,
AND MILES
OF BRAKE LIGHTS,
BECAUSE SHE
HATES DRIVING
IN HEAVY CONGESTION
AND GETS
ANXIOUS BEHIND
THE WHEEL. I
ALWAYS DRIVE,
THAT PART ISN'T
UP FOR DEBATE. SHE
ALSO STRUGGLES
WITH MOTION SICKNESS.
WHICH MEANS
SHE INSISTS ON
RIDING IN THE
FRONT SEAT, SINCE
SHE CAN'T TAKE
STANDARD MOTION
SICKNESS MEDS
AFTER A BAD REACTION
YEARS AGO. HERE'S
THE PROBLEM, SHE
IS A NIGHTMARE PASSENGER.
I DON'T
SAY THAT LIGHTLY.
I'M A CAUTIOUS
DRIVER WITH
A CLEAN RECORD.
NO ACCIDENTS,
NO TICKETS,
NO RISKY
BEHAVIOR.
I SLOW DOWN
EARLY, LEAVE
SPACE, AND
STAY ALERT, BUT
THE MOMENT A
CAR THREE LANES
OVERTAPS ITS
BRAKES, SHE
GASPS LIKE WE'RE
ABOUT TO COLLIDE.
SHE GRABS
THE DOOR HANDLE,
HANDLE.
SLAPS
HER PALM AGAINST
THE DASHBOARD.
INHALES SHARPLY.
AND BLURTS
OUT WARNINGS NON-STOP.
WATCH OUT.
SLOW DOWN.
OH MY GOD.
OVER AND OVER.
FOR HOURS.
IT'S RELENTLESS.
I'VE TRIED TO
EXPLAIN.
CALMLY.
REPEATEDLY.
THAT HER REACTIONS
ACTUALLY MAKE
IT HARDER FOR
ME TO FOCUS.
WHEN SOMEONE
BESIDE YOU
KEEPS REACTING
LIKE DISASTER
IS SECONDS
AWAY.
IT PLANTS
DOUBT WHERE THERE
DOESN'T NEED TO
BE ANY. SHE
ALWAYS RESPONDS
THE SAME WAY.
SHE'S NERVOUS.
SHE CAN'T
HELP IT. AND
IF SHE'S REACTING
THAT STRONGLY,
IT MUST
BE BECAUSE I'M
DRIVING BADLY.
THE DRIVE
TO HER PARENTS'
PLACE WAS MISERABLE.
THE WEATHER WAS
ICY, TRAFFIC
CRAWLED,
AND THE TENSION
IN THE FRONT SEAT
FELT THICKER
THAN THE FOG
ON THE WINDSHIELD.
BY THE
TIME WE ARRIVED,
I WAS EXHAUSTED,
NOT FROM THE
ROAD, BUT
FROM BEING CONSTANTLY
SECOND-GUESSED
AND STARTLED.
SO WHEN
IT WAS TIME TO
HEAD HOME, I
MADE A DECISION.
I TOLD
HER I COULDN'T DO
ANOTHER DRIVE
LIKE THAT. I
SAID SHE COULD EITHER
SIT IN THE BACK
SEAT, OR
SHE COULD DRIVE.
SHE IMMEDIATELY
ACCUSED ME
OF BEING CRUEL,
REMINDING ME
OF HER MOTION
SICKNESS AND
SAYING I WAS HUMILIATING
HER.
I
SUGGESTED SHE
REST, OR
TRY TO SLEEP
THROUGH THE DRIVE,
THAT ONLY
MADE THINGS WORSE.
SHE REFUSED
TO DRIVE,
REFUSED TO
CONSIDER ANY
COMPROMISE, AND
FINALLY CLIMBED
INTO THE BACKSEAT
BESIDE OUR YOUNGER
CHILD IN SILENCE.
THE
DIFFERENCE WAS
NIGHT AND DAY.
THE ROAD HOME
WAS CALMER.
NOT JUST
TRAFFIC-WISE,
BUT EMOTIONALLY.
NO GASPS,
NO GRABBING,
NO RUNNING
COMMENTARY ON
EVERY CAR WITHIN
SIGHT.
JUST QUIET
AND FOCUS.
SHE DIDN'T
SAY A WORD THE
ENTIRE DRIVE.
WHEN WE
GOT GOT HOME, THAT
SILENCE EXPLODED,
SHE TOLD ME
SHE FELT NAUSEOUS
THE WHOLE TIME
AND CHOSE NOT
TO SAY ANYTHING
BECAUSE SHE
DIDN'T WANT TO
MAKE A BIG DEAL,
SHE SAID
BEING SENT TO
THE BACKSEAT MADE
HER FEEL SMALL,
DISMISSED,
AND DEEPLY HURT,
THAT I CHOSE
MY COMFORT
OVER HER PHYSICAL
WELL-BEING,
I TOLD
HER I CHOSE
SAFETY AND
SANITY AFTER
YEARS OF ASKING
HER TO STOP BEHAVIOR
SHE ADMITS
SHE CAN'T
CONTROL, NOW
SHE'S STILL ANGRY,
AND I'M STILL
CONFLICTED,
I DIDN'T WANT
TO EMBARRASS HER,
BUT I ALSO
DIDN'T WANT TO SPEND
ANOTHER MULTI-HOUR
DRIVE ON EDGE,
MESSAGE
FIGHTING DISTRACTIONS
I'VE REPEATEDLY
SAID ARE DANGEROUS
SO
DID I PROTECT EVERYONE
IN THE CAR OR
DID I GO TOO FAR