I'M A
FULL-TIME PARENT
TO TWO YOUNG KIDS,
AND MY SPOUSE
WORKS LONG
HOURS IN A
TECHNICAL JOB.
FOR THE LAST
SEVERAL MONTHS,
HE'S BEEN
OBSESSIVELY
SAVING MONEY
FOR AN OVERSEAS
SPORTS TRIP,
CUTTING BACK
ON HOUSEHOLD
SPENDING SO
HE COULD AFFORD IT.
I TRIED
NOT TO COMPLAIN,
EVEN THOUGH
IT MEANT TIGHTER
GROCERIES AND
NO EXTRAS, BECAUSE
HE KEPT SAYING
THIS WAS THE
ONE THING HE
WAS FINALLY DOING
FOR HIMSELF.
WHEN WE
TALKED ABOUT THE
HOLIDAYS, HE
TOLD ME NOT
TO WORRY AND
SAID I SHOULD HANDLE
EVERYTHING BECAUSE
HE WOULDN'T BE
BACK UNTIL JUST
DAYS
BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
HE CLAIMED
HE'D SET ASIDE MONEY
FOR DECORATIONS,
FOOD,
AND GIFTS
FOR THE KIDS.
WHEN I
FINALLY SAW
THE AMOUNT, IT
WAS BARELY ENOUGH
TO COVER A
SINGLE GROCERY
RUN, LET
ALONE AN ENTIRE
HOLIDAY FOR
A FAMILY. I
WAS STUNNED AND
TOLD HIM IT WASN'T
REALISTIC.
HE BRUSHED
IT OFF AND REMINDED
ME THAT HE WAS
ALSO HELPING
COVER TRAVEL
COSTS FOR
FRIENDS JOINING
HIM
ON THE TRIP,
THEN TOLD ME
TO MAKE IT WORK.
I TOLD
HIM FLAT OUT
THAT IF THAT WAS
TRULY ALL THE
MONEY HE PLANNED
TO LEAVE, THEN
I WASN'T GOING
TO PRETEND EVERYTHING
WAS FINE
AND MAGICALLY CREATE
A HOLIDAY OUT
OF NOTHING WE
ARGUED FOR
DAYS GOING
IN CIRCLES
UNTIL
HE LEFT FOR
HIS TRIP ANYWAY
AFTER
HE WAS GONE
I FOUND
AN ENVELOPE WITH
THE SAME SMALL
AMOUNT OF CASH
AND A NOTE
TELLING ME AGAIN
TO
FIGURE IT OUT
I MESSAGED
HIM AND SAID I'D
MADE MY DECISION
THERE
WOULD BE NO BIG
HOLIDAY THIS
YEAR IF THIS WAS
ALL WE HAD TO
WORK WITH HE
COMPLETELY LOST
IT HE
SENT MESSAGE
AFTER MESSAGE
ACCUSING ME
OF BEING UNGRATEFUL
CALLING
ME SPOILED
AND SAYING
I WAS DELIBERATELY
RUINING THE
KID'S HOLIDAY
TO PUNISH
HIM FOR GOING AWAY.
ACCORDING TO
HIM, I
WAS TRYING TO
GUILT HIM OVER MONEY
HE EARNED HIMSELF.
I HAVEN'T
RESPONDED SINCE.
FROM MY
PERSPECTIVE, I
WASN'T CANCELING
ANYTHING OUT OF
SPITE.
I JUST
REFUSED TO
CARRY THE EMOTIONAL
AND FINANCIAL
BURDEN ALONE
WHILE HE ENJOYED
A LUXURY TRIP.
BUT NOW
HE'S FURIOUS,
AND I'M LEFT
WONDERING IF
HOLDING MY GROUND
REALLY MAKES
ME THE VILLAIN HERE.