SO I'M
TURNING 34,
AND MY
FRIEND ROWAN
WAS RIDICULOUSLY
EXCITED
ABOUT MY
BIRTHDAY PRESENT
THIS
YEAR.
HE
KEPT TELLING
ME I WAS
ABSOLUTELY GOING
TO FREAK OUT
IN A GOOD
WAY.
WHEN
THE DAY ROLLED
AROUND, HE
HANDED ME
THIS NEATLY WRAPPED
BOX,
AND INSIDE
WAS A PAIR
OF NOISE -SHIELDING
EARMUFFS MEANT
FOR MY
DOG.
FOR CONTEXT,
I HAVE A
TINY MARU
ISLAND TERRIER
WHO TREATS
ANYTHING MADE
OF FABRIC
LIKE IT OWES
HER
MONEY.
SHE'S ADORABLE,
BUT SHE
DESTROYS
EVERYTHING, AND
SHE ABSOLUTELY
HATES
HAVING ANYTHING
ON HER
HEAD.
I'VE TRIED
SIMILAR THINGS
BEFORE, AND
THEY NEVER LASTED
MORE THAN
A FEW
MINUTES.
ROWAN
KNOWS ALL OF
THIS.
JUST
TO BE CLEAR,
I DIDN'T
TURN DOWN THE
GIFT BECAUSE
IT WAS TECHNICALLY
FOR MY
DOG.
IF
IT WERE SOMETHING
SHE'D ENJOY
OR ACTUALLY
USE, I
WOULD'VE ACCEPTED
IT WITHOUT
HESITATION.
I TURNED
IT DOWN BECAUSE
I KNEW IT
WOULD END UP
RIPPED APART
INSTANTLY.
LATER,
I FOUND
OUT HE SPENT
AROUND $50
ON THEM,
AND I
WOULD'VE FELT AWFUL
WATCHING HER
DESTROY SOMETHING
THAT
PRICEY.
I
THANKED HIM,
TOLD HIM
I APPRECIATED
THE THOUGHT,
AND EXPLAINED
WHY IT WOULDN'T
WORK.
I GENUINELY
TRIED TO
BE GENTLE ABOUT
IT.
I'LL ADMIT
I DID FIND
IT A LITTLE STRANGE
THAT HE GOT
MY DOG SOMETHING
FOR MY
BIRTHDAY.
NOW
ROWAN ISN'T
ANSWERING MY
MESSAGES OR
CALLS AT ALL,
WHICH MAKES
ME WONDER IF
I UNINTENTIONALLY
HURT HIS FEELINGS
OR IF HE'S
JUST
EMBARRASSED.
SO,
WAS I
WRONG FOR
DECLINING THE
GIFT?