MY
COUSIN, I'LL
CALL HER MARIN,
ADOPTED A
FLUFFY RETRIEVER
PUP LAST
YEAR AFTER
HER PARTNER
IN OSLO,
NORWAY CLAIMED
A DOG WOULD
HELP HER FEEL
CENTERED.
THEY BROKE
UP LESS THAN
FIVE DAYS
LATER.
ABOUT
SEVEN MONTHS
AGO, MARIN
CALLED ME
SOBBING,
SAYING SHE
NEEDED A
BRIEF PAUSE
FROM CARING
FOR
HIM.
SHE PROMISED
IT WOULD BE THREE
DAYS.
NO
MORE.
I'M 22,
JUGGLING
A MUSEUM
INTERNSHIP AND
EVENING CLASSES
IN
VALENCIA.
BUT I'VE
ALWAYS LOVED
ANIMALS.
SO
I
AGREED.
READ.
THOSE THREE
DAYS STRETCHED
INTO MORE
THAN HALF A
YEAR.
MARIN STOPPED
CHECKING IN
ENTIRELY.
SHE STOPPED
SENDING ANY
MONEY.
SHE EVEN
REMOVED ME
FROM HER SOCIAL
MEDIA WHILE
STILL POSTING
BEACH TRIPS,
ROOFTOP
PARTIES,
AND A
NEW ROMANCE
EVERY OTHER
WEEK.
MEANWHILE,
HER DOG,
A WARM,
HONEY -COLORED
RETRIEVER
WITH A GOOFY
GRIN, BECAME
PART OF MY
LIFE.
HE CURLS
UP AGAINST MY
LEGS EVERY
NIGHT, TROTS
BEHIND ME
FROM ROOM TO
ROOM, AND
PLAYS GENTLY
WITH MY TWO
OLDER CATS
LIKE HE'S
ALWAYS BELONG
HERE I'VE
COVERED EVERYTHING
VETS
FOOD
GROOMING
TRAINING
GEAR EASILY
OVER 900
EUROS
BY NOW
THEN
TWO DAYS
AGO SHE
SUDDENLY REAPPEARED
WITH A CHEERFUL
I'M
FINALLY FEELING
BALANCED AGAIN
CAN
YOU BRING MY
DOG BACK THIS
WEEKEND AS
IF SHE HADN'T
VANISHED FOR
HALF A YEAR
I
TOLD HER I
WAS GLAD SHE
WAS DOING BETTER
BUT
SHE HAD WALKED
AWAY FROM
HIM FOR MONTHS
AND
TAKING HIM
FROM A STEADY
HOME NOW
WOULD BE DEEPLY
UNFAIR THAT'S
WHEN SHE ERUPTED
LONG
MESSAGES
ACCUSING ME
OF DESTROYING
THROWING HER LIFE,
CLAIMING I
STOLE HER
COMPANION, AND
THREATENING
TO INVOLVE
AUTHORITIES.
MY MOTHER
TOOK HER SIDE,
INSISTING
THAT FAMILY
SHOULD COOPERATE,
BUT MY AUNT
QUIETLY TOLD
ME SHE WAS
PROUD OF ME
FOR GIVING
THE DOG
THE STABILITY MARIN
NEVER
MANAGED.
I
TOLD MARIN
THAT IF SHE
TRULY INTENDED
TO TAKE
HIM BACK,
SHE
NEEDED TO
REIMBURSE THE
MONEY I'D
SPENT AND
SIGN A CLEAR
AGREEMENT ACCEPTING
FULL ONGOING
RESPONSIBILITY.
SHE
REFUSED IMMEDIATELY,
TELLING ME
TO STAY GONE
FOREVER, AND
IS NOW TELLING
RELATIVES I
SNATCHED HER
DOG, EVEN
THOUGH HE'S
CURRENTLY ASLEEP
WITH HIS
HEAD ON MY
KNEE, SAFE
AND TRUSTING,
WAS I
WRONG TO KEEP
CARING FOR
THE DOG SHE
ABANDONED?
OR IS
SHE FURIOUS
ONLY BECAUSE
SHE SUDDENLY
WANTS SOMETHING
SHE DIDN'T
BOTHER TO
KEEP?