I'M IN MY
MID -TWENTIES,
WORKING
IRREGULAR HOURS
IN HEALTHCARE WHILE
LIVING WITH MY
MOM.
SHE OWNS
THE HOUSE OUTRIGHT,
AND I PAY
HER REDUCED RENT
AND HANDLE MOST
OF THE CHORES BECAUSE
OUR SCHEDULES
ARE
CHAOTIC.
SHE'S SELF
-EMPLOYED AND
OFTEN
TRAVELS.
LAST WEEK,
MY OLDER
SISTER, LENA,
HER HUSBAND EVAN,
AND THEIR SEVEN
-YEAR -OLD DAUGHTER
MOVED IN
TEMPORARILY.
THEIR HOUSE TURNED
OUT TO HAVE MAJOR
PLUMBING AND
HEATING ISSUES THAT
WILL TAKE WEEKS TO
REPAIR SO
STAYING WITH THIS
MADE THE MOST SENSE
A
DAY AFTER THEY
ARRIVED LENA
ASKED IF I
COULD TAKE THEIR DAUGHTER
TO SCHOOL EVERY
MORNING THE
SCHOOL IS A
SHORT WALK FROM
OUR MOM'S HOUSE
MINUTES FLAT
SIDEWALKS
CROSSWALKS
EVERYTHING BUT
LENA AND EVAN
NORMALLY RELY
ON A NEIGHBOR
FOR DROP -OFFS
AND
EVAN'S JOB STARTS
VERY EARLY
THEY
SHARE ONE CAR
AND
LENA ONLY
WORKS ONE WEEKEND
SHIFT SO
SHE'S USUALLY
HOME I
TOLD HER I COULDN'T
COMMIT TO DOING
MORNING SCHOOL
RUNS BECAUSE
MY OWN SHIFTS ARE
ALL OVER THE PLACE
SOMETIMES
I GET
OFF AT 9
OR 10 A .M
AFTER AN OVERNIGHT
SHIFT AND
OTHER TIMES
I'M CLOCKING
IN BEFORE SUNRISE
THERE
IS NO WORLD
WHERE MY BOSS
WOULD ACCEPT ME
SAYING SORRY
I NEED
MY MORNINGS FREE
FOR SCHOOL DROP
OFF WITHOUT
CUTTING MY HOURS
WHICH
I CAN'T AFFORD
INSTEAD
OF DISCUSSING
IT LENA
GOT EMOTIONAL
AND SAID SHE
NEEDED ME TO DO
THIS THAT
WOULD JUST MAKE
THINGS EASIER
WHEN
I GENTLY POINTED
OUT THAT SHE
COULD SIMPLY WALK
HER DAUGHTER
TO SCHOOL SINCE
SINCE SHE'S HOME MOST
MORNINGS, SHE
SAID THAT A 15
-MINUTE WALK
WAS TOO LONG
FOR A YOUNG
KID.
I EVEN
PULLED UP THE DISTANCE
ON MY PHONE,
THINKING SHE
HADN'T REALIZED
HOW CLOSE
IT
WAS.
BUT SHE DOUBLED
DOWN.
I TOLD
HER I COULDN'T
TAKE ON DAILY
DROP -OFFS
AND THAT WALKING
REALLY WAS THE
SIMPLEST
SOLUTION.
LATER, MY
MOM TOLD ME
LENA HAD GONE
TO HER CRYING ABOUT
IT.
MOM SAID
IT WOULD BE A KIND
THING FOR ME TO
HELP.
BUT SHE
ALSO ACKNOWLEDGED
THAT MY SCHEDULE
IS UNPREDICTABLE AND
DIDN'T PUSH
FURTHER.
NOW EVAN
IS CALLING ME
SELFISH.
FISH INSISTING
IT'S A SMALL ASK
SINCE THEIR OLD
NEIGHBOR COULD DO
IT BUT
THEIR OLD NEIGHBOR
ALSO DIDN'T
WORK ROTATING
SHIFTS AND
WASN'T COMING OFF
10 HOUR NIGHTS
I
FEEL LIKE I'M
LOSING MY MIND
BECAUSE
WHEN I WENT
TO THAT SAME SCHOOL
MY
MOM LITERALLY
WALKED ME EVERY
MORNING FROM
THE SAME HOUSE
SO
WAS I REALLY IN
THE WRONG FOR
TELLING LENA
SHE NEEDS TO
WALK HER DAUGHTER INSTEAD
OF EXPECTING
ME
TO REARRANGE MY
WORK LIFE