MY PARTNER'S
BIRTHDAY IS
COMING UP IN A
COUPLE OF
WEEKS.
AND SHE
MENTIONED WANTING
TO SPEND A
NIGHT OR TWO
SOMEWHERE AWAY
FROM
HOME.
MAYBE A
HOTEL OR
A SHORT LITTLE
ESCAPE.
SHE ALSO
SAID SHE'D LIKE
TO INVOLVE HER SISTER
IN THE
PLANS.
I CONSIDERED
ORGANIZING SOMETHING
A BIT
SPECIAL.
MAYBE EVEN
A SMALL DOMESTIC
TRIP.
WE LIVE
IN CANADA, BUT
SHE DIDN'T WANT
TO TRAVEL
FAR.
WE HAVE
KIDS WE CAN'T
REALLY BE AWAY
FROM
OVERNIGHT.
AND HER SISTER
HAS KIDS AS
WELL.
THE ISSUE
IS THAT WHENEVER
I BRING UP
IDEAS.
PLACES TO
STAY.
THINGS TO DO,
POSSIBLE
LOCATIONS.
SHE SHOWS
ALMOST NO
ENTHUSIASM.
EVEN A
BASIC HOTEL
STAY AROUND
HERE WOULD RUN
AT LEAST $350
FOR
A COUPLE OF
NIGHTS.
ESPECIALLY THIS
CLOSE TO THE
HOLIDAYS.
SO I
WANTED TO MAKE SURE
SHE WAS GENUINELY
INTERESTED BEFORE
SPENDING THAT
MUCH.
I ARRANGED
A CALL WITH
HER SISTER SO
WE COULD ALL TALK
ABOUT
POSSIBILITIES.
BUT SHE
DIDN'T ENGAGE AT
ALL AND WALKED
AWAY HALFWAY
THROUGH.
WHEN I TRY
TO DISCUSS OPTIONS,
I GET
THE USUAL SHORT
RESPONSES
LIKE, WHATEVER
YOU THINK,
OR, IT
DOESN'T MATTER,
WHICH MAKES IT
REALLY
HARD TO PLAN
ANYTHING MEANINGFUL
I
KNOW SHE'D PROBABLY
PREFER IF
I HANDLED EVERYTHING
FROM START
TO FINISH BUT
WITH MONEY BEING
TIGHT AROUND THIS
SEASON IT
FELT REASONABLE
TO EXPECT
AT LEAST A
LITTLE BIT OF INPUT
ON
TOP OF THAT
THE LAST
TWO TIMES I
ORGANIZED FAMILY
TRIPS SHE
SPENT MOST OF
THE TIME INSIDE
THE HOTEL OR
SAID SHE DIDN'T
FEEL COMFORTABLE IN
THE AREA SO
I DIDN'T WANT TO
REPEAT OF THAT
HER
SISTER EVENTUALLY
BACKED
OUT BECAUSE OF
THE COST AND
WITH NO REAL
GUIDANCE FROM
MY PARTNER I
DECIDED NOT
TO BOOK ANYTHING
I
TOLD HER WE COULD
JUST GO OUT
FOR A NICE DINNER
INSTEAD.
NOW SHE'S
UPSET, DESPITE
BARELY REACTING
WHENEVER I
TRIED INVOLVING
HER IN THE
PLANNING.
SO NOW
I'M WONDERING,
WAS IT WRONG
NOT TO ARRANGE
A GETAWAY
WHEN SHE DIDN'T
SHOW ANY INTEREST
IN HELPING CHOOSE
ANYTHING?