I'M
IN MY MID
-TWENTIES,
AND MY
CLOSEST FRIEND
AND I HAVE ALWAYS
BEEN A PACKAGE
DEAL.
SHE
STILL CLINGS
TIGHTLY TO
A GROUP OF OLD
FRIENDS FROM
HER SCHOOL DAYS,
MOST
OF WHOM NOW
LIVE IN DIFFERENT
COUNTRIES
AND ONLY SHOW
UP
OCCASIONALLY.
I
DON'T DISLIKE
THEM, BUT
THEY HAVE A
PATTERN.
PLANS
ARE OPTIONAL,
COMMITMENTS
ARE FLEXIBLE,
AND SOMEONE
ELSE ALWAYS
ENDS UP PICKING
UP THE
PIECES.
LAST
WINTER, SHE
HOSTED A
HOLIDAY NIGHT
FOR THEM AFTER
THEIR PLANS
COLLAPSED, AND
IT TURNED INTO
JUST THE TWO
OF US COOKING,
WORKING, CLEANING,
AND SCRAMBLING
WHILE EVERYONE
ELSE DRIFTED
IN AND
OUT.
SHE WAS
FURIOUS AFTERWARD
AND SWORE
SHE WAS DONE
CHASING
PEOPLE.
SO THIS
YEAR, MONTHS
IN ADVANCE,
I SUGGESTED
SOMETHING SIMPLE
AND
INTENTIONAL.
MY MOTHER
HAD ACCESS
TO A QUIET
RENTAL IN
A SNOWY MOUNTAIN
TOWN.
AND
I OFFERED
THAT THE THREE
OF US SPEND
THE HOLIDAY
THERE
TOGETHER.
IT
TOOK REAL EFFORT
TO
ARRANGE.
AND IT
WASN'T
CHEAP.
BUT MY FRIEND
IMMEDIATELY AGREED
AND SAID SHE
WAS RELIEVED
TO HAVE A SOLID
PLAN.
I
TOLD HER MORE
THAN ONCE
THAT IF SHE CHANGED
HER MIND
AND WANTED
TO BE WITH HER
OLD FRIENDS
INSTEAD.
SAID.
SHE
JUST NEEDED
TO SAY SO
EARLY.
SHE
PROMISED SHE
WOULDN'T.
WEEKS
LATER, SHE
CASUALLY MENTIONED
THAT HER OLD
FRIEND GROUP
HAD DECIDED
TO BE IN
THE SAME TOWN
FOR THE
HOLIDAY.
I
WAS SURPRISED
BUT TRIED
TO STAY POSITIVE,
SUGGESTING
DAYTIME
PLANS
AND ASSURING
HER AGAIN THAT
SHE COULD BACK
OUT IF SHE
WANTED.
SHE
INSISTED SHE
WAS STAYING
WITH
US.
EVENTUALLY,
MY MOM
EVEN INVITED
MY FRIEND'S
PARENT AND
SIBLING SO
NO ONE WOULD
FEEL AWKWARD
OR
ALONE.
AND
SHE PAID
FOR THE WHOLE
STAY.
AT THAT
POINT, IT
FELT LOCKED
IN.
THEN,
OUT OF
NOWHERE, MY
FRIEND MESSAGED
ME SAYING SHE'D
DECIDED TO
SPEND THE ACTUAL
HOLIDAY
NIGHT WITH
HER OLD
FRIENDS.
INSTEAD, NOT
ASKING, TELLING,
SHE SAID
HER OWN PARENT
WAS FINE
WITH IT AND ASSUMED
EVERYONE ELSE
WOULD BE
TOO.
WHEN I
ASKED WHAT THAT
MEANT FOR HER
FAMILY, SHE
EXPLAINED THEY'D
JUST STAY BEHIND
WITH ME
AND MY MOM
WHILE SHE WENT
OUT.
SHE BRUSHED
OFF MY DISCOMFORT
AND SAID
IT WAS ONLY
ONE NIGHT,
AND THAT WE'D
STILL HAVE THE
REST OF THE
TRIP
TOGETHER.
THE MORE
SHE TALKED,
THE WORSE
IT
SOUNDED.
SHE
ADMITTED SHE'D
BEEN THE ONE
TO INVITE HER
OLD FRIENDS
TO TOWN
AND SAID SHE'D
FEEL MISERABLE
KNOWING
THEY WERE NEARBY
WITHOUT CELEBRATING
WITH THEM
SHE
EVEN FRAMED
IT LIKE SHE'D
DONE ME A FAVOR
BY AGREEING
TO BRING HER
FAMILY ALONG
SO I WOULDN'T
BE
LONELY AS
IF I HADN'T
BUILT THIS ENTIRE
PLAN AROUND
HER IT
FELT LIKE
I'D BEEN REDUCED
TO THE SAFE
BACKUP OPTION
THE
ONE WHO ORGANIZES
PAYS
AND
ACCOMMODATES
IT DOESN'T
GET CHOSEN
WHEN IT ACTUALLY
COUNTS SO
I CANCELED
EVERYTHING I
TOLD HER SHE
SHOULD GO ENJOY
THE HOLIDAY
EXACTLY HOW
SHE WANTED
WITHOUT
DRAGGING HALF
KEPT PROMISES
BEHIND HER
SHE
SEEMED RELIEVED
APOLOGIZED
VAGUELY
FOR NOT
NOT REALIZING
SOONER AND
THEN TURNED
IT ON
ME.
SAYING I
WAS RIGID
FOR NOT JUST
GOING ALONG
WITH IT AND
LEAVING MY
MOTHER
BEHIND.
SINCE THEN,
SHE'S
BARELY SPOKEN
TO ME, ACTING
LIKE I'M THE
ONE WHO BLEW
THINGS UP
BY EXPECTING
ONE NIGHT
TO STAY THE
SAME.