AFTER NEARLY
SEVEN YEARS
TOGETHER, I
THOUGHT I UNDERSTOOD
MY PARTNER'S
FAMILY DYNAMICS.
BUT HIS
GRADUATION WEEKEND
PUSHED EVERYTHING
OVER THE EDGE.
HIS RELATIVES
HAVE ALWAYS STRUGGLED
WITH MONEY, YET
SOMEHOW STILL
MANAGED TO
SPEND FAR BEYOND
THEIR LIMITS,
LIVING AS
IF CONSEQUENCES
DON'T APPLY.
WHEN MY
PARTNER FINISHED
HIS DEGREE,
MY OWN
FAMILY DROVE
SEVERAL HOURS
TO CELEBRATE HIM,
AND I MADE
IT CLEAR AHEAD
OF TIME THAT
HIS FAMILY SHOULD
BE PREPARED TO
COVER THE COST
OF THE GRADUATION
DINNER.
THIS WAS
HIS MILESTONE
AFTER
ALL THE
PRICE OF THE MEAL
CAME UP AGAIN
AND AGAIN IN
THE DAYS LEADING
UP TO IT TO
THE POINT THAT MY
PARTNER FELT
SO GUILTY HE
DELIBERATELY CHOSE
A CHEAP CASUAL
RESTAURANT
JUST TO AVOID
TENSION EVEN
THEN THE
NIGHT ENDED IN
EMBARRASSMENT HIS
FAMILY ASKED
TO SPLIT THE BILL
ANYWAY I
WAS STUNNED AT
MY OWN GRADUATION
MY
PARENTS COVERED
A LARGE EXPENSIVE
DINNER WITHOUT
HESITATION AND
NEVER WOULD HAVE EXPECTED
ANYONE ELSE
TO CHIP IN
YET
HERE MY
FAMILY WAS
ASKED TO PAY
THEIR SHARE FOR
MY PARTNER'S
CELEBRATION AND
THE AMOUNT SMALL
AS IT WAS
FELT
INSULTING
ON PRINCIPLE
IT
WASN'T ABOUT THE
MONEY IT
WAS ABOUT THE
MESSAGE IT
FELT RUDE DISMISSIVE
AND PAINFULLY
UNCOMFORTABLE FOR
EVERYONE INVOLVED
WHAT
MADE IT WORSE
WAS WHAT HAPPENED
SHORTLY AFTER
JUST
DAYS LATER HIS
RELATIVES WERE
HAPPILY UPGRADING
THEIR PHONES
CASUALLY
DROPPING HUNDREDS
OF DOLLARS AND
ADDING IT TO THEIR
GROWING DEBT WITHOUT
A SECOND THOUGHT
WATCHING
THEM SPEND FREELY
ON LUXURIES
RIGHT AFTER
ASKING MY
FAMILY TO
HELP PAY FOR
A GRADUATION DINNER
FELT LIKE A
SLAP SLAP IN THE FACE.
THAT WAS
THE MOMENT SOMETHING
IN ME SNAPPED.
I TOLD
MY PARTNER
THAT I WAS DONE
EXTENDING MYSELF
FOR PEOPLE
WHO CLEARLY DIDN'T
RESPECT US.
I DECIDED
I WOULDN'T BE
BUYING HIS FAMILY
CHRISTMAS GIFTS
THIS YEAR. BECAUSE
I COULDN'T BRING
MYSELF TO
REWARD BEHAVIOR
THAT FELT SO
INCONSIDERATE
AND HYPOCRITICAL.
NOW I'M
BEING MADE TO FEEL
COLD AND PETTY
FOR DRAWING THE
LINE.
BUT TO
ME IT FEELS
LIKE BASIC BOUNDARIES
AFTER ONE
TOO MANY DISAPPOINTMENTS.
SO WAS
I WRONG FOR
FINALLY SAYING
ENOUGH AND
LETTING CHRISTMAS
BE THE BREAKING
POINT?