I'M A WOMAN
IN MY LATE 20S,
AND I'M
PLANNING A GAME
NIGHT AT MY PLACE
THAT'S SUPPOSED TO
FEEL RELAXED,
FUN, AND
SOCIAL, THE
KIND WHERE PEOPLE
ACTUALLY GET
TO LAUGH, PLAY,
AND FINISH
A SENTENCE. I
DESPERATELY WANT
MY OLDER BROTHER
THERE.
HE'S SOMEONE
I LOVE AND
MISS.
EVEN THOUGH
WE LIVE IN THE SAME
CITY, THE
PROBLEM'S HIS
WIFE.
SHE ISN'T
OPENLY MEAN
OR CRUEL, BUT
ONCE SHE ENTERS
A ROOM, THE
AIR SHIFTS. SHIFTS.
SHE SPEAKS
LOUDLY, CONSTANTLY,
AND WITHOUT
PAUSE, AS
IF SILENCE ITSELF
IS SOMETHING SHE
HAS TO DEFEAT.
CONVERSATIONS DON'T
HAPPEN AROUND HER.
IT GETS
SWALLOWED.
IT DOESN'T
MATTER IF WE'RE
AT A FAMILY DINNER,
A HOLIDAY
GATHERING, OR
A CASUAL HANGOUT.
IF SOMEONE STARTS
TALKING, SHE
INTERRUPTS BEFORE
THEY FINISH THE
THOUGHT, REDIRECTS
IT TO HERSELF, AND
BARRELS FORWARD
WITH ANOTHER LONG
STORY THAT
SOMEHOW LOOPS
BACK TO HER LIFE.
HER FEELINGS,
HER OPINIONS,
ASKING QUESTIONS
ISN'T REALLY
HER THING, UNLESS
IT'S JUST A
SET UP TO TALK
MORE.
IF
I WANT TO HAVE
AN ACTUAL CONVERSATION
WITH MY BROTHER
I
HAVE TO PHYSICALLY
CORNER HIM
WHEN SHE'S DISTRACTED
BECAUSE
WHEN THEY'RE TOGETHER
SHE
SPEAKS FOR
BOTH OF THEM
AND HE FADES INTO
THE BACKGROUND THEY'VE
BEEN MARRIED A
LITTLE OVER A
YEAR BUT
THIS BEHAVIOR
HAS EXISTED
FAR LONGER
I'VE
TALKED TO MY BROTHER
ABOUT IT MORE
THAN ONCE HE
ADMITS IT'S
EXHAUSTING ADMITS
IT'S DISRUPTIVE
ADMITS
HE'S TRIED TO
ADDRESS IT WITH HER
NOTHING
CHANGES HE
SAYS SHE STRUGGLES
WITH ANXIETY AND
CLAIMS SHE'S BEEN
SEEING A THERAPIST
FOR YEARS
AND
I GENUINELY TRY
TO BE EMPATHETIC
BUT EMPATHY
DOESN'T MAKE
IT EASIER TO
SIT THROUGH HOURS
OF BEING TALKED
OVER.
THE LAST
TIME SHE CAME
TO A GAME NIGHT,
IT WAS A
DISASTER.
SHE TALKED
OVER THE RULES,
DELAYED PEOPLE'S
TURNS, AND
PRACTICALLY SHOUTED
UNRELATED STORIES
WHILE OTHERS
WERE TRYING TO PLAY.
PEOPLE STOPPED
ENGAGING, THE
ENERGY DIED,
WHAT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE FUN
TURNED INTO EVERYONE
POLITELY
ENDURING HER
UNTIL THE NIGHT
FINALLY ENDED.
SO THIS
TIME, I
MADE A CHOICE I'M
NOT PROUD OF
BUT FELT CORNERED
INTO.
I INVITED
COUSINS AND
CLOSE FRIENDS INSTEAD,
SOME OF
WHOM ARE TRAVELING
FROM ANOTHER CITY
TO BE THERE.
I DIDN'T
INVITE MY BROTHER
BECAUSE
REALISTICALLY
HE
WOULDN'T COME WITHOUT
HIS WIFE AND
I DON'T HAVE THE
EMOTIONAL BANDWIDTH
TO SACRIFICE
ANOTHER GATHERING
TO HER INABILITY
TO STOP
TALKING
I HAVEN'T
TOLD HIM YET
AND I'M
DREADING THE MOMENT
HE FINDS OUT
ESPECIALLY
SINCE HE
LIVES NEARBY AND
OTHERS ARE COMING
FROM MUCH FARTHER
AWAY I
FEEL LIKE I'M
CHOOSING BETWEEN
PROTECTING THE
JOY OF THE NIGHT
AND HURTING SOMEONE
I LOVE AND
I CAN'T TELL
IF I'M SETTING
A NECESSARY BOUNDARY
OR QUIETLY
BECOMING THE
VILLAIN IN MY OWN
FAMILY