AT 26,
I WAS STANDING
IN A CROWDED CHAPEL
DURING THE FUNERAL
OF MY AUNT,
WHO
HAD JUST LOST
HER SECOND, BRUTAL
FIGHT WITH A
LONG ILLNESS, WHEN
AN OLD ACQUAINTANCE
FROM WORK CAME
UP TO ME, OFFERED
BRIEF CONDOLENCES,
AND THEN PRESSED
FOR DETAILS ABOUT
HOW SHE DIED.
SO THROUGH
TEARS I
EXPLAINED THE COMPLICATIONS
AND HOW
HARD THE FINAL
MONTHS HAD BEEN.
ONLY FOR
HER TO SMILE SOFTLY
AND SAY HOW
GRATEFUL SHE
WAS THAT NOTHING
LIKE THAT HAD EVER
TOUCHED HER
FAMILY BECAUSE
THEY WERE, BLESSED,
PROTECTED, AND
CLEARLY FAVORED
BY HER GOD.
A COMMENT
THAT FELT LIKE
A KNIFE TWISTING
WHILE I WAS
ALREADY BARELY HOLDING
MYSELF TOGETHER
AND
I SNAPPED BACK
THAT IT MUST BE
COMFORTING TO
BELIEVE SOME FAMILIES
ARE CHOSEN FOR
MERCY WHILE OTHERS
ARE LEFT TO
BURY THEIR LOVED
ONES WHICH
CAUSED AN AUDIBLE
STIR AND
DREW UNCOMFORTABLE LOOKS
FROM EVERYONE NEARBY
HER
RELATIVES IMMEDIATELY
TURNED ON
ME ACCUSING
ME OF ATTACKING
SOMEONE WHO
WAS JUST BEING
KIND WITH
ONE OF THEM EVEN
IMPLYING THAT
MY REACTION
WAS THE VERY
REASON MY
FAMILY HADN'T
BEEN SPARED AND
OVERWHELMED BY
GRIEF AND FURY
I
TOLD THEM TO
LEAVE THE SERVICE
CUTTING
OFF CONTACT
WITH EVERYONE
WHO DEFENDED HER
AFTERWARD BUT
NOW I'M LEFT
QUESTIONING WHETHER
MY PAIN JUSTIFIED
MY OUTBURST
OR WHETHER I
CROSS IN UNFORGIVABLE
LINE IN
A MOMENT MEANT
FOR MOURNING