FOR MY
BIRTHDAY, I
PLANNED A FULL-DAY
TRIP FROM OUR
SMALL TOWN
TO A NEARBY
MAJOR CITY
WITH MY SISTER
AND A CLOSE FRIEND,
LAYING OUT
THE SCHEDULE CLEARLY
AHEAD OF TIME,
LEAVING MID-MORNING,
SEVERAL HOURS
AT A LARGE MUSEUM,
EXPLORING
THE CITY AFTERWARD,
AND RETURNING
THAT EVENING,
I INVITED
HER TO THE MUSEUM
FOR FREE
AND KNEW SHE HAD
DIABETES AND
AN OLD LEG INJURY.
SO BEFORE
WE EVEN LEFT
I TOLD HER I
BROUGHT EXTRA SNACKS,
BOTH
FAST-ACTING
AND LONGER-LASTING
CARBS, JUST
IN CASE
SHE NEEDED THEM
AND REMINDED
HER SHE COULD
SPEAK UP AT
ANY TIME WE
SPENT HOURS
WALKING THROUGH
EXHIBITS SKIP
ONE FLOOR
BECAUSE NEITHER
OF US WAS INTERESTED
AND
TOOK BREAKS WHERE
SHE SAT DOWN
WITHOUT COMPLAINT
WHEN
WE FINISHED EARLY
MY
SISTER AND
I OPENLY SUGGESTED
WALKING AROUND
NEARBY STREETS
AND USING THE
SUBWAY TO EXPLORE
AND
SHE DIDN'T OBJECT
OR SAY SHE
NEEDED FOOD
OR REST EVEN
WHEN WE REPEATEDLY
CHECKED IN
AND STOPPED FOR
A SMOOTHIE AND
A BAGEL ALONG
THE WAY SHE
KEPT ONE HEADPHONE
IN MOST OF
THE DAY AND NEVER
TOLD US SHE
WAS STRUGGLING DAYS
LATER SHE
SHE BLEW UP AT ME,
SAYING I
DIDN'T WARN HER
ABOUT HOW MUCH
WALKING THERE WOULD
BE.
THAT SHE
COULDN'T PREPARE PROPERLY.
AND THAT I
LEFT HER VULNERABLE.
DESPITE THE
ORIGINAL PLAN
INVOLVING HOURS
ON OUR FEET.
DESPITE US
CHECKING IN CONSTANTLY.
AND DESPITE
THE FACT WE
WERE SURROUNDED BY
FOOD OPTIONS
THE ENTIRE TIME.
NOW SHE'S
FRAMING IT AS
IF I WAS CARELESS
WITH HER HEALTH.
AND I'M
STUCK WONDERING
IF I GENUINELY
FAILED HER.
OR IF SHE'S
ANGRY BECAUSE
SHE DIDN'T SPEAK
UP AND WANT
SOMEONE ELSE TO
BLAME.