I'M A
WOMAN IN MY LATE
TWENTIES LIVING
BY CHOICE WITH
MY GRANDFATHER. NOT
BECAUSE EITHER
OF US NEEDS HELP
BUT BECAUSE WE
GENUINELY ENJOY
SHARING A HOME.
AND UNTIL
RECENTLY OUR
LIFE TOGETHER FELT
WARM, PEACEFUL,
AND DEEPLY
FAMILIAR, FULL
OF SMALL ROUTINES
LIKE HIM MAKING
TEA WHILE I
VENT ABOUT WORK
OR QUIETLY BRAIDING
MY HAIR. WHILE
I RAMBLE ABOUT
MY LOVE LIFE,
THAT SENSE
OF SAFETY
CRACKED AT
A RELATIVE'S
VERY TRADITIONAL WEDDING,
WHERE I
WAS ALREADY DRAINED
AND OVERSTIMULATED
WHEN I WAS
PUSHED INTO TO
PARTICIPATING IN
A LOUD PUBLIC
FAMILY DANCE
I DIDN'T WANT
TO DO, ONLY
TO SIT DOWN
AFTERWARD AND
HAVE AN OLDER WOMAN
I HAD NEVER
MET SLOWLY LOOK
ME UP AND DOWN,
BEFORE
MAKING A
SHARP, HUMILIATING
COMMENT ABOUT
MY BODY
AND HOW RARELY
I MUST DANCE,
I SWALLOWED
MY EMBARRASSMENT
TO AVOID CAUSING
A SCENE AND
ASSUMED I'D NEVER
SEE HER AGAIN,
BUT
TO MY SHOCK MY
GRANDFATHER INVITED
THE SAME WOMAN,
AN ACQUAINTANCE
FROM THE WEDDING,
NOT EVEN
A CLOSE FRIEND,
BACK TO
OUR HOUSE WITHOUT
ASKING OR
TELLING ME, TURNING
WHAT I ASSUMED
WAS A BRIEF STOP
INTO A STAY
THAT STRETCHED FROM
ONE NIGHT INTO
MORE THAN A WEEK
SINCE
THEN SHE'S
LINGERED ENDLESSLY
IN OUR SHARED
SPACE INSERTING
HERSELF INTO
INTIMATE CONVERSATIONS
THAT AREN'T
DIRECTED AT HER
CRITICIZING
MY BODY
WHEN I MENTION
CRAMPS SCOLDING
ME FOR CRYING
OVER WORK
STRESS AND
SPEAKING TO
ME LIKE A MISBEHAVING
CHILD RATHER
THAN AN ADULT
IN HER OWN HOME
I
HAVEN'T RAISED MY
VOICE INSULTED
HER OR
CONFRONTED HER
DIRECTLY I'VE
ONLY EXPRESSED PRIVATELY
TO MY GRANDFATHER
AND
MY SIBLINGS
THAT I FEEL UNCOMFORTABLE
UNCOMFORTABLE, DISRESPECTED,
AND BLINDSIDED
BY HAVING
A JUDGMENTAL
STRANGER LIVING
IN MY SPACE.
YET SOMEHOW
THAT HAS BEEN
TWISTED INTO
ME BEING LABELED
RUDE AND
UNGRATEFUL.
LEAVING ME
WONDERING WHETHER
I'M ACTUALLY WRONG
FOR WANTING BASIC
CONTROL OVER
MY OWN HOME
AND FEELING
HURT THAT MY
COMFORT SEEMS
TO MATTER LESS
THAN THE FEELINGS
OF SOMEONE I
NEVER INVITED.