A FEW
WEEKS BEFORE THE
HOLIDAYS, MY
PARTNER AND
I DECIDED TO
SURPRISE OUR
ONLY CHILD WITH
SOMETHING BIG.
A TICKET
TO A LIVE SHOW
JUST BEFORE
THE NEW YEAR.
IT WASN'T
A CASUAL GIFT.
THE VENUE
IS SEVERAL HOURS
AWAY, REQUIRED
AN OVERNIGHT
STAY, TIME
OFF WORK, AND
CAREFUL PLANNING.
I WAS GOING
TOO, PARTLY
BECAUSE SHE'S
STILL YOUNG,
PARTLY BECAUSE
I GENUINELY
LOVE THE
ARTIST, AND
PARTLY BECAUSE
IT FELT LIKE
ONE OF THOSE RARE,
MEMORY-MAKING
MOMENTS PARENTS
HOPE FOR.
WE WRAPPED
THE CONFIRMATION NICELY
AND GAVE
IT TO HER EARLY
AND HER
REACTION WAS
PURE JOY NOT
LONG AFTER
MY PARTNER'S
SISTER CALLED
TO CHAT ABOUT
HOLIDAY PLANS
DURING
THE CONVERSATION
I
MENTIONED THE
CONCERT NOT
THINKING MUCH
OF IT THERE
WAS A LONG PAUSE
THEN
A QUIET COMMENT
ABOUT HOW HER
CHILD WOULD HAVE
LOVED SOMETHING LIKE
THAT SHE
ASKED QUESTIONS
WHERE
IT WAS WHEN
IT WAS HOW
EXCITING IT
SOUNDED AND
EVENTUALLY SAID
OUTRIGHT THAT
HER KID WOULD HAVE
BEEN OVER THE MOON
TO GO BY
THEN THE
TICKET WAS ALREADY
GIVEN THE
PLANS ALREADY
SET AND
MY HEART ALREADY
SINKING AFTER
WE HUNG
UP, THE
GUILT HIT HARD.
I CHECKED THE
WEBSITE AND
SAW THERE WERE STILL
TICKETS AVAILABLE,
BUT BUYING
ANOTHER ONE
WOULDN'T HAVE BEEN SIMPLE.
THAT WOULD MEAN
EXPLAINING WHY
ONLY ONE OF
THE OTHER CHILDREN
WAS INCLUDED. ARRANGING
EXTRA TRAVEL,
SUPERVISION,
AND EXPENSES
WE HADN'T
BUDGETED FOR,
AND QUIETLY
TURNING A
CAREFULLY PLANNED
PARENT-CHILD
EXPERIENCE INTO
SOMETHING COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT.
OUR
FAMILY CIRCUMSTANCES
AREN'T
THE SAME, FINANCIALLY
OR LOGISTICALLY,
AND THIS GIFT
WAS SOMETHING WE
CHOSE INTENTIONALLY
FOR OUR OWN
CHILD.
CHILD NOW
CHRISTMAS DINNER
IS APPROACHING AND
THE EXCITEMENT IN
MY HOUSE FEELS
TANGLED WITH
DREAD I
CAN ALREADY PICTURE
THE MOMENT WHEN
THE STORY COMES UP
THE COMPARISON
THE
DISAPPOINTMENT I
DIDN'T MEAN TO
EXCLUDE ANYONE
BUT
I CAN'T UNDO
WHAT'S ALREADY BEEN
GIVEN WHAT
WAS SUPPOSED TO
BE A JOYFUL SURPRISE
NOW FEELS
LIKE A SILENT
HOLIDAY LANDMINE
WAITING TO GO
OFF