FOR MOST
OF MY LIFE,
MY FATHER,
NOW IN
HIS EARLY 60S,
WAS MARRIED
TO MY MOTHER,
WHOM HE
TREATED LIKE AN
AFTERTHOUGHT FOR
NEARLY THREE DECADES.
THEIR MARRIAGE
UNRAVELED
SLOWLY AND PAINFULLY,
MARKED BY
REPEATED AFFAIRS,
QUIET HUMILIATIONS,
AND A KIND
OF DISRESPECT THAT
BECAME NORMAL
BEHIND CLOSED
DOORS.
WHEN THEY
FINALLY DIVORCED,
IT FELT LESS
LIKE A TRAGEDY
AND MORE LIKE
AN OVERDUE
ENDING TO SOMETHING
THAT HAD BEEN
BROKEN FOR
YEARS.
I MADE
MY PEACE WITH
THAT AND EVEN
ACCEPTED THE
IDEA THAT ONE
DAY HE MIGHT
REMARRY.
WHAT I
CAN'T ACCEPT
IS WHO HE'S MARRYING.
THE WOMAN
HE'S ENGAGED
TO IS THE LAST
PERSON HE CHEATED
ON MY MOTHER WITH.
THE FINAL
BETRAYAL BEFORE
EVERYTHING COLLAPSED.
AS IF
THAT WEREN'T SURREAL
ENOUGH.
SHE ALSO
HAPPENS TO
SHARE MY MOTHER'S
FIRST NAME.
WHICH MAKES
THE WHOLE SITUATION
FEEL LIKE
SOME CRUEL JOKE
I DON'T UNDERSTAND.
I'VE NEVER
MET HER, I'VE
NEVER WANTED TO,
AND I GENUINELY
DON'T KNOW
HOW I'D EVEN REFER
TO HER WITHOUT
FEELING SICK
TO MY STOMACH.
MY
SIBLINGS, AFTER
THEIR OWN TENSE
CONVERSATIONS WITH
HIM, HAVE
ALREADY MADE IT
CLEAR THEY WON'T
BE ATTENDING THE
CEREMONY.
I TRIED
TO STAY QUIET
AND AVOID THE
CONFRONTATION, HOPING
DISTANCE WOULD
SPEAK FOR ME.
BUT RECENTLY
MY FATHER
CORNERED ME
AND ASKED IF
I'D NOT ONLY ATTEND
THE WEDDING, BUT
TAKE PART IN
IT.
THE REQUEST
FELT UNREAL,
LIKE HE EXPECTED
ME TO CELEBRATE
A RELATIONSHIP
THAT EXISTS
BECAUSE MY
FAMILY WAS TORN
APART.
THE IDEA
OF STANDING THERE,
SMILING
FOR PHOTOS,
AND PRETENDING
THIS UNION
ISN'T BUILT
ON YEARS OF DAMAGE
FEELS WRONG
ON A LEVEL ONE
CAN'T EXPLAIN.
LANE.
NOW I'M
STUCK WONDERING
WHETHER REFUSING
MAKES ME
DISLOYAL, OR
IF GOING WOULD
MEAN BETRAYING
MYSELF.