I'M IN
MY EARLY 30S
AND WORK AT A MODEST-SIZED
FIRM WITH
A FEW DOZEN EMPLOYEES.
THE KIND
OF PLACE WHERE
EVERYONE PRETENDS
TO KNOW EVERYONE ELSE
BUT MOST INTERACTIONS
ARE SHALLOW.
AND TRANSACTIONAL.
LAST WEEK,
A SENIOR
ADMINISTRATOR NAMED
MARLENE TOOK
IT UPON HERSELF
TO SWEEP THROUGH
THE OFFICE ANNOUNCING
THAT
WE WERE ALL
PITCHING IN
FOR A BIRTHDAY
SURPRISE FOR
A WOMAN NAMED TALIA.
SOMEONE FROM
A COMPLETELY DIFFERENT
DIVISION WHOSE
FACE I RECOGNIZE
ONLY BECAUSE
WE'VE PASSED EACH
OTHER
NEAR THE COFFEE
MACHINE A HANDFUL
OF TIMES. WE'VE
NEVER COLLABORATED
NEVER
SPOKEN BEYOND
POLITE NODS
AND CERTAINLY
NEVER SHARED
ANYTHING RESEMBLING
A RELATIONSHIP MARLENE
DECLARED THE
CONTRIBUTION WOULD
BE 35 PER
PERSON FOR
A GIFT CARD AND
AN ELABORATE
DESSERT AS
IF THIS WERE A
FOREGONE CONCLUSION
RATHER THAN
A REQUEST AND
WHEN I DIDN'T
IMMEDIATELY RESPOND
SHE
APPEARED AT MY
DESK LATER
THAT AFTERNOON
WITH A TIGHT
SMILE AND
ASKED IF I WAS
PARTICIPATING I
CALMLY TOLD
HER I WAS OPTING
OUT EXPLAINING
THAT I DON'T
USUALLY CONTRIBUTE TO
GROUP GIFTS FOR
PEOPLE I DON'T
ACTUALLY WORK WITH
OR KNOW,
WHICH SEEMED
REASONABLE TO
ME.
HER EXPRESSION
SHIFTED INSTANTLY,
SURPRISE CURDLING
INTO MILD
DISAPPROVAL,
AND SHE
BRUSHED IT OFF
WITH A POINTED,
IT'S NOT
A LOT OF MONEY,
BEFORE WALKING
AWAY.
SINCE THEN,
THE AIR AROUND
ME HAS CHANGED.
CONVERSATIONS GO
QUIET WHEN
I APPROACH. SMILES
FEEL FORCED,
AND ONE COLLEAGUE
EVEN JOKED
LOUDLY THAT
I WAS THE HOLDOUT
AS IF I'D COMMITTED
SOME KIND OF
SOCIAL
BETRAYAL.
NOW I'M
LEFT WONDERING WHETHER
I UNKNOWINGLY
VIOLATED SOME
SACRED WORKPLACE
RITUAL OR
IF REFUSING. GOODBYE
AFFECTION FOR
A NEAR STRANGER
HAS SOMEHOW
BRANDED ME
AS DIFFICULT OR
STINGY.
EVEN
THOUGH I GENUINELY
BELIEVE GENEROSITY
SHOULD BE VOLUNTARY
AND PERSONAL,
NOT ENFORCED
THROUGH SIDE
EYES AND WHISPER
JUDGMENTS.