I'M
A WOMAN IN
MY LATE 30S,
AND
I BECAME
A PARENT
VERY YOUNG,
WHICH
MEANT MY OLDEST
CHILD
THAT I GREW UP
ALMOST SIDE
BY SIDE
RATHER THAN
IN CLEARLY DEFINED
ROLES.
BECAUSE
OF THAT, OUR
RELATIONSHIP
HAS ALWAYS
BEEN INTENSE,
CLOSE,
AND EMOTIONALLY
CHARGED.
WE LIVE
IN A SMALL
CITY OUTSIDE
THE CAPITAL,
AND I'M
RAISING SEVERAL
KIDS WHILE
WORKING FULL
TIME, SO
MY ENTIRE
LIFE REVOLVES
AROUND SCHEDULES,
RESPONSIBILITIES,
AND EVERYONE
ELSE'S
NEEDS.
ANYTIME I
DO SOMETHING JUST
FOR MYSELF,
EVEN
SOMETHING SMALL
AND HARMLESS,
IT
TENDS TO CREATE
TENSION.
ESPECIALLY
WITH MY
OLDEST, WHO
TAKES IT PERSONALLY
WHEN I'M
NOT HOME OR
NOT
AVAILABLE.
LAST
NIGHT I ATTENDED
A COMPANY HOLIDAY
DINNER THAT
HAD BEEN PLANNED
FOR
WEEKS.
EARLIER
THAT DAY,
MY OLDEST
HELPED ME PICK
OUT AN OUTFIT,
JOKE WITH
ME ABOUT HOW
FANCY I
LOOKED, AND
ACTED GENUINELY
SUPPORTIVE,
WHICH MADE
ME FEEL LIKE
WE WERE IN A
GOOD
PLACE.
MY YOUNGER
KIDS WERE
STAYING WITH RELATIVES
OVERNIGHT, SO
THERE WAS NO
CHILDCARE ISSUE
AT
ALL.
BEFORE I
LEFT I
WAS ASKED
WHEN I'D BE HOME
AND
I SAID I
WASN'T SURE
WHETHER I'D
LEAVE EARLY
BUT THAT THE EVENT
OFFICIALLY WRAPPED
UP AROUND
10.
I
CHECKED MY
PHONE THROUGHOUT
THE EVENING
MADE
SURE THERE
WERE NO URGENT
MESSAGES
AND
ENJOYED MYSELF
FOR
ONCE.
WHEN THE
DINNER ENDED
A FEW MINUTES
AFTER THE
SCHEDULED TIME
I
LOOKED AT MY
PHONE AND
SAW MULTIPLE
MISSED CALLS
WITHIN THE
SPAN OF TWO
MINUTES FOLLOWED
IMMEDIATELY
BY
ANOTHER INCOMING
CALL.
AS
SOON AS I
ANSWERED I
WAS MET WITH
ANGER AND
ACCUSATIONS.
I
WAS TOLD I
HAD LIED ABOUT
COMING HOME
EARLY THAT
I SHOULD HAVE
BEEN ON MY WAY
ALREADY AND
THAT I WAS FAILING
IN MY ROLE
BECAUSE SOMETHING
TERRIBLE
COULD HAVE HAPPENED
WHILE I WAS
GONE.
NO
EXPLANATION
SEEMED
TO MATTER, NOT
THE FACT THAT
THE EVENT HAD
JUST ENDED
OR THAT I NEVER
PROMISED
AN EARLY
RETURN.
SINCE
THEN, I'VE
BEEN GIVEN THE
COLD SHOULDER,
AND EVERY
ATTEMPT TO
SMOOTH THINGS
OVER HAS
ONLY MADE
THINGS
WORSE.
NOW
I'M LEFT WONDERING
IF I'M EXPECTED
TO NEVER GO
OUT, NEVER
RELAX,
AND NEVER
EXIST OUTSIDE
OF BEING A
PARENT, AND
WHETHER TAKING
A FEW EXTRA
MINUTES FOR
MYSELF SOMEHOW
CROSSED AN
UNFORGIVABLE
LINE.