I HAD TO
RETURN TO THE TOWN
WHERE I GREW UP
ON SHORT NOTICE
AFTER A RELATIVE
PASSED
AWAY.
EVERYTHING HAPPENED
QUICKLY, AND
I HAD TO DROP
MY PLANS
AND HEAD
OUT.
I LET A
LONGTIME FRIEND,
LET'S CALL HER
MIA, KNOW
WHAT WAS GOING ON,
AND SHE
IMMEDIATELY OFFERED
TO LET ME STAY
AT HER PLACE FOR
A FEW
DAYS.
I TOLD
HER I'D BE BRINGING
MY TWO LARGE
DOGS WITH
ME AND COMPLETELY
UNDERSTOOD IF
THAT WOULDN'T
WORK FOR
HER.
SHE INSISTED
IT WASN'T
A PROBLEM AND
SAID SHE WAS HAPPY
TO
HELP.
FOR CONTEXT,
MY DOGS
ARE WELL -TRAINED
BUT
BIG.
ONE'S
A GOLDEN MIX
AND THE OTHER IS
A SHEPHERD
MIX.
SO THEY
CAN FEEL OVERWHELMING
IN SMALL
SPACES.
ESPECIALLY FOR
PEOPLE WHO AREN'T
USED TO BIG
DOGS.
I'M VERY
AWARE OF THIS
AND USUALLY AVOID
BRINGING THEM
TO OTHER PEOPLE'S
HOMES UNLESS ABSOLUTELY
NECESSARY.
THE DRIVE
WAS AROUND 4
HOURS.
AND WHEN I
ARRIVED, MIA
CAME OUT TO
GREET
ME.
AS I UNLOADED
THE CAR, I
LET THE DOGS OUT
TO STRETCH AND
RELIEVE
THEMSELVES.
MY GOLDEN
MIX WENT STRAIGHT
TO SOME
BUSHES.
BUT MY SHEPHERD
DECIDED TO
PEE RIGHT ON
THE PAVED FRONT
STEP.
SHE HAS
A WEIRD PREFERENCE
FOR SOLID
SURFACES.
MIA IMMEDIATELY
PANICKED.
I APOLOGIZED,
OF COURSE,
BUT SINCE
IT WAS OUTSIDE,
I DIDN'T
UNDERSTAND WHY
IT UPSET HER
SO
MUCH.
DURING THE
STAY, THE
DOGS WERE PERFECTLY
BEHAVED.
NO ACCIDENTS
INDOORS, NO
DAMAGE, NOTHING,
THEY LET ME
KNOW WHENEVER THEY
NEEDED TO GO
OUT, AND
I PICKED UP AFTER
THEM RIGHT
AWAY.
I KEPT
A CLOSE EYE ON
THEM THE ENTIRE
TIME.
AFTER I
GOT HOME, MIA
TEXTED ME
SAYING HER PLACE
WAS MESSY
FROM THE DOGS
AND THAT SHE
PLANNED TO HIRE
A
CLEANER.
SHE ASKED
IF I WOULD COVER
THE COST I
WAS
CONFUSED.
SO I ASKED
WHAT NEEDED
CLEANING.
SHE SAID
THERE WAS DOG HAIR
EVERYWHERE.
YES.
MY DOG'S
SHED.
I KNOW
THAT.
IF SHE HAD
ASKED ME TO VACUUM
BEFORE I
LEFT.
I ABSOLUTELY
WOULD
HAVE.
BUT SHE NEVER
MENTIONED
IT.
I ALSO
DON'T THINK A
PROFESSIONAL DEEP
CLEAN IS
NECESSARY.
JUST A
QUICK VACUUM
OF THE
RUGS.
SOFA.
AND BEDDING
WOULD HAVE HANDLED
IT.
SHE OFFERED
TO HOST
ME.
SHE KNEW
ABOUT THE
DOGS.
THEY
DIDN'T DAMAGE
ANYTHING OR
CAUSE INDOOR
MESSES.
NOW I
FEEL STUCK BECAUSE
I DON'T WANT
CONFLICT.
BUT I ALSO
DON'T FEEL RESPONSIBLE
FOR A FULL
CLEANING SERVICE
WHEN THE SITUATION
WAS EXACTLY
WHAT I TOLD
HER TO
EXPECT.