I
WENT TO THANKSGIVING
WITH MY
WIFE AND
OUR 14
-YEAR -OLD
DAUGHTER TO
A RELATIVE'S
HOUSE.
ALSO
THERE WERE MY
NEPHEW, HIS
BOYFRIEND, AND
MY COUSIN
BY MARRIAGE,
WHO HAS
A HABIT
OF SAYING OFFENSIVE
THINGS
AND CALLING IT
JUST BEING
HONEST.
WHILE
I WAS IN THE
KITCHEN, MY
DAUGHTER PULLED
ME ASIDE
AND TOLD
ME MY COUSIN
WAS BEING REALLY
WEIRD AND
MAKING THE
SITUATION
UNCOMFORTABLE.
I
WENT TO CHECK
AND FOUND HIM
LOUDLY MAKING
HOMOPHOBIC
COMMENTS TOWARD
MY NEPHEW AND
HIS BOYFRIEND
NOTHING
PHYSICAL
BUT
IT WAS CLEARLY
ESCALATING
AND
TEMPERS
WERE FLARING
I TOOK
MY COUSIN
OUTSIDE AND
TOLD HIM HE
NEEDED TO LEAVE
HE
ARGUED THAT
IT WAS IN MY
HOUSE AND
I HAD NO AUTHORITY
BUT
I STOOD MY
GROUND AND
DIDN'T LET HIM
BACK IN LATER
THE
HOST DEMANDED
TO KNOW
WHERE HE WAS
WHEN
I EXPLAINED
SHE
EXPLODED
SAYING
I RUINED
THANKSGIVING
AND THAT WHAT
HE SAID WASN'T
THAT BAD SHE
TOLD ME
MY WIFE
MY DAUGHTER
AND
THE THE COUPLE TO
LEAVE AND SAID
WE MIGHT BE
INVITED BACK
NEXT YEAR,
ONCE WE LEARN
TO
BEHAVE.
WE
LEFT AND HAD
A SURPRISINGLY
NICE DINNER
ELSEWHERE.
BUT SINCE
THEN I'VE BEEN
GETTING MESSAGES
FROM FAMILY
SAYING I
OVERSTEPPED
AND HAD NO RIGHT
TO KICK ANYONE
OUT.
NOW I'M
STUCK WONDERING
WHETHER I
PROTECTED PEOPLE
FROM A SITUATION
GETTING
WORSE.
OR
IF I CROSSED
A LINE BY
ACTING WHEN
IT WASN'T TECHNICALLY
MY
PLACE.