I DO
ALMOST ALL
THE COOKING IN
OUR HOME. EVERY
MEAL, EVERY
DAY.
TWO YEARS AGO,
MY WIFE
GIFTED ME A
$130
TAKUMI-EDGE
CHEF'S KNIFE
FOR CHRISTMAS.
IT
WAS THE FIRST
HIGH-END KNIFE
I'VE EVER OWNED,
AND I TREAT
IT LIKE A FRAGILE
TREASURE.
HAND WASH
ONLY, DRY
IMMEDIATELY, NEVER
THE DISHWASHER.
MY WIFE,
HOWEVER, TREATS
IT LIKE A $5
MEGAMAR UTILITY
KNIFE.
SHE LEAVES
IT ON THE COUNTER,
CUTS LEMONS
AND TOMATOES
ON IT, AND
WORST OF ALL,
SLICES
THROUGH THICK PLASTIC
PACKAGING
THAT RUINS THE
BLADE.
I'VE ASKED
REPEATEDLY FOR
HER TO STOP. BUT
NOTHING CHANGES.
THIS MORNING,
SHE GRABBED
IT TO OPEN A
SAUSAGE PACK.
I TOLD HER
TO USE SCISSORS
OR ONE OF THE
CHEAP KNIVES IN
THE DRAWER. SHE
IGNORED ME
AND USED THE EXPENSIVE
KNIFE ANYWAY.
I FINALLY
SNAPPED.
USING THIS
KNIFE LIKE THAT
IS LIKE TAKING ONE
OF YOUR DESIGNER
DRESSES AND
SCRUBBING THE FLOOR.
WITH IT,
SHE SHRUGGED.
AND OUR ADULT
DAUGHTER SAID,
YOU GAVE
IT TO HER. SHE
CAN DO WHAT SHE
WANTS.
NOW, I'M
HIDING THE KNIFE
AFTER EVERY USE.
I
COOK FOR MY FAMILY
EVERY DAY AND
IT FEELS LIKE
SOMETHING I LOVE
IS BEING SLOWLY
DESTROYED IN
FRONT OF ME SHOULD
I KEEP LETTING
HER USE IT THIS
WAY?