AFTER A
TERRIFYING BIRTH
THAT NEARLY KILLED
BOTH ME AND
MY NEWBORN DAUGHTER.
MY LIFE
WAS SPLIT INTO
A CLEAR BEFORE
AND AFTER.
I'M A 27-YEAR-OLD
WOMAN, MARRIED
TO MY 29-YEAR-OLD
HUSBAND, AND
WE WELCOMED OUR
FIRST CHILD
AFTER A LABOR
SO TRAUMATIC
THAT DOCTORS
LATER TOLD
US HOW CLOSE
IT CAME
TO TRAGEDY.
SHE WAS
BORN SILENT
AND MOTIONLESS,
AND FOR
SEVERAL AGONIZING
MOMENTS, NO
ONE KNEW IF
SHE WOULD SURVIVE.
THAT EXPERIENCE
CHANGED EVERYTHING
ABOUT HOW I
SEE FAMILY, SAFETY,
AND SUPPORT.
COURT.
MY HUSBAND
AND I GREW UP
IN COMPLETELY DIFFERENT
REGIONS OF
THE COUNTRY. AFTER
UNIVERSITY, HE
RELOCATED
ACROSS THE MAP
TO LIVE NEAR MY
RELATIVES.
WE CURRENTLY
RENT A SMALL
PLACE ABOUT
20 MINUTES
FROM MY SIDE
OF THE FAMILY.
BUT DESPITE
THE DISTANCE,
THEY'VE BEEN LARGELY
ABSENT.
MY MOTHER,
WHO LIVES
NEARBY, HAS
STOPPED BY ONLY
A HANDFUL OF
TIMES SINCE
THE BIRTH. EACH
VISIT IS
BRIEF, JUST
LONG ENOUGH TO
SNAP PHOTOS
FOR SOCIAL MEDIA
BEFORE
SHE DISAPPEARS
AGAIN.
MY FATHER,
ON THE OTHER
HAND, IS
VERY PRESENT,
BUT OUR HISTORY
IS COMPLICATED.
GROWING GROWING UP,
HE WAS CONTROLLING,
EMOTIONALLY HARSH,
AND MANIPULATIVE,
AND WHILE HE
DOTES ON MY DAUGHTER
NOW, THOSE
OLD WOUNDS
NEVER FULLY
HEAL.
BY CONTRAST,
MY HUSBAND'S
RELATIVES LIVE
ROUGHLY 12
HOURS AWAY
AND SOMEHOW
MANAGE TO
SHOW UP MORE FOR
US THAN
ANYONE CLOSE
BY.
WHEN WE VISIT
THEM, THE
DIFFERENCE IS
OVERWHELMING.
MEALS APPEAR
WITHOUT BEING ASKED
FOR.
LAUNDRY IS
QUIETLY DONE.
WE'RE ENCOURAGED
TO SLEEP, SHOWER,
STEP OUTSIDE,
AND BREATHE.
BABYSITTERS ARE
OFFERED SO WE
CAN FEEL LIKE
A COUPLE AGAIN
INSTEAD OF
TWO EXHAUSTED PEOPLE
BARELY HOLDING
IT TOGETHER. WHEN
WE SPEND TIME
WITH MY FAMILY,
THE EXPERIENCE
IS THE OPPOSITE.
HANDS IMMEDIATELY
GRABBED FOR
THE BABY. NO
ONE ASKS HOW
WE'RE DOING. AND
HELP IS NON-EXISTENT.
FINANCIALLY, WHERE
WE LIVE NOW
FEELS LIKE A
DEAD END. THE
COST OF LIVING
IS CRUSHING. AND
HOMEOWNERSHIP
FEELS LIKE A
FANTASY RATHER
THAN A GOAL.
THE AREA
NEAR MY HUSBAND'S
FAMILY IS MORE
AFFORDABLE, HAS
BETTER SCHOOLS,
AND OFFERS
THE KIND OF
LONG-TERM STABILITY
WE DESPERATELY
WANT FOR
OUR DAUGHTER. SO
WE QUIETLY STARTED
APPLYING FOR
JOBS THERE.
HOPING FOR
A FRESH START
SURROUNDED BY
PEOPLE WHO ACTUALLY
SHOW UP FOR
US.
THAT'S
WHEN EVERYTHING EXPLODED
SOMEHOW
MY FATHER
FOUND OUT ABOUT
OUR PLANS
AND ACCUSED US
OF STEALING HIS
GRANDDAUGHTER HE
SAID IF WE MOVED
HE WOULD
STEP BACK FROM
OUR LIVES ENTIRELY
WHAT
HURT THE MOST
WASN'T JUST THE
THREAT IT
WAS THE REALIZATION
THAT HE
SEEMED MORE DEVASTATED
ABOUT LOSING
ACCESS TO
MY CHILD THAN
ABOUT LOSING
HIS OWN DAUGHTER
MY MOTHER
ECHOED SIMILAR
GUILT-LADEN
COMMENTS QUESTIONING
WHY WE EVEN
CONSIDER LEAVING
WHEN THEY'RE RIGHT
HERE DESPITE
RARELY MAKING
THE EFFORT
TO BE INVOLVED
I
DON'T WANT TO HURT
ANYONE OR
CUT TIES OUT
OF SPITE I
KNOW MY FATHER
GENUINELY LOVES
HIS GRANDDAUGHTER
AND
PART OF ME
FEELS GUILTY
FOR EVEN CONSIDERING
A MOVE BUT
I ALSO KNOW
WHAT IT'S LIKE TO
NEARLY DIE TO
WATCH MY CHILD
ALMOST SLIP
AWAY AND
TO REALIZE HOW
FRAGILE EVERYTHING
IS I
WANT A LIFE
WHERE MY FAMILY
IS SUPPORTED STABLE
AND SURROUNDED
BY PEOPLE
WHO DON'T JUST
WANT PHOTOS
BUT
ACTUALLY WANT
TO HELP US SURVIVE
SO
AM I REALLY WRONG
FOR WANTING TO
RELOCATE TO
A PLACE WHERE
WE CAN FINALLY
FEEL SAFE
SUPPORTED
AND HOPEFUL
ABOUT THE FUTURE