I LIVE
WITH MY PARTNER
AND OUR TWO KIDS,
AN ELEMENTARY-AGED
CHILD AND
A TODDLER, AND
LATELY EVERY
EVENING FEELS
LIKE AN ENDURANCE
TEST I'M
FAILING IN SLOW
MOTION.
I WORK
FULL-TIME WITH
BRUTALLY EARLY
MORNINGS, WHILE
MY PARTNER
IS ENROLLED IN
AN INTENSE ACADEMIC
PROGRAM
THAT CONSUMES
MOST OF
HER TIME AND ENERGY.
THE MOMENT
MY WORKDAY
ENDS, I
BECOME THE DEFAULT
PARENT ON
DUTY, RUSHING
TO PICK UP
THE KIDS, JUGGLING
DINNER, HOMEWORK,
HOMEWORK TANTRUMS
BATHS
PAJAMAS AND
BEDTIME ALL
WHILE SHE RETREATS
UPSTAIRS TO
STUDY BEHIND
A CLOSED DOOR
ON
PAPER IT SOUNDS
MANAGEABLE BUT
THE REALITY IS
PURE CHAOS
BECAUSE OF
OUR YOUNGEST THE
SECOND OUR TODDLER
REALIZES
HER OTHER PARENT
IS HOME BUT
INACCESSIBLE
SHE
COMPLETELY UNRAVELS
SHE SCREAMS
FOR HER CRIES
UNTIL SHE'S
HOARSE INVENTS
EXCUSES LIKE
SUDDENLY NEEDING
THE BATHROOM UPSTAIRS
OR A TOY
THAT ONLY EXISTS
IN THE BEDROOM
AND
ONCE SHE GETS
NEAR THAT DOOR
SHE
POUNCE ON
IT LIKE THE WORLD
IS ENDING. I'M
CONSTANTLY DRAGGING
HER AWAY, TRYING
TO SOOTHE HER,
TRYING TO
STAY CALM,
AND FAILING
MORE OFTEN
THAN I WANT TO
ADMIT.
WHAT BREAKS
ME IS THAT WHEN
MY PARTNER ISN'T
HOME AT ALL,
THE
TODDLER ACCEPTS
IT, SHE
STILL MISSES
HER, BUT
SHE COPES.
THE SCREAMING
STOPS.
THE EVENINGS
ARE HARD BUT
SURVIVABLE.
WHEN MY
PARTNER IS
PHYSICALLY PRESENT
YET EMOTIONALLY
UNAVAILABLE,
EVERYTHING EXPLODES.
THE STRESS
BUILDS UNTIL I
FEEL LIKE I'M
VIBRATING WITH
IT.
WHAT MAKES
THIS FEEL EVEN
MORE UNFAIR
IS THAT MY PARTNER
HAS OPTIONS. SHE
COULD STUDY
NEARBY WITH
FAMILY OR
STAY ON CAMPUS
OR ANYWHERE
ELSE WHERE
THE KIDS WOULDN'T
BE TORTURED BY
THE KNOWLEDGE THAT
SHE'S JUST UPSTAIRS
REFUSING
TO OPEN
THE DOOR BUT
SHE INSISTS ON
STUDYING AT
HOME EVERY NIGHT
LEAVING
ME TO MANAGE
THE EMOTIONAL FALLOUT
ALONE EVENTUALLY
EXHAUSTED
AND FRAYING
I TOLD
HER THAT IF SHE
PLANS TO SHUT
HERSELF AWAY
FOR HOURS
IT
WOULD HONESTLY BE
BETTER FOR EVERYONE
IF SHE STUDIED
SOMEWHERE ELSE
BECAUSE
I CANNOT PHYSICALLY
OR PSYCHOLOGICALLY
KEEP A
TODDLER FROM
WANTING HER PARENT
SHE
WAS HURT AND
ANGRY SAID
I WAS BEING UNSUPPORTIVE
AND NOW
I'M SITTING HERE
WRACKED WITH GUILT
RESENTMENT
AND
BONE DEEP EXHAUSTION
WONDERING
IF I'M TRULY
ASKING FOR
TOO MUCH OR
IF I'VE JUST BECOME
THE PERSON EXPECTED
TO ABSORB ALL
THE
STRESS SO EVERYONE
ELSE CAN FUNCTION