MY PARTNER
AND I WENT TO
A LARGE ASIAN-STYLE
BUFFET TO
RING IN THE NEW YEAR
TOGETHER.
HOPING FOR
A RELAXED,
FESTIVE MEAL,
AS WE WALKED
ALONG THE HOT
FOOD LINE, WE
NOTICED ONE
OF THE MOST POPULAR
ITEMS.
STICKY GLAZED
PORK RIBS,
HAD JUST RUN
OUT, BUT
A SERVER WAS
WEAVING THROUGH
THE CROWD WITH
A FRESH METAL
TRAY.
WE STEPPED
ASIDE POLITELY
AND WAITED, ASSUMING
IT WOULD BE FAIR
GAME ONCE
IT WAS SET DOWN.
THE MOMENT
THE TRAY HIT
THE COUNTER, ANOTHER
DINER LUNGED
FOR THE SERVING TONGS
AND BEGAN AND PILING
RIBS ONTO HER
PLATE.
AT FIRST,
I DIDN'T THINK
MUCH OF IT,
FIGURING SHE'D
TAKE A PORTION AND
MOVE ON. INSTEAD,
SHE KEPT
GOING, CAREFULLY
STACKING PIECE
AFTER PIECE
UNTIL HER PLATE
WAS NEARLY OVERFLOWING.
THEN, TO
MY SURPRISE, SHE
GRABBED A SECOND
PLATE AND WAVED
OVER A YOUNG BOY,
POSSIBLY HER
GRANDSON, AND
STARTED LOADING
THAT ONE TOO.
BY THE
TIME SHE WAS
DONE, CLOSE
TO HALF THE TRAY
WAS GONE,
AND A SMALL
CROWD HAD FORMED
BEHIND US WAITING,
UNDER MY
BREATH, BUT
LOUD ENOUGH TO
CARRY.
I REMARKED
TO MY PARTNER SOMETHING
LIKE, WOW
I
GUESS EVERYONE
ELSE IS JUST
SUPPOSED TO MISS
OUT THE
WOMAN CLEARLY HEARD
ME SHE
SPUN AROUND
SLAMMED
THE TONGS
BACK INTO THE TRAY
WITH A SHARP
CLATTER SHOT
AS AN ANGRY LOOK
AND
STORMED OFF
WITHOUT TAKING
ANOTHER BITE
MY
PARTNER IMMEDIATELY
LOOKED MORTIFIED
AND TOLD ME I'D
MADE A SCENE FOR
NO REASON SHE
SAID IT WOULD HAVE
BEEN EASIER AND
LESS AWKWARD
TO JUST
GRAB SOMETHING ELSE
AND CIRCLE BACK
LATER INSTEAD
OF CALLING ATTENTION
TO IT
BUT
WAS I REALLY WRONG
FOR SPEAKING UP
WHEN ONE PERSON
WAS CLEARLY TAKING
MORE THAN THEIR
SHARE