MY
MOTHER -IN
-LAW IS VERY
GENEROUS, AND
THIS YEAR
SHE BOUGHT CHRISTMAS
GIFTS FOR
BOTH OF MY
SONS.
MY
TODDLER, WHO
JUST TURNED
ONE, AND
MY EIGHT -YEAR
-OLD, WHO'S
BEEN HAVING A
HARD TIME
ADJUSTING TO
NO LONGER BEING
THE BABY
OF THE
FAMILY.
BECAUSE
OF THAT, I'VE
BEEN EXTRA CAREFUL
ABOUT MAKING
SURE HE
FEELS SEEN
AND
VALUED.
HERE'S
WHERE THINGS WENT
SIDEWAYS.
WAYS.
FOR
THE BABY, MY
MILL BOUGHT SEVERAL
FUN, FLASHY
TOYS, A
TALKING CHARACTER
PLUSH,
A RIDE
-ON CAR, THE
KIND OF BIG,
EXCITING
ITEMS LITTLE
KIDS IMMEDIATELY
LATCH
ONTO.
BUT FOR
MY EIGHT -YEAR
-OLD, SHE
CHOSE A BOARD
GAME HE'S
NEVER SHOWN INTEREST
IN, A
NUTCRACKER
FIGURINE,
AND A
BASQUIAT
ART COFFEE
TABLE
BOOK.
SHE SAID
SHE THOUGHT IT
WOULD INSPIRE
HIM,
BUT HE'S NOT
AN ART KID
IN THAT
WAY.
HE
LIKES DRAWING
CHARACTERS
FROM GAMES
HE PLAYS,
BUT HE'S
NOT SPENDING
AFTERNOONS
STUDYING MODERN
ART.
I TOLD
HER I WAS
WORRIED.
I CAN
ALREADY PICTURE
CHRISTMAS
MORNING.
THE BABY
HAS A HUGE
UNWRAPPED
RIDE ON CAR
AND ANIMATED
TOYS.
AND
MY 8 YEAR
OLD, WHO'S
BEEN FRAGILE
LATELY, UNWRAPS
A BOARD GAME
HE WON'T
TOUCH AND
A GIANT ART
BOOK MEANT FOR
ADULTS.
I'M NOT ASKING
FOR ANYTHING
EXTRAVAGANT.
JUST SOMETHING
AGE APPROPRIATE
THAT FEELS
FUN FOR
HIM.
SHE PUSHED
BACK
IMMEDIATELY.
SHE SAID
SHE SPENT THE
SAME AMOUNT
OF MONEY ON
BOTH
KIDS.
THE NUTCRACKER
WAS THE BIG
GIFT AND
IT'S UNFAIR
FOR ME TO
ASK HER TO BUY
ANYTHING
ELSE.
SHE
ALSO SEEMED
OFFENDED THAT
I QUESTIONED
HER CHOICES
AT ALL
I'M
TRYING TO ADVOCATE
FOR MY
SON NOT
MICROMANAGE
HER GIFT GIVING
BUT
NOW I'M SECOND
GUESSING MYSELF
SO
AM
I WRONG FOR
ASKING HER
TO GET A MORE
SUITABLE PRESENT
OR IS IT
REASONABLE TO
WORRY ABOUT
HOW AN EIGHT
-YEAR -OLD WILL
FEEL ON CHRISTMAS
MORNING