MORE
THAN A DECADE
AGO, WHEN
I WAS IN MY
MID -TWENTIES,
I SURVIVED
A HORRIFIC
ACCIDENT
THAT TOOK THE
LIFE OF THE MAN
I WAS SUPPOSED
TO
MARRY.
WE
WERE TOGETHER
IN THE
CAR.
I WALKED
AWAY WITH
MINOR
INJURIES.
HE NEVER
MADE IT
OUT.
THE AFTERMATH
SHATTERED
ME.
I SPENT
YEARS CYCLING
THROUGH THERAPY
OFFICES, GRIEF
GROUPS, AND
LONG STRETCHES
WHERE SIMPLY
GETTING THROUGH
THE DAY FELT
LIKE
WORK.
EVENTUALLY,
THROUGH ONE
OF THOSE SUPPORT
GROUPS, I
MET MY CURRENT
PARTNER, A
WIDOWER WHO
HAD HAD ALSO LOST
THE LOVE OF
HIS
LIFE.
WE UNDERSTOOD
EACH OTHER
IN A WAY FEW
PEOPLE
COULD.
AND AFTER
YEARS OF
FRIENDSHIP, WE
SLOWLY BUILT
SOMETHING
NEW.
RECENTLY,
WE TOOK
THE STEP OF
MOVING IN
TOGETHER.
THROUGHOUT
ALL THESE
YEARS, I
STAYED CLOSE
TO MY LATE
PARTNER'S
FAMILY.
THEY WERE
MY LIFELINE
IN THE BEGINNING,
AND I
BELIEVED WE
HAD BUILT SOMETHING
LASTING
OUT OF SHARED
LOSS.
THAT
BELIEF CRACKED
WHEN HIS MOTHER
CALLED ME LAST
WEEK AND
CALMLY ASKED
ME TO RETURN
MY ENGAGEMENT
RING
NOW THAT I
WAS MOVING
ON.
SHE SAID
SHE WANTED IT
BACK TO KEEP
IT IN THE
FAMILY.
AS
IF THE RING
HAD ALWAYS BELONGED
TO THEM
IT
HADN'T WE
CHOSE IT
TOGETHER IT
WASN'T A
DIAMOND OR
AN HEIRLOOM
BUT
A CUSTOM PIECE
WITH STONES
TIED TO
OUR BIRTHDAYS
SOMETHING
HE SAVED
FOR AND SURPRISED
ME WITH
BECAUSE IT FELT
PERSONAL
AND RIGHT THAT
RING CARRIES
MEMORIES THAT
ARE PAINFUL YES
BUT
ALSO FULL
OF LOVE JOY
AND
THE LIFE WE
PLANNED I
NO LONGER
WEAR IT ON
MY LEFT HAND
BUT
IT HASN'T
BEEN HIDDEN AWAY
EITHER I
WEAR IT OPENLY
ON MY RIGHT
JUST
AS MY PARTNER
WEARS HIS OWN
WEDDING BAND
IN
OUR HOME BOTH
OF OUR PAST
LOVES ARE
ACKNOWLEDGED WITHOUT
SHAME OR
SECRECY
THEIR
PHOTOS SIT
ON OUR
SHELVES.
NOT
AS
GHOSTS.
BUT AS
PARTS OF WHO
WE
ARE.
MY CURRENT
PARTNER HAS
NEVER ONCE
FELT THREATENED
BY
THIS.
AND NEITHER
HAVE
I.
WE HONOR
WHAT WAS WHILE
STILL CHOOSING
WHAT
IS.
WHEN
I EXPLAINED
THIS.
HIS MOTHER
DOUBLED
DOWN.
SHE SAID
THE RING MATTERED
BECAUSE IT
WAS ONE OF THE
LAST SIGNIFICANT
THINGS
HER SON EVER
BOUGHT.
AS
IF MY CONNECTION
TO IT WAS
SECONDARY.
THE CONVERSATION
SPIRALED
UNTIL I WAS
SHAKING.
OVERWHELMED.
AND HURT ENOUGH
THAT I ENDED
THE
CALL.
SINCE
THEN.
I'VE AVOIDED
HER ATTEMPTS
TO REACH
ME.
MY PARTNER
IS FURIOUS
ON MY
BEHALF.
HALF.
CONVINCED
I'M BEING PUNISHED
FOR SURVIVING
AND FINDING
HAPPINESS
AGAIN.
MY
OWN PARENTS
ARE
SPLIT.
ONE
URGING COMPASSION
FOR
A GRIEVING
MOTHER.
THE OTHER
REMINDING ME
THAT THE RING WAS
A
GIFT.
FREELY
GIVEN.
AND STILL
MINE.
NOW I'M
LEFT SITTING
WITH THIS
HEAVY.
FAMILIAR
GUILT.
WONDERING
WHEN REMEMBRANCE
QUIETLY
TURNED INTO
OBLIGATION.
AND WHETHER
LOVING SOMEONE
NEW MEANS
I'M EXPECTED
TO GIVE UP
THE LAST TANGIBLE
PROOF OF
A LOVE
THAT.
SHAPED
MY ENTIRE
LIFE.