I GREW
UP IN A HOUSEHOLD
WHERE LOVE CAME
WITH CONDITIONS
AND ANGER
CAME WITHOUT WARNING.
BY THE
TIME I WAS
BARELY A TEENAGER,
THINGS HAD
ESCALATED
SO BADLY
THAT SOCIAL SERVICES
INTERVENED
AND I WAS LEGALLY
PLACED WITH
MY OTHER
PARENT.
DURING THAT
PROCESS, MY
MOTHER MADE IT
PAINFULLY CLEAR
HOW SHE FELT
ABOUT ME. ON
OFFICIAL PAPERWORK,
SHE WROTE
THAT SHE NO LONGER
HAD A CHILD.
THAT SINGLE
SENTENCE FOLLOWED
ME FOR DECADES
AND PERMANENTLY
SHATTERED WHAT
LITTLE SENSE OF
FAMILY I
HAD LEFT. FOR
MOST OF
MY ADULT LIFE.
I COPE
BY SELF-DESTRUCTING.
I DRINK
HEAVILY THROUGH
MY 20S
AND 30S,
DRIFTING FROM
JOB TO JOB,
RELATIONSHIP
TO RELATIONSHIP,
UNTIL I
FINALLY GOT SOBER
SEVERAL YEARS
AGO.
SOBRIETY FORCED
ME TO CONFRONT
OLD WOUNDS.
AND AGAINST
MY BETTER JUDGMENT,
I REACHED
OUT TO MY MOTHER
AGAIN.
SHE WAS NEARING
70 BY
THEN AND HAD
ALREADY LOST CONTACT
WITH MOST OF
HER CHILDREN. I
HOPED TIME HAD
SOFTENED HER.
IT HADN'T,
WHEN I CAUTIOUSLY
ASKED IF
SHE HAD HAD EVER REFLECTED
ON THE PAST.
SHE DISMISSED
IT ENTIRELY
AND TOLD
ME TO STOP LIVING
IN THE PAST.
I REALIZED THEN
THAT ANY RELATIONSHIP
WE HAD WOULD
REQUIRE ME
TO STAY QUIET
ABOUT MY PAIN.
DESPITE THAT,
WE MAINTAINED
A FRAGILE
CONNECTION, OCCASIONAL
FAMILY GATHERINGS,
LONG PHONE
CALLS THAT
TURNED INTO ARGUMENTS,
EVEN A
TENSE INTERNATIONAL
TRIP
THAT FELT MORE
LIKE EMOTIONAL ENDURANCE
TRAINING THAN
A VACATION. STILL,
I KEPT TRYING.
LAST YEAR,
I INVITED
HER TO VISIT
ME IN MY CITY
TO SEE A MUSICIAN
SHE'D ADORED
SINCE MY CHILDHOOD.
THE PLAN
WAS SPECIFIC
AND SHORT.
SHE'D ARRIVE
MIDWEEK, WE'D
ATTEND THE SHOW,
SHE'D LEAVE
THE NEXT AFTERNOON
TO VISIT MY
SIBLINGS, AND
I'D DEPART EARLY
THE FOLLOWING MORNING
FOR A WORK TRIP.
THE MOMENT
SHE ARRIVED,
SHE CASUALLY
MENTIONED SHE'D
ONLY PURCHASED
A ONE-WAY
TICKET.
MY STOMACH
DROPPED.
I REMINDED
HER, SEVERAL
TIMES, THAT
I WOULDN'T BE HOME
AFTER HER SCHEDULED
DEPARTURE AND
THAT I WASN'T COMFORTABLE
WITH ANYONE STAYING
IN MY HOME
WHILE I WAS AWAY.
EACH REMINDER
WAS BRUSHED
OFF WITH VAGUE REASSURANCES
AFTER
THE CONCERT
SHE ADMITTED
SHE STILL HADN'T
BOOKED A FLIGHT
PRICES
HAD INCREASED
SHE
SAID AND
SHE DECIDED TO
STAY A FEW EXTRA
DAYS INSTEAD
ALONE
IN
MY HOUSE WHILE
I WAS GONE
I TOLD
HER CLEARLY THAT
I WAS LEAVING BEFORE
SUNRISE AND
THAT SHE NEEDED TO
BE ON A PLANE
I
EVEN OFFERED
TO PAY THE DIFFERENCE
SHE
REFUSED ACCUSED
ME OF TREATING
HER LIKE A
STRANGER AND
INSISTED THAT
BEING MY MOTHER
GAVE HER THE
RIGHT TO STAY THE
ARGUMENT EXPLODED
FINALLY
SHE
SHE SNAPPED AND DEMANDED
I TAKE HER TO
THE AIRPORT. I
THINK SHE EXPECTED
ME TO FOLD
LIKE I ALWAYS
HAD BEFORE. I
DIDN'T.
I DROVE HER
THERE IN SILENCE.
UNLOADED HER
BAG, AND
TOLD HER THAT
IF SHE COULDN'T
SECURE A FLIGHT,
I'D HELP
PAY FOR A HOTEL.
THEN I WALKED
AWAY, HEART
POUNDING, KNOWING
EXACTLY HOW
DRAMATIC IT
LOOKED.
IT'S BEEN MONTHS,
AND I STILL
REPLAY THAT
MOMENT.
STANDING AT
THE CURB, CHOOSING
MYSELF FOR
THE FIRST TIME,
AND WONDERING
IF SETTING THAT
BOUNDARY COST
ME WHATEVER FRAGILE
PEACE WE
HAD LEFT. OR
IF IT WAS THE ONLY
CHOICE I
EVER REALLY HAD.