I'M ABOUT
TO TURN 18
AND PLANNED
A SMALL BIRTHDAY
DINNER AT MY
HOUSE WITH JUST
MY CLOSEST
FRIENDS.
NOTHING WILD,
SOME SIMPLE
GRILLING, ORDERING
PIZZA, AND
LETTING PEOPLE BRING
FOOD IF THEY
WANTED.
BUT WITH NO
PRESSURE, ONE
OF MY FRIENDS ASKED
IF HE COULD BRING
HIS NEW GIRLFRIEND.
AND I
AGREED SINCE
HE WASN'T EVEN
PLANNING TO
STAY LONG. SHE
OFFERED TO MAKE
SOMETHING FOR THE
DINNER.
AND I THANKED
HER BUT TOLD HER
IT WASN'T NECESSARY.
SHE INSISTED
ANYWAY.
I LATER
CREATED A
GROUP CHAT FOR
EVERYONE ATTENDING
AND SENT OUT
THE BASIC DETAILS.
INCLUDING
ONE VERY CLEAR
AND SERIOUS RULE
ONE
OF MY FRIENDS
HAS A SEVERE
NUT ALLERGY
SO
ANYTHING BROUGHT
NEEDED TO BE
COMPLETELY NUT
FREE INCLUDING
AVOIDING CROSS-CONTAMINATION
EVERYONE
ACKNOWLEDGED THE
MESSAGE INCLUDING
THE GIRLFRIEND
WHO
REACTED TO
IT THE NIGHT
BEFORE MY PARTY
SHE
CASUALLY MENTIONED
WHAT SHE'D MADE
AND SENT ME
A PHOTO IT
WAS A HOMEMADE CAKE
THAT I IMMEDIATELY
RECOGNIZED
AS ONE THAT
USUALLY CONTAINS
NUTS WHEN
I ASKED SHE
CONFIRMED IT
DID BUT
SAID IT WASN'T
MUCH AND
THAT THE ALLERGIC FRIEND
COULD JUST NOT
EAT IT I
TOLD HER I WASN'T
COMFORTABLE HAVING
IT IN MY HOUSE
AT ALL AND ASKED
HER NOT TO BRING IT.
SHE GOT
ANGRY AND
SAID SHE'D ALREADY
PUT IN A LOT
OF EFFORT. SO
EITHER THE CAKE
COMES OR SHE
DOESN'T.
I TOLD
HER THEN SHE
SHOULDN'T COME
BECAUSE
I'D BEEN CLEAR
FROM THE START
AND I WASN'T
RISKING MY FRIEND'S
HEALTH FOR A DESSERT.
SHE ACCUSED
ME OF BEING
DISRESPECTFUL,
SAID SHE
HAD A RIGHT TO
BE THERE BECAUSE
SHE WAS DATING
MY FRIEND.
AND THINGS
ESCALATED
FAST WHEN
HER BOYFRIEND CALLED
ME.
HE YELLED
THAT I WAS CRUEL
AND UNGRATEFUL.
AND I
SNAPPED BACK,
SAYING I
DIDN'T CARE HOW
LONG THE CAKE
TOOK.
NUTS WERE
THE THE ONE THING
I EXPLICITLY SAID
NOT TO BRING. I
ALSO SAID
SOME HARSH THINGS
IN FRUSTRATION ABOUT
HER IGNORING CLEAR
INSTRUCTIONS.
NOW THEY'RE
BOTH SKIPPING THE
PARTY AND TELLING
OTHERS I DISINVITED
HER AFTER SHE
WORKED HARD ON.
SOMETHING FOR
ME.
MOST PEOPLE
NOT ATTENDING
THINK I WAS
WRONG.
WHILE THE
FEW WHO ARE COMING,
ESPECIALLY
THE FRIEND
WITH THE ALLERGY,
SAY I
DID THE RIGHT THING.
WITH MY
PARTY HAPPENING
TOMORROW, I'M
LEFT WONDERING IF
STANDING FIRM
ABOUT SAFETY
MADE ME THE
VILLAIN.
OR IF
I WAS RIGHT TO
DRAW THE LINE EVEN
WHEN IT BLEW UP
FRIENDSHIPS.