A FEW MONTHS
AGO, I
WAS COMPETING
IN A TWO
-WEEK SHOOTING
COMPETITION.
IT REQUIRED
A 35
-MINUTE DRIVE
EACH WAY,
EVERY
SINGLE DAY,
OVER AN
HOUR OF DRIVING
ON TOP OF
PHYSICALLY EXHAUSTING
LONG SESSIONS
AT THE
RANGE.
MY
ROOMMATE WAS
ALSO COMPETING,
BUT
HIS CAR HAD
COMPLETELY GIVEN
OUT, SO
HE RODE WITH
ME EVERY
DAY.
AT
FIRST, I
DIDN'T THINK
MUCH OF IT,
BUT HALFWAY
THROUGH THE FIRST
WEEK, I
STARTED NOTICING
HOW QUICKLY
MY GAS TANK
WAS
DRAINING.
THE
COST WASN'T
SMALL, AND
IT GENUINELY
WASN'T
SOMETHING I HAD
BUDGETED
FOR.
NOT
DAILY, NOT
AT THAT
DISTANCE.
ONE EVENING,
AFTER AN
ESPECIALLY LONG
DAY IN THE HEAT,
I FINALLY
ASKED HIM
IF HE COULD SPOT
$10
TO HELP
COVER
GAS.
JUST
$10, WITHOUT
EVEN LOOKING
UP FROM HIS
PHONE.
HE SAID,
FLAT AS
STONE, NOT
GONNA
HAPPEN.
IT WASN'T
JUST THE REFUSAL,
IT WAS
THE
DISMISSIVENESS.
I WAS
TIRED, STRESSED,
AND SUDDENLY
VERY AWARE
THAT I WAS
FOOTING THE ENTIRE
BILL FOR
BOTH OF
US.
I
TOLD HIM THAT
IF HE COULDN'T
CHIP IN EVEN
A LITTLE, HE'D
NEED TO FIND
A DIFFERENT RIDE
THE
NEXT DAY AFTER
SHOOTING SOME
OF OUR MUTUAL
FRIENDS CALLED
ME OVER APPARENTLY
HE
HAD GONE STRAIGHT
TO THEM AND
TOLD THEM EVERYTHING
EXCEPT
OF
COURSE THE
PART ABOUT REFUSING
TO HELP
AT ALL THEY
TOOK HIS SIDE
IMMEDIATELY TELLING
ME I WAS
BEING UNREASONABLE
THAT
I NEEDED TO
BE A GOOD ROOMMATE
THAT ASKING
FOR GAS
MONEY
WAS OUT OF
LINE IT
FELT LIKE
BEING AMBUSHED
I DIDN'T
HAVE THE ENERGY
FOR A CONFLICT
AND
THE PRESSURE FROM
EVERYONE MADE
ME CAVE
I
I APOLOGIZED,
EVEN THOUGH
A PART OF ME
HATED DOING
IT, AND
LET HIM RIDE
WITH ME FOR
THE REST OF
THE
COMPETITION.
BUT NOW
THAT TIME HAS
PASSED, I
STILL CAN'T
SHAKE THE FEELING
THAT SOMETHING
ABOUT THE
WHOLE SITUATION
WAS VERY
ONE
-SIDED.
I
WAS THE ONLY
ONE DRIVING,
THE ONLY
ONE PAYING,
AND THE ONLY
ONE ASKED
TO BE A GOOD
ROOMMATE.
SO
I KEEP WONDERING,
WAS I
REALLY OUT
OF LINE FOR
ASKING FOR
$10
IN GAS
MONEY?
OR WAS
I JUST EXPECTED
TO CARRY
THE FULL BURDEN
WITHOUT SAYING
A
WORD?