I'M
A 23-YEAR-OLD
WOMAN WHO JUST
FINISHED UNIVERSITY
AND FINALLY
LANDED A COMPETITIVE
ENTRY-LEVEL
JOB
IN MARKETING
WITH A MAJOR
TECH COMPANY,
THE KIND
OF OPPORTUNITY THAT
ONLY COMES ONCE
IF YOU'RE LUCKY.
MY YOUNGER
BROTHER, EVAN,
IS 19 AND
HAS A GENETIC
DISABILITY.
HE'S BRIGHT,
AFFECTIONATE,
LOVES COMIC
BOOKS, AND
CAN HOLD CONVERSATIONS,
BUT HE ALSO
NEEDS DAILY
SUPERVISION,
HELP WITH
ROUTINES, AND
CAREFUL MANAGEMENT
OF A HEART
CONDITION.
GROWING
UP,
I WAS THE DEFAULT
CAREGIVER.
FROM MY
EARLY TEENS
ONWARD, I
HANDLED PICKUPS,
MEDICATIONS, MELTDOWNS,
BEDTIME ROUTINES,
AND CRISIS
MOMENTS WHILE
MY PARENTS WORKED
AND MY OLDER SISTER
MOVED OUT
AND FOCUSED ON
HER OWN LIFE.
I MISSED
SOCIAL EVENTS,
CLUBS, AND
OPPORTUNITIES BECAUSE
I WAS CONSTANTLY
REMINDED THAT
EVAN TRUSTED ME
MOST AND
NEEDED ME
MORE THAN
ANYONE ELSE.
I DID
IT WITHOUT COMPLAINT
BECAUSE I LOVE
HIM.
RIGHT AS
I WAS PREPARING
TO START MY
NEW JOB,
MY BROTHER'S
DAY PROGRAM LOST
FUNDING AND
CUT HOURS, LEAVING
A GAP IN
HIS CARE. AT
A FAMILY LUNCH,
MY PARENTS
BLINDSIDED ME
AND TOLD ME THEY
EXPECTED ME
TO QUIT, OR
AT LEAST INDEFINITELY
DEFER, MY
JOB TO STAY
HOME WITH EVAN
DURING THE DAY.
THEY FRAMED
IT AS A TEMPORARY
SACRIFICE
AND A MORAL
OBLIGATION, INSISTING
THAT STRANGERS COULDN'T
BE TRUSTED AND
THAT MY CAREER
COULD WAIT. WHEN
I ASKED WHY
MY SISTER COULDN'T
HELP OR WHY THEY
COULDN'T ADJUST WORK
SCHEDULES OR
USE SAVINGS. THINGS.
I WAS
TOLD SHE HAD
HER OWN LIFE
NOW AND THAT IT
WAS MY TURN
TO STEP UP.
EVEN THOUGH
I ALREADY HAD
FOR MOST OF
MY CHILDHOOD. WHEN
I REFUSED, MY
FATHER ACCUSED
ME OF CHOOSING
MONEY OVER
MY DISABLED BROTHER.
AND MY
MOTHER CRIED
THAT I WAS ABANDONING
THE FAMILY. THAT
NIGHT, THE
ARGUMENT ESCALATED
SO BADLY
THAT I PACKED
A BAG AND
MOVED IN WITH A
FRIEND.
SINCE THEN,
RELATIVES HAVE
BEEN CALLING ME
SELFISH.
SAYING A
FEW MONTHS WON'T
HURT MY CAREER
BUT LOSING CONSISTENT
CARE COULD
DEVASTATE MY
BROTHER.
I FEEL
CRUSHED WITH GUILT
BECAUSE I LOVE
HIM DEEPLY. BUT
I ALSO FEEL
LIKE I'VE ALREADY
GIVEN UP YEARS
OF MY LIFE
AND THIS JOB REPRESENTS
MY FIRST
REAL CHANCE
AT INDEPENDENCE.
I CAN'T
TELL IF I'M FINALLY
SETTING A HEALTHY
BOUNDARY OR
IF I'M FAILING
MY FAMILY
WHEN THEY NEED
ME MOST.