MY SISTER'S
CLOSE FRIEND,
CALL HER DANA,
LOST HER
RENTAL UNEXPECTEDLY
EARLIER
THIS YEAR,
SINCE SHE
HAD NOWHERE TO
GO ON SHORT
NOTICE.
MY WIFE
OFFERED FOR DANA
AND HER TWO TEENAGE
SONS, COLIN
AND MASON, BOTH
17, TO
STAY WITH US
TEMPORARILY.
WE HAVE
A 15 -YEAR
-OLD SON,
LEO.
HE'S GENERALLY
POLITE AND
GETS ALONG WITH
MOST PEOPLE,
BUT HE'S
INTROVERTED AND
VALUES PERSONAL
SPACE.
NOT LONG
AFTER THEY MOVED
IN, COLIN
AND MASON STARTED
TREATING LEO'S
ROOM LIKE A
COMMUNAL HANGOUT
SPOT.
EVEN THOUGH HE
REPEATEDLY ASKED
THEM NOT
TO.
THEY'D WALK
IN WHENEVER THEY
WANTED, BORROWING
HIS GAMING
HEADSET, TAKING
SNACKS FROM
HIS DRAWERS, MESSING
WITH HIS ART
SUPPLIES, AND
EVEN USING
HIS COMPUTER
WITHOUT
PERMISSION.
LEO COMPLAINED
TO ME SEVERAL
TIMES, BUT
WHENEVER I BROUGHT
IT UP, MY
WIFE AND DANA
BRUSHED IT OFF
AS NORMAL TEENAGE
BOY BEHAVIOR
AND SAID
I SHOULDN'T MAKE
A BIG DEAL
OUT OF
IT.
THE BREAKING
POINT CAME
WHEN LEO SPENT
WEEKS SAVING
UP FOR A SET
OF SPECIALTY MARKERS
HE NEEDED FOR
AN
ART
COMPETITION.
WHEN HE
FINALLY BOUGHT
THEM,
HIM.
HE LEFT
THE SET NEATLY
ARRANGED ON
HIS
DESK.
A DAY LATER,
HE FOUND
THE MARKERS SCATTERED
ALL OVER
THE
CARPET.
SEVERAL OF
THEM DRIED OUT
OR
CRUSHED.
APPARENTLY, COLIN
AND MASON HAD
TAKEN THEM TO
TRY DRAWING SOMETHING
COOL AND
LEFT THEM
BEHIND.
LEO WAS
DEVASTATED.
HE'D BEEN WORKING
TOWARD THAT PURCHASE
FOR
AGES.
I DECIDED
ENOUGH WAS
ENOUGH.
I INSTALLED
A LOCK ON
LEO'S DOOR
SO HE COULD AT
LEAST KEEP HIS
BELONGINGS
SAFE.
WHEN DANA
AND THE BOYS SAW
IT, THEY
WERE
FURIOUS.
DANA INSISTED
HER SONS
AREN'T DOING ANYTHING
MALICIOUS AND
ACCUSED ME
OF MAKING THEM FEEL
UNWELCOME SHE
SAID LEO WAS
BEING DRAMATIC
AND NEEDED TO
LEARN TO SHARE
MY
WIFE SIDED
WITH HER SAYING
THE LOCK MADE
THE BOYS FEEL
LIKE CRIMINALS
SHE
DEMANDED I
REMOVE IT BUT
I REFUSED I
TOLD HER THE
LOCK STAYS UNTIL
DANA AND HER
SONS FIND
A PERMANENT PLACE
TO STAY LEO
SHOULDN'T HAVE TO
HIDE HIS BELONGINGS
OR LOSE THINGS
BECAUSE OTHER
PEOPLE'S BOUNDARIES
ARE NON
-EXISTENT
MY WIFE
GOT UPSET AND
SAID I WAS BASICALLY
TELLING HER
FRIEND TO GET OUT
THEN
SHE SAID HER
SIDE OF THE FAMILY
WOULD THINK I
WAS BEING INSENSITIVE
SINCE
THEY WERE THE ONES
WHO ENCOURAGED HER
TO HELP DANA
IN THE FIRST
PLACE.
I REMINDED
HER THAT NO
ONE ELSE ACTUALLY
OFFERED DANA
A PLACE TO
STAY.
AND THAT
IF THEY HAD, OUR
HOUSEHOLD WOULDN'T
BE DEALING WITH
THIS LEVEL OF
CHAOS.
NOW DANA
AND THE BOYS BARELY
SPEAK TO ME,
MY WIFE
IS STILL ANGRY,
AND THE ATMOSPHERE
IN THE HOUSE IS
TENSE.
I'M STANDING
BY THE DECISION,
BUT IT'S
BECOME A HUGE
ISSUE.