I MOVED
INTO A SHARED
APARTMENT IN
A CITY AFTER
A CO-WORKER,
LENA, OFFERED
ME HER SPARE ROOM
WHEN I WAS STRUGGLING
TO FIND HOUSING.
WE WEREN'T
CLOSE, BUT
SHE SEEMED KIND
AT FIRST, AND
I WAS RELIEVED
TO HAVE SOMEWHERE
AFFORDABLE.
THAT GRATITUDE
MADE ME OVERLOOK
A LOT EARLY ON.
LENA WOULD
WANDER INTO
MY ROOM WITHOUT
ASKING, SIT
ON MY BED
AFTER WALKING AROUND
BAREFOOT, SNACK
ON MY FOOD,
AND USE MY
THINGS LIKE THEY
WERE COMMUNAL. WHEN
I TRIED
TO SET BOUNDARIES
CASUALLY, SHE
LEFT IT OFF
AND KEPT DOING
IT.
OVER TIME,
IT STOPPED
FEELING HARMLESS.
I STARTED
LOCKING MY
DOOR WHEN I
LEFT, BUT
I KEPT GETTING
THIS UNSETTLING
SENSE THAT
SOMEONE HAD STILL
BEEN INSIDE. WHEN
I ASKED HER DIRECTLY
IF SHE HAD A
SPARE KEY, SHE
SNAPPED, ACCUSED
ME OF BEING
PARANOID, AND
SHUT THE CONVERSATION
DOWN.
THAT WAS THE
MOMENT I REALIZED
I DIDN'T FEEL
SAFE IN MY
OWN ROOM ANYMORE.
WHILE SHE WAS
OUT ONE EVENING,
I ASKED
A FRIEND TO REPLACE
THE LOCK ON
MY BEDROOM DOOR.
A
FEW DAYS
LATER, SHE
EXPLODED,
FLOODING MY
PHONE WITH MESSAGES
ABOUT HOW
I DISRESPECTED
HER, CLAIMING
I NEEDED HER
PERMISSION, AND
SAYING BUILDING
STAFF WERE
QUESTIONING HER
BECAUSE OF ME.
WHEN I GOT
HOME, SHE
YELLED THAT SHE
REGRETTED LETTING
ME MOVE IN
AND SAID I'D BE
FORCED OUT.
I WENT
TO THE BUILDING OFFICE
MYSELF THE
NEXT DAY. THEY
TOLD ME SHE ALREADY
HAD MULTIPLE
COMPLAINTS
FROM PAST ROOMMATES
INVOLVING INTIMIDATION
AND MISSING
PROPERTY.
THEY ALSO
CONFIRMED I
HAD EVERY RIGHT
TO CHANGE THE
LOCK ON MY PRIVATE
ROOM.
AFTER THAT,
I FILED
A FORMAL REPORT.
COURT.
A NOTICE
WAS ISSUED TO
HER ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
AND WHILE
THE APARTMENT IS
TENSE NOW, I
FINALLY FEEL
SECURE.
I DIDN'T
WANT CONFLICT.
I WANTED BOUNDARIES.
I JUST
DIDN'T EXPECT PROTECTING
MYSELF TO
TURN INTO A
FULL-BLOWN WAR.