AFTER GIVING
BIRTH IN
LATE NOVEMBER, I
THOUGHT WE HAD A
CLEAR PLAN FOR
THE HOLIDAYS. THE
IDEA WAS
TO SPEND CHRISTMAS
EVE, CHRISTMAS
DAY, AND
THE DAY AFTER
WITH MY PARTNER'S
FAMILY, GIVING
US ABOUT A
MONTH AT HOME
FIRST TO SETTLE
IN WITH OUR NEWBORN
AND FIND
OUR RHYTHM. THAT
PLAN FELL APART
FAST OUR
BABY ENDED
UP IN THE NEONATAL
INTENSIVE CARE
UNIT AND STAYED
THERE FOR
ALMOST FOUR
WEEKS.
ON TOP
OF THAT, I
HAD A SERIOUS
MEDICAL SCARE
MYSELF AND
EXPERIENCED A
POSTPARTUM
HEMORRHAGE AT
HOME TWO WEEKS
AGO.
BETWEEN MEDICATIONS,
MONITORING
BLOOD SUGAR
LEVELS, AND
THE EMOTIONAL
WHIPLASH
OF IT ALL, THE
PAST MONTH
HAS BEEN EXHAUSTING
AND OVERWHELMING.
OUR BABY
HAS ONLY BEEN
HOME FOR THREE
FULL DAYS. WE'RE
STILL ADJUSTING,
STILL ANXIOUS,
STILL HEALING.
BECAUSE OF
THAT, WE
DECIDED THE
SAFEST AND
CALMEST OPTION
WAS TO STAY
HOME FOR CHRISTMAS.
WE TOLD
FAMILY THEY
WERE WELCOME TO
COME BY BRIEFLY,
AND I EVEN
SAID I WAS OPEN
TO A SHORT VISIT
ON CHRISTMAS DAY.
BUT WE
WOULDN'T BE TRAVELING
ANYWHERE OR
HOSTING LONG,
DRAWN-OUT
GATHERINGS.
BEING IN
OUR OWN SPACE FEELS
ESSENTIAL RIGHT
NOW.
THIS DECISION
DIDN'T GO OVER
WELL WITH MY
PARTNER'S MOTHER.
SHE'S EXTREMELY
UPSET AND
HAS SAID SHE MAY
NOT COME AT ALL.
HER FRUSTRATION
GREW WHEN
SHE FOUND OUT
ANOTHER RELATIVE
WOULD BE VISITING
AROUND THE SAME
TIME.
THE DIFFERENCE IS
THAT THIS OTHER PERSON
ACTUALLY HELPED.
BRINGING MEALS,
DOING LAUNDRY,
AND EVEN CLEANING
UP AFTER MY
MEDICAL EMERGENCY
AT HOME.
MY PARTNER'S
MOTHER TENDS TO
FRAME HER HELP
AS WANTING TO
HOLD A BABY
SO I CAN GET
THINGS DONE. WHICH,
RIGHT NOW,
ISN'T WHAT
I NEED MOST.
MY PARTNER
ADMITTED SHE
EXPECTED THIS
REACTION AND
SAID IT FELT LIKE
AN IMPOSSIBLE SITUATION
WHERE SOMEONE
WAS BOUND TO
BE HURT. SHE'S
TRIED TO STAY
NEUTRAL, NOT
REALLY TAKING
SIDES, WHICH
LEAVES ME FEELING
A BIT ALONE
IN HOLDING THIS
BOUNDARY.
I'VE ALREADY
COMPROMISED MORE
THAN I WANTED TO.
I ALLOWED
A VISIT LESS
THAN A DAY AFTER
WE GOT HOME.
EVEN THOUGH
I WANTED MORE
TIME, I'VE
OFFERED MULTIPLE SHORT
VISITS OVER
THE HOLIDAYS.
I EVEN
AGREED TO MAKE
THE TRIP TO SEE
THEM IN EARLY JANUARY.
AT THIS
POINT, I'M
NOT SURE WHAT
ELSE I CAN REASONABLY
GIVE WITHOUT
SACRIFICING MY
RECOVERY OR
MY PEACE OF MIND.
I'M
EXHAUSTED, STILL
HEALING, AND
JUST TRYING TO
PROTECT OUR BABY
AND OURSELVES. AM
I WRONG FOR WANTING
A QUIET CHRISTMAS
AFTER EVERYTHING
WE'VE BEEN THROUGH?