I'M A
TEENAGE GIRL
WHO GENUINELY LOVES
BAKING AND COOKING,
AND OVER
THE PAST FEW
YEARS IT'S
BECOME THE WAY
I SHOW CARE FOR
PEOPLE AROUND ME.
I OFTEN
MAKE TREATS JUST
BECAUSE, OR
HELP PREPARE MEALS
FOR FAMILY GATHERINGS
SINCE I HAVE
MORE FREE TIME
THAN MOST OF
THE ADULTS. EVERYONE
KNOWS THIS
ABOUT ME, AND
IT'S KIND OF BECOME
MY THING,
ESPECIALLY DURING
HOLIDAYS.
THIS YEAR,
I WAS TOLD
THAT CHRISTMAS
WOULDN'T BE SPENT
ALL TOGETHER LIKE
USUAL.
I
WAS DISAPPOINTED,
BUT I ACCEPTED
IT.
A FEW DAYS
LATER, A
RELATIVE CALLED
AND CASUALLY ASKED
WHAT DISHES I
WAS PLANNING TO
MAKE FOR CHRISTMAS
NIGHT.
I WAS
CONFUSED, BECAUSE
NO ONE HAD
MENTIONED A PARTY
TO ME. SHE
EXPLAINED THAT
SHE WAS HOSTING
A GET-TOGETHER
AND THAT MY PARENT
HAD ALREADY TOLD
HER I WOULD BE
COOKING FOR EVERYONE.
I DIDN'T
MIND HELPING AT
FIRST, SINCE
I ENJOY IT
AND THERE WAS STILL
TIME TO PLAN.
BUT THEN
THE CONVERSATION
SHIFTED.
I MENTIONED
GETTING READY
BEFOREHAND, AND
SHE TOLD ME
IT WAS AN ADULTS-ONLY
EVENING.
WHEN
I ASKED
FOR CLARIFICATION,
SHE LISTED
SEVERAL COUSINS
CLOSE TO
MY AGE WHO
WERE INVITED. I
REALIZED I
WAS THE ONLY ONE
EXCLUDED.
THE EXPLANATION
GIVEN WAS
THAT I WAS NOT MATURE
ENOUGH TO ATTEND
LATE EVENTS.
THAT HURT
MORE THAN I EXPECTED.
I FELT
EMBARRASSED AND
USED.
MATURE ENOUGH
TO PROVIDE FREE
FOOD FOR A
CROWD, BUT
NOT MATURE ENOUGH
TO ACTUALLY BE
INCLUDED.
I ENDED
THE CALL AND
SPOKE TO MY PARENT,
WHO DIDN'T
SEE A PROBLEM
WITH THE ARRANGEMENT
AND INSISTED
THE DECISION
WAS FINAL.
WHEN I
SAID I WOULDN'T
COOK IF I WASN'T
WELCOME, THE
ARGUMENT ESCALATED.
I WAS TOLD
I WAS BEING SELFISH,
DRAMATIC,
AND THAT IF
I DIDN'T HELP,
EVERYONE ELSE
WOULD BE INCONVENIENCED.
AT THAT
POINT, I
WAS OVERWHELMED
AND EMOTIONAL.
I SUGGESTED
ALTERNATIVES
LIKE ORDERING
FOOD OR
BUYING READY-MADE
OPTIONS.
BUT THOSE
IDEAS WERE
DISMISSED.
EVENTUALLY, ANOTHER
PARENT OFFERED
FOR ME TO SPEND
CHRISTMAS WITH
THEM INSTEAD. SOMEWHERE
I WOULD ACTUALLY
BE WANTED. I
AGREED, WHICH
MEANT I WOULDN'T
EVEN BE NEARBY
TO HELP ANYMORE.
NOW THE
FAMILY GATHERING
IS APPARENTLY SCRAMBLING
BECAUSE THEY
HAD BEEN COUNTING
ON ME FOR FOOD.
AND I'M
BEING PAINTED
AS THE REASON
THINGS ARE STRESSFUL.
FROM THEIR
PERSPECTIVE, I'M
REFUSING OUT
OF SPITE. FROM
MINE, I
JUST DIDN'T WANT
TO SPEND CHRISTMAS
WORKING FOR
A PARTY I WASN'T
ALLOWED TO ATTEND. SO
WAS I WRONG FOR
SAYING NO?