I WAS
AT COSTCO, WHEN
I REALIZED JUST
AFTER CHECKOUT
THAT I'D ACCIDENTALLY
GRABBED THE
WRONG PRODUCT. ANNOYED
BUT CALM, I
WHEELED MY CART
OVER TO THE CUSTOMER
SERVICE COUNTER
AND TOOK MY
PLACE BEHIND ANOTHER
SHOPPER WHO
WAS
CLEARLY ALREADY
WAITING.
IT WASN'T
BUSY, BUT
IT ALSO WASN'T
EMPTY, AND
I EXPECTED TO
BE THERE FOR A
FEW MINUTES LIKE
EVERYONE ELSE.
WHILE I
WAS STANDING THERE,
A WOMAN
SUDDENLY PUSHED
PAST MY CART,
PHYSICALLY EDGING
IN FRONT OF ME,
AND TOSSED
ME A CASUAL
LITTLE WAVE LIKE
WE WERE OLD FRIENDS.
WITHOUT EVEN APOLOGIZING,
SHE SAID,
I'LL BE SUPER
QUICK, I
DOES HAVE A QUESTION,
AS IF THAT AUTOMATICALLY
GRANTED HER
PRIORITY OVER
EVERYONE ELSE.
SOMETHING IN
ME SNAPPED, I
TOLD HER BLUNTLY
THAT I DIDN'T CARE
HOW QUICK SHE
THOUGHT SHE'D BE
AND THAT SHE NEEDED
TO WAIT. HER
TURN LIKE THE REST
OF US. SHE
IMMEDIATELY LOOKED
OFFENDED, LIKE
I'D COMMITTED SOME
HUGE SOCIAL
CRIME, AND
SHOT BACK THAT
I WAS BEING INCREDIBLY
RUDE AND
AGGRESSIVE.
THAT REACTION
ONLY MADE
ME ANGRIER. I
POINTED OUT
THAT I ALSO HAD
A QUESTION AND
ASKED HER WHAT
EXACTLY MADE
HER SO IMPORTANT
THAT IT JUSTIFIED
CUTTING IN
FRONT OF STRANGERS.
STRANGERS THE
EXCHANGE DREW
A FEW LOOKS
FROM NEARBY CUSTOMERS
AND
SHE SCOFFED
MUTTERED UNDER
HER BREATH AND
STEPPED BACK
CLEARLY
ACTING LIKE
I WAS THE PROBLEM
FOR NOT LETTING
HER GET AWAY WITH
IT BY
THE TIME I
GOT HOME THE
ADRENALINE HAD
WORN OFF
BUT I
WAS STILL IRRITATED
WHEN
I TOLD MY PARTNER
WHAT HAPPENED
SHE
AGREED THE WOMAN
WAS WRONG FOR
CUTTING THE LINE
BUT SAID I ESCALATED
THINGS UNNECESSARILY
AND SHOULDN'T
HAVE SWORN OR
COME IN SO HOT
I GET
THAT I COULD HAVE HANDLED
IT MORE POLITELY
BUT
AT THE SAME TIME
I'M
TIRED OF PEOPLE
ACTING ENTITLED
AND EXPECTING
EVERYONE EVERYONE
ELSE TO JUST
ACCEPT IT QUIETLY.
I DON'T
REGRET STANDING UP
FOR MYSELF, BUT
NOW I'M STUCK
WONDERING WHETHER
THE WAY I DID
IT CROSSED A LINE
AND TURNED ME
INTO THE ASSHOLE.
INSTEAD.