I LIVE
IN A SHARED HOUSE
WHERE I PAY RENT.
ALONG WITH
ANOTHER LONG-TERM
TENANT WHO RENTS
THE LOWER LEVEL,
MY PARTNER
WORKS DEMANDING
OVERNIGHT
SHIFTS AT
A MEDICAL FACILITY,
USUALLY
FROM EARLY
EVENING UNTIL
EARLY MORNING.
AFTER FINISHING
WORK, SHE
WOULD SOMETIMES COME
TO MY PLACE AROUND
SUNRISE TO
SHOWER QUICKLY AND
SLEEP.
IT WAS
NEVER LOUD
OR DRAWN OUT,
JUST A
SHORT RINSE BEFORE
RESTING AFTER
A LONG NIGHT.
ONE MORNING,
THE DOWNSTAIRS
TENANT TOLD
THE HOMEOWNER
THAT THE SOUND
OF THE SHOWER WOKE
HIM UP. THE
MESSAGE WAS
PASSED TO ME
WITH A REQUEST
THAT MY PARTNER
WAKE TO SHOWER
UNTIL EVERYONE
WAS AWAKE.
WHEN I
RELAYED THIS TO
HER, SHE
FELT UNCOMFORTABLE
CONTINUING
TO COME OVER
IN THE MORNINGS.
AFTER WORKING
ALL NIGHT, SHE
DIDN'T WANT TO
FEEL LIKE SHE WAS
INCONVENIENCING
PEOPLE JUST
BY DOING SOMETHING
BASIC.
SO SHE
QUIETLY DECIDED
TO STOP
COMING BY ALTOGETHER.
LATER, WHEN
THE HOMEOWNER FOUND
OUT, SHE
BECAME UPSET,
NOT ABOUT
THE SHOWER ITSELF,
BUT ABOUT
THE FACT THAT
MY PARTNER CHOSE
NOT TO COME
OVER ANYMORE. SHE
INSISTED THAT
WASN'T WHAT SHE
MEANT, BUT
FROM FROM HER PERSPECTIVE,
BEING ASKED
TO AVOID SHOWERING
AFTER AN OVERNIGHT
SHIFT MADE
IT CLEAR THAT
HER PRESENCE WASN'T
WELCOME.
NOW I'M
STUCK IN THE MIDDLE.
I DIDN'T
ARGUE OR ESCALATE
THINGS.
I JUST
PASSED ALONG
THE CONCERN.
AND MY PARTNER
MADE HER OWN
CALM DECISION.
WAS IT
UNREASONABLE FOR
HER TO STEP BACK
AFTER FEELING
LIKE A DISRUPTION?
OR FOR
ME NOT TO PUSH
HARDER AGAINST
THE COMPLAINT IN
THE FIRST PLACE?