I'M HOSTING
CHRISTMAS EVE
AT MY HOME THIS
YEAR, SOMETHING
I'VE DONE FOR
YEARS.
AND MY TRADITION
IS A BIG
DESSERT TABLE
INSTEAD OF
A SINGLE CAKE.
BAKING IS
MY THING, AND
I USUALLY PUT
OUT A WIDE SPREAD
OF HOMEMADE COOKIES
SO EVERYONE
CAN PICK THEIR
FAVORITES.
THIS YEAR
IS A LITTLE DIFFERENT
BECAUSE MY DAUGHTER-IN-LAW
HAS TWO CHILDREN
FROM A PREVIOUS
MARRIAGE.
BOTH UNDER
12, WHO
HAVE A PEANUT ALLERGY.
IT'S NOT
CONTACT-BASED,
BUT IF THEY EAT
PEANUTS THEY
BREAK OUT BADLY
AND SWELL. WELL,
BECAUSE
OF THAT, I
PLANNED AHEAD. I
DECIDED TO
KEEP ANY PEANUT-BASED
COOKIES ON
A SEPARATE TABLE,
CLEARLY LABELED,
AND BAKE THEM
AT DIFFERENT TIMES
TO AVOID CROSS-CONTAMINATION.
EVERYTHING ELSE
WOULD BE COMPLETELY
PEANUT-FREE.
I EXPLAINED
THIS PLAN
TO MY SON,
AND HE WAS
FINE WITH IT.
HE SAID
HE'D REMIND THE
KIDS, WHO
ALREADY MANAGED
THEIR ALLERGIES
AT SCHOOL AND
OTHER EVENTS WITHOUT
ISSUE.
A FEW
DAYS LATER, MY
DAUGHTER-IN-LAW
CALLED AND IMMEDIATELY
SHUT THE
IDEA DOWN.
SHE INSISTED
THERE COULDN'T
BE ANYTHING WITH
PEANUTS IN
THE HOUSE AT ALL
INSTEAD HAVING THOSE
COOKIES
OUT WOULD BE
TEMPTING THE
KIDS I
TOLD HER I
WASN'T COMFORTABLE
SCRAPPING RECIPES
I'VE MADE FOR
YEARS ESPECIALLY
WHEN PRECAUTIONS
WERE ALREADY
IN PLACE AND
OTHER GUESTS ENJOYED
THEM I
SUGGESTED THAT
KEEPING AN EYE
ON THE KIDS
LIKE
THEY DO EVERYWHERE
ELSE WOULD
SOLVE THE PROBLEM
THAT DIDN'T
GO OVER WELL
THE
CALL ESCALATED
QUICKLY AND
SHE ACCUSED ME
OF BEING CARELESS
AND SELFISH
EVEN
CALLING ME
NAMES BEFORE
HANGING UP
LATER
MY
SON REACHED OUT
AND SAID WHILE
HE AGREED THE
SETUP WAS REASONABLE
I
COULD HAVE HANDLED
THE CONVERSATION
WITH MORE
DIPLOMACY NOW
I'M LEFT
FEELING LIKE
WHAT WAS SUPPOSED TO
BE A THOUGHTFUL COMPROMISE
SOMEHOW TURNED
INTO A FAMILY
STANDOFF
RIGHT BEFORE THE
HOLIDAYS.