I'M A WOMAN
IN MY LATE 30S
WITH TWO YOUNG CHILDREN
OF MY OWN.
BOTH STILL
IN GRADE SCHOOL.
AND WE LIVE
VERY CAREFULLY
WITHIN OUR MEANS.
EVERY DOLLAR
IS PLANNED, EVERY
BILL ACCOUNTED FOR.
BY EARLY DECEMBER,
MY PARTNER
AND I HAD ALREADY
STRETCHED OURSELVES
TO MAKE SURE
OUR KIDS' CHRISTMAS
WAS COVERED.
GIFTS WRAPPED
AND TUCKED AWAY.
AROUND THE
SAME TIME,
A CLOSE FAMILY
MEMBER, SOMEONE
I GREW UP
ALONGSIDE, WAS
BARELY SURVIVING
AFTER LOSING
HER SPOUSE
UNEXPECTEDLY JUST
A FEW MONTHS EARLIER.
EARLIER SHE
HAS TWO TODDLERS
AND THE
LOSS SHATTERED
HER ABILITY TO
FUNCTION IN WAYS
I CAN'T EVEN
FULLY DESCRIBE
SINCE
THE DEATH I'VE
DONE EVERYTHING I
COULD TO HOLD THINGS
TOGETHER FOR
HER I
TOOK HER CHILDREN
WITH MINE TO
FALL EVENTS WHEN
SHE COULDN'T GET
OUT OF BED KEPT
THEM FOR WEEKENDS
SO SHE COULD
SLEEP OR CRY
WITHOUT AN AUDIENCE
AND
SHOWED UP WHENEVER
SHE CALLED IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT
WHEN
THE HOLIDAYS
STARTED APPROACHING
SHE
ADMITTED SHE COULDN'T
BRING HERSELF TO
SHOP AT ALL
SO THE
FAMILY QUIETLY
STEPPED IN
I BOUGHT
GIFTS FOR HER
KIDS ON TOP
OF MY OWN
EVEN
THOUGH MONEY WAS
ALREADY TIGHT
BECAUSE
THE IDEA
OF THEM WAKING
UP TO NOTHING
FELT UNBEARABLE
THEN
LIFE HIT MY
HOUSEHOLD TOO
I
WAS INVOLVED IN
A MINOR ACCIDENT
NO
INJURIES THANKFULLY
BUT
THE REPAIR COSTS
WERE BRUTAL
BETWEEN
THAT GROCERIES
AND
RENT WE
WERE SUDDENLY COUNTING
PENNIES JUST
TO STAY AFLOAT
NOT LONG
AFTER SHE
CALLED ME IN
TEARS SAYING
SHE DIDN'T
THINK HER CHILDREN
HAD ENOUGH
FOR CHRISTMAS
MORNING I
TRIED TO EXPLAIN
CALMLY THAT
I HAD TRULY DONE
ALL I COULD THAT
THERE SIMPLY WASN'T
ANY EXTRA MONEY
LEFT.
I EVEN
SUGGESTED ORDERING
A FEW MORE
THINGS ONLINE
TO ARRIVE AFTER
THE HOLIDAY IF
SHOPPING FELT IMPOSSIBLE.
THAT SUGGESTION
UPSET HER
DEEPLY.
SHE INSISTED
THAT ANYTHING
ARRIVING LATE
WOULD RUIN
CHRISTMAS AND
ACCUSED ME OF
NOT UNDERSTANDING
HOW
IMPORTANT THIS
WAS.
THAT CONVERSATION
BROKE SOMETHING
IN ME. I
FELT LIKE ALL
THE NIGHTS, FAVORS,
MONEY, AND
EMOTIONAL LABOR
I'D POURED INTO
HELPING HER SURVIVE
WERE SUDDENLY
INVISIBLE BECAUSE
I COULDN'T
MAGICALLY CREATE
MORE.
OTHER RELATIVES
HAD ALREADY CONTRIBUTED
AS WELL,
BUT SOMEHOW
IT STILL WASN'T
ENOUGH.
I KNOW
GRIEF MAKES
PEOPLE DESPERATE
AND IRRATIONAL, AND
I DON'T BLAME
HER FOR HURTING,
BUT I
ALSO CAN'T
IGNORE HOW SMALL
AND GUILTY SHE
MADE ME FEEL FOR
HAVING LIMITS.
I'M EXHAUSTED,
FINANCIALLY STRAINED,
AND EMOTIONALLY
TORN BETWEEN
COMPASSION AND
RESENTMENT.
I NEVER
PROMISED TO
REPLACE WHAT
SHE LOST, ONLY
TO HELP WHERE
I COULD. AM
I WRONG FOR
FINALLY SAYING
I CAN'T GIVE MORE,
EVEN WHEN
CHILDREN AND
CHRISTMAS ARE
INVOLVED?