THIS SCHOOL
YEAR, A
NEW GIRL, I'LL
CALL HER MARA,
TRANSFERRED INTO
MY DAUGHTER'S
SMALL PRIVATE
ACADEMY, WITH
BARELY A DOZEN
KIDS PER CLASS.
THERE'S NO
ROOM TO FADE
INTO THE BACKGROUND,
AND MARA
MADE AN IMPRESSION
ALMOST IMMEDIATELY.
LESSONS
WERE CONSTANTLY
INTERRUPTED, TEACHERS
WERE STRETCHED
THIN, AND
BY MID-AUTUMN
THERE WAS AN INCIDENT
WHERE LUNCHES
STARTED GOING MISSING.
MY
DAUGHTER WAS ONE
OF THE KIDS AFFECTED.
THERE WERE APOLOGIES,
AWKWARD MEETINGS,
AND SHORTLY
AFTER, A
CAREFULLY WORDED
SCHOOL-WIDE
MESSAGE ABOUT
PERSONAL SPACE
AND KEEPING
HANDS TO YOURSELF.
WHEN
I ASKED WHAT
SPARKED IT,
MY DAUGHTER
ADMITTED MARA
HAD BEEN GRABBING,
HUGGING,
AND CLEANING
TO CLASSMATES
WHO WERE VISIBLY
UNCOMFORTABLE.
THIS ISN'T
KINDERGARTEN, IT'S
THE LAST STRETCH
BEFORE MIDDLE
SCHOOL.
SOCIAL LINES
ARE SHARPER
NOW, AND
MY DAUGHTER HAS
GROWN INCREASINGLY
ANXIOUS AROUND
MARA.
SHE'S
NEVER BEEN UNKIND,
NEVER MOCKED
OR EXCLUDED HER
OUTRIGHT, BUT
SHE DREADS
BEING CORNERED
OR TOUCHED WITHOUT WARNING.
I'VE CROSSED
PATHS WITH
MARA MYSELF
A FEW TIMES,
AND WHILE
I WON'T PRETEND
TO DIAGNOSE ANYTHING
IT'S
CLEAR SHE STRUGGLES
SOCIALLY IN
WAYS THE OTHER
KIDS DON'T
THAT AWARENESS
SITS HEAVY
WITH ME BECAUSE
I KNOW HOW
ISOLATING THAT
CAN BE THEN
THE BIRTHDAY INVITATIONS
WENT OUT
BRIGHT ENVELOPES
HANDED OUT
WITH HOPE MY
DAUGHTER BROUGHT HERS
HOME AND QUIETLY
TOLD ME SHE
DIDN'T WANT TO GO
NORMALLY
THAT
WOULD BE THE END
OF IT SHE'S
OLD ENOUGH TO
DECIDE WHERE
SHE FEELS SAFE
AND COMFORTABLE BUT
AS THE WEEK WENT
ON I
SPOKE TO OTHER
PARENTS THE
ONES WHOSE KIDS
ARE MY DAUGHTER'S
CLOSEST FRIENDS
ONE
BY ONE THEY
ADMITTED THE SAME
THING THEIR
KIDS WORTH GOING
EITHER.
THE PARTY
IS NEXT WEEKEND.
AND UNLESS
SOMETHING CHANGES.
MARA MAY
BE CELEBRATING ALONE.
NOW I'M
TORN IN TWO.
ONE PART
OF ME BELIEVES
FORCING MY
DAUGHTER TO ATTEND
WOULD TEACH HER
A TERRIBLE LESSON.
THAT HER
DISCOMFORT DOESN'T
MATTER.
THAT POLITENESS
SHOULD COME AT THE
EXPENSE OF
HER BOUNDARIES. THE
OTHER PART OF
ME CAN'T SHAKE
THE IMAGE OF
A CHILD WAITING
FOR GUESTS
WHO NEVER ARRIVE.
CANDLES BURNING
DOWN IN SILENCE.
PARENTS SCRAMBLING
TO HIDE THEIR
HEARTBREAK.
I KNOW I
COULD PREVENT THAT
SCENE BY MAKING
MY DAUGHTER GO.
EVEN IF
SHE'S THE ONLY ONE
THERE.
BUT IS
IT KINDNESS TO
SACRIFICE MY
CHILD'S SENSE
OF SAFETY FOR
SOMEONE ELSE'S
FEELINGS?
OR AM
I TEACHING HER
THAT COMPASSION ONLY
COUNTS WHEN
IT COSTS NOTHING?
AND IF
I DO NOTHING AT
ALL, AM
I THE ADULT
WHO ALLOWED A
LONELY CHILD'S
WORST FEAR TO
COME TRUE?