DURING A
BRUTAL WINTER
STORM, MY
CAR SKIDDED
ON UNSEEN ICE
AND SMASHED STRAIGHT
INTO MY NEIGHBOR'S
MAILBOX.
I WAS
HORRIFIED AND
IMMEDIATELY OWNED
UP TO IT, GAVE
HER MY INSURANCE
DETAILS, AND
APOLOGIZED REPEATEDLY.
A FEW DAYS
LATER, SHE
TOLD ME THE INSURANCE
COMPANY WANTED
HER TO PAY OUT
OF POCKET FIRST
AND WAIT FOR
REIMBURSEMENT,
WHICH
SHE CLAIMED SHE
COULDN'T DO. WANTING
TO MAKE THINGS RIGHT
AS QUICKLY AS
POSSIBLE, I
OFFERED TO PERSONALLY
BUY A NEW
MAILBOX AND
PAY SOMEONE I
KNOW TO INSTALL
IT.
EXPLAINING THAT
THERE WOULD BE A SHORT
DELAY BECAUSE
THE MAILBOX WOULDN'T
ARRIVE UNTIL THE
END OF THE
MONTH AND THE INSTALLER
WAS OUT OF
TOWN WITH FAMILY.
WHEN THE
MAILBOX FINALLY
ARRIVED, SHE
CALLED ME WHILE
I WAS DEALING WITH
A MEDICAL EMERGENCY
INVOLVING MY
CHILD THAT LANDED
US IN THE HOSPITAL.
I COULDN'T
ANSWER, BUT
I IMMEDIATELY REACHED
OUT TO THE INSTALLER
AND HAD HIM CONTACT
HER DIRECTLY.
HE CONFIRMED
HE HAD THE MAILBOX
AND SCHEDULED
THE INSTALLATION
FOR EARLY
THE FOLLOWING WEEK.
INSTEAD OF
BEING RELIEVED, SHE
STARTED SENDING
POINTED, SARCASTIC
MESSAGES ACCUSING
ME OF NOT
CARING AT ALL.
I EXPLAINED,
AGAIN, THAT
MY CHILD HAD
BEEN HOSPITALIZED
AND THAT I
HADN'T IGNORED HER.
I'D JUST
BEEN OVERWHELMED
AND STILL
MADE SURE THE
REPAIR WAS SCHEDULED.
THAT'S WHEN HER
TONE ESCALATED.
SHE TOLD
ME I SHOULD BE
ASHAMED, THAT
I WAS DISRESPECTFUL,
AND THAT I
HADN'T APOLOGIZED
ENOUGH.
DESPITE THE
FACT THAT WE'D
ALREADY SPENT HOURS
ON THE PHONE
WHERE I'D TAKEN
FULL RESPONSIBILITY
AND EXPRESSED
HOW SORRY
I WAS WHEN
I FINALLY SAID
THAT IF THE TIMELINE
WASN'T ACCEPTABLE
SHE COULD JUST
PROCEED THROUGH
MY MY
INSURANCE.
SHE COMPLETELY
EXPLODED.
SHE SENT
A LONG MESSAGE
CALLING ME
IMMORAL, INSULTING
MY CHARACTER,
AND MOCKING
ME FOR EVEN
THINKING I
COULD HANDLE THE
REPAIR MYSELF.
AT THAT
POINT, SOMETHING
SNAPPED.
I TOLD HER
I WAS RETURNING
THE MAILBOX.
THAT SHE
SHOULD GO THROUGH
INSURANCE USING
THE INFORMATION
I ALREADY PROVIDED.
AND THAT
I WAS DONE BEING
VERBALLY ABUSED
OVER AN ACCIDENT
I WAS ACTIVELY
TRYING TO
FIX.
THEN I
BLOCKED HER. NOW
I'M LEFT WONDERING
IF I CROSS A
LINE BY PULLING
MY HELP
AT FORCING THE
INSURANCE ROUTE
AFTER.
SHE TURNED
THE SITUATION INTO
A PERSONAL ATTACK.
THANK
YOU.