I'M 29F,
AND THIS YEAR
I HOSTED OUR
FRIEND GROUP'S
ANNUAL AUTUMN
GET -TOGETHER
FOR THE FIRST
TIME.
I PLANNED
THE WHOLE
THING.
DECORATIONS.
MENU.
KIDS'
CORNER.
THE
WORKS.
ONE OF MY
FRIENDS, TESSA,
27F,
HAS TWO SMALL
DOGS SHE
BRINGS
EVERYWHERE.
THEY'RE NOT TRAINED
SUPPORT
ANIMALS.
SHE JUST
INSISTS THEY
GO WHEREVER SHE
GOES.
MOST OF
THE TIME I TOLERATE
IT DURING SHORT
VISITS.
BUT TWO YEARS
AGO AT ANOTHER
FRIEND'S GATHERING,
ONE OF
HER DOGS JUMPED
ONTO THE BUFFET
TABLE.
AND TORE APART THE
ROASTED VEGETABLES
BEFORE ANYONE
HAD
EVEN SAT
DOWN.
PEOPLE LAUGHED
IT
OFF.
I
DIDN'T.
SO WHEN
IT WAS MY HOME
THIS YEAR, I
DECIDED ON
A SIMPLE NO
PETS
RULE.
A FEW DAYS
BEFORE THE
DINNER, I
TEXTED THE GROUP
CONFIRMING THE
TIME AND ADDED,
JUST A
REMINDER, NO
ANIMALS THIS
TIME.
I DIDN'T
MENTION ANYONE
BY
NAME.
TESSA IMMEDIATELY
PRIVATE
MESSAGED ME
ASKING IF
I MEANT HER
DOGS.
I TOLD
HER YES, BECAUSE
I DIDN'T WANT
TO MONITOR PETS
WHILE
COOKING.
DIDN'T WANT
FUR ANYWHERE NEAR
THE
DISHES.
AND WE
ALSO HAVE A
HANDFUL OF TODDLERS
ATTENDING.
PENDING SHE
GOT IRRITATED
RIGHT AWAY
SHE
TOLD ME SHE
CAN'T LEAVE THEM
ALONE AT HOME
AT ALL BECAUSE
THEY GET EMOTIONALLY
DISTRESSED
AND
SHE INSISTED
THEY'RE FAR BETTER
BEHAVED THAN
MOST CHILDREN SHE
SAID I WAS EXCLUDING
PART OF
HER FAMILY
AND THAT IF HER
DOGS WEREN'T
WELCOME NEITHER
WAS SHE
SHE
WAS SUPPOSED TO
BRING A CHICKEN POT
PIE AND APPLE
CRUMBLE SO
I ASKED HOW
SHE'D LIKE ME
TO PICK THEM UP
SHE SAID
SHE WOULDN'T BE
GIVING ME ANYTHING
SINCE I DIDN'T
WANT ALL OF HER
I
TOLD HER I
RESPECTED
HER CHOICE
AND
ENDED UP MAKING
A LAST MINUTE
ROSARY RUN
ACROSS TOWN
NOW
ONE OF OUR MUTUAL
FRIEND SAYS
I WAS BEING TOO
RIGID AND
SHOULD HAVE BEEN MORE
FLEXIBLE
SINCE.
IT'S A SEASONAL
CELEBRATION, BUT
THE WAY I SEE
IT, IT'S
MY HOUSE,
MY KITCHEN,
AND MY RESPONSIBILITY
TO KEEP
THINGS FROM TURNING
INTO CHAOS
AGAIN.
WAS I
WRONG FOR STANDING
MY
GROUND?