MY SON EVAN
WORKS LONG
ROTATIONS
ON INTERNATIONAL
CARGO
VESSELS, WHICH
MEANS HE'S GONE
FOR WEEKS AT
A TIME AND OFTEN
UNREACHABLE.
HE'S MARRIED
TO LENA, AND
TOGETHER THEY
HAVE TWO YOUNG CHILDREN.
THE LAST
COUPLE OF YEARS
HAVE BEEN BRUTAL
FOR THEM. LENA
LOST HER JOB
AND HASN'T BEEN
ABLE TO FIND
ANYTHING THAT
FITS AROUND CHILDCARE
WHILE EVAN
IS AWAY,
AND THE FINANCIAL
PRESSURE HAS
CLEARLY TAKEN
A TOLL ON
THE HOUSEHOLD. OVER
TIME, I
STARTED NOTICING
A PATTERN THAT
MADE MY STOMACH
DROP.
UP.
WHENEVER MONEY
GOT TIGHT,
THE KIDS' BELONGINGS
WOULD QUIETLY
DISAPPEAR.
NOT TOYS
THEY'D OUTGROWN
OR BROKEN THINGS.
BUT NEWER,
EXPENSIVE GIFTS.
A CONSOLE
GAME I BOUGHT
FOR MY GRANDDAUGHTER
WAS SOLD
ONLINE LESS
THAN TWO WEEKS
AFTER SHE OPENED
IT.
SUPPOSEDLY BECAUSE
SHE WAS PLAYING
TOO INTENSELY,
THE LENA COULDN'T
EXPLAIN WHAT
THAT MEANT. WHAT
MADE IT WORSE
WAS SEEING THAT,
DESPITE
THESE SACRIFICES,
LENA STILL
FOUND MONEY
FOR REGULAR PERSONAL
SPLURGES.
WHICH MADE
THE EXPLANATIONS
FEEL HOLLOW.
AS CHRISTMAS
APPROACHED, LENA
ASKED IF
I COULD BUY THE KIDS
TWO TABLETS.
THEY WEREN'T
CHEAP, AND
THE MOMENT SHE
ASKED, I
FELT A KNOT IN
MY CHEST I
IMAGINED THE
KIDS TEARING OPEN
THE WRAPPING PAPER,
THEIR
EXCITEMENT LIGHTING
UP THE ROOM,
ONLY FOR
THOSE TABLETS
TO QUIETLY VANISH
A MONTH LATER
UNDER THE EXCUSE
OF DISCIPLINE,
OR NECESSITY,
I DIDN'T WANT
TO DISAPPOINT THE
KIDS, BUT
I ALSO COULDN'T
STOMACH THE IDEA
OF POURING THAT
MUCH MONEY INTO
SOMETHING I BELIEVED
WOULDN'T
STAY
WITH THEM, SO
I MADE A DECISION
THAT I KNEW MIGHT
CAUSE CONFLICT,
I BOUGHT THE
TABLETS, SET
THEM UP MYSELF,
AND LOCKED THE
SYSTEM SETTINGS
WITH A PASSCODE
ONLY I KNOW,
THE KIDS
CAN USE THEM
FREELY BUT
THEY CAN'T BE WIPED
RESET
OR
SOLD WHEN
I CALLED LENA
TO TELL HER THE
GIFTS WERE BOUGHT
AND EXPLAIN THE
PASSCODE THE
CONVERSATION EXPLODED
ALMOST INSTANTLY
SHE
ACCUSED ME
OF SPYING ON
HER OF
TREATING HER LIKE
A THIEF OF
DELIBERATELY HUMILIATING
HER RIGHT BEFORE
CHRISTMAS
WITHIN
HOURS MY
PHONE WAS BLOWING
UP WITH MESSAGES
SAYING I'D
CROSSED A LINE
UNDERMINED
HER AUTHORITY
AND
POISONED THE
HOLIDAY SPIRIT
NOW
CHRISTMAS IS
DAYS AWAY TENSIONS
ARE SKY HIGH,
AND I'M
LEFT WONDERING
IF PROTECTING
THE KIDS' GIFTS
WAS WORTH TURNING
A FRAGILE FAMILY
SITUATION INTO
AN OUTRIGHT WAR.