I'M REALLY
INTO TABLETOP
MODELING AND
SPENT A LOT OF
MY FREE TIME PRINTING
AND PAINTING FIGURINES.
SO I'VE
SET UP A DEDICATED
WORKSPACE IN
THE BASEMENT OF
OUR HOUSE WITH
SPECIALIZED TOOLS,
PAINTS, AND
EQUIPMENT THAT
I'VE INVESTED A
LOT OF MONEY AND
TIME INTO MAINTAINING.
MY SPOUSE,
LENA, IS
ALSO INTO
ARTS AND CRAFTS.
AND WHILE
I DON'T MIND SHARING
SOME GENERAL
ITEMS, SHE
REGULARLY TAKES
MY SUPPLIES WITHOUT
ASKING AND
NEVER RETURNS
THEM TO WHERE THEY
BELONG.
SHE STRUGGLES
WITH ATTENTION ISSUES
AND ORGANIZATION.
SO I'VE FOUND
MY HIGH-END PAINTS
LEFT OPEN
IN RANDOM ROOMS.
BRUSHES RUINED
IN SINKS.
AND ONCE
EVEN DISCOVERED
MY PRECISION
SPRAY TOOL
COMPLETELY CLOGGED
BECAUSE SHE USED
IT AND WALKED AWAY
WITHOUT CLEANING
IT, LEAVING
ME TO SPEND HOURS
FIXING THE
DAMAGE.
I'VE TRIED
REPEATEDLY TO
TALK TO HER CALMLY
ABOUT PUTTING THINGS
BACK OR AT
LEAST LETTING ME
KNOW WHEN
SHE BORROWS
SOMETHING, BUT
NOTHING EVER CHANGES.
AND SHE ADMITS
SHE GRABS MY
EQUIPMENT BECAUSE
SHE CAN'T KEEP
TRACK OF HER
OWN MATERIALS. AFTER
MONTHS OF FRUSTRATION
AND FEELING
LIKE MY BOUNDARIES
WEREN'T BEING RESPECTED,
I
FINALLY INSTALLED
A LOCK ON THE
CABINET THAT
HOLDS MY PERSONAL
SUPPLIES SO
I COULD AT LEAST RELY
ON
MY THINGS
BEING USABLE
WHEN I NEEDED
THEM.
WHEN SHE
NOTICED, SHE
BECAME FURIOUS
AND ACCUSED ME
OF EXCLUDING HER
AND TREATING OUR
SHARED HOME LIKE
IT WASN'T HERS.
2.
WHILE I ARGUE
THAT I WAS JUST
PROTECTING ITEMS
I PAID FOR
AND MAINTAINED AFTER
EVERY OTHER APPROACH
FAILED, SO
AM I THE ASSHOLE
FOR LOCKING
MY STUFF UP?