DURING
A SHORT SOLO
HOLIDAY
IN MALTA
THIS SPRING,
I BOOKED
AN ALL -INCLUSIVE
RESORT SO
I WOULDN'T HAVE
TO WANDER AROUND
ALONE LOOKING
FOR PLACES
TO
EAT.
THE
DINING HALL
HAD COMMUNAL
TABLES THAT
SAT ABOUT EIGHT
PEOPLE EACH,
WHICH
THE STAFF
SAID HELPED
ENCOURAGE CONVERSATION
AMONG
TRAVELERS.
ONE
EVENING, I
ARRIVED EARLY
AND WAS ENJOYING
A GLASS OF
ROSÉ WHEN
A GROUP OF FOUR,
A
COUPLE AND THEIR
TWO YOUNG NIECES,
WERE PLACED
AT THE SAME
TABLE.
AS SOON
AS THEY SAT
DOWN, THE
WOMAN LEANED
OVER AND
TOLD ME THEY
DIDN'T WANT THE
CHILDREN EXPOSED
TO ADULTS
DRINKING.
I
POLITELY
SUGGESTED THEY
COULD ASK TO
BE MOVED IF
IT MADE THEM
UNCOMFORTABLE.
BUT
I PLANNED TO
FINISH MY
DRINK.
WHEN THEY
NOTICED I
WAS TRAVELING ALONE,
THEY EXCHANGED
COMMENTS
MEANT TO SOUND
SYMPATHETIC
BUT CLEARLY
WEREN'T.
WHEN I
WENT TO GET FOOD,
MY GLASS
VANISHED.
A SERVER
APPROACHED AND
ASKED TO CHECK
MY WRISTBAND
BECAUSE THE
FAMILY CLAIMED
I WAS A MINOR
DINING.
WITHOUT
SUPERVISION,
HE REALIZED
QUICKLY WHAT
HAD HAPPENED,
APOLOGIZED,
AND BROUGHT
ME A FRESH
DRINK JUST
AS THE FAMILY
RETURNED WITH
THEIR
PLATES.
FEELING
BOTH AMUSED
AND IRRITATED AT
HOW FAR THEY
HAD TAKEN
THINGS.
I
ASKED THE SERVER
IF HE COULD
BRING THE FULL
BOTTLE ALONG
WITH TWO SMALL
LIQUOR
POURS.
HE
DID, AND
I CALMLY
TOOK THE DRINKS
AS HE SET
THEM
DOWN.
THE FAMILY
STOOD UP
IMMEDIATELY, GATHERED
THEIR THINGS WITHOUT
A WORD,
AND LEFT
THE DINING HALL
IN A
RUSH.
NOW
I'M WONDERING
WHETHER ORDERING
THE EXTRA DRINKS
WAS EXCESSIVE,
OR SIMPLY
A REASONABLE
RESPONSE
AFTER
BEING TREATED
LIKE A PROBLEM
AT MY OWN
TABLE.