I'M A MAN
IN MY EARLY 20S
WORKING OVERNIGHT
SECURITY AT
A WAREHOUSE RUN
BY A LOGISTICS
COMPANY.
I'LL CALL
STILLWAY FREIGHT.
FROM THE BEGINNING,
I BECAME KNOWN
FOR ALWAYS CARRYING
A BACKPACK STUFFED
WITH USEFUL THINGS.
PAIN RELIEVERS,
GUM, BREATH
SPRAY, BANDAGES,
ALLERGY MEDS,
YOU NAME
IT.
COWORKERS JOKED
THAT I WAS BASICALLY
A WALKING CORNER
STORE.
AND DURING
LONG, QUIET
NIGHT SHIFTS,
IT GAVE PEOPLE
A REASON TO
TALK TO ME INSTEAD
OF JUST STARING
AT LOADING DOCKS
FOR HOURS. EVENTUALLY,
I ADDED
A FEW PERSONAL
CARE ITEMS
THAT PEOPLE ON
NIGHT SHIFT OFTEN
GOT STUCK NEEDING
WHEN NOTHING WAS
OPEN.
PADS, TAMPONS,
A SMALL
DEODORANT
STICK FROM A
BRAND LIKE FRESH
MIST, AND
SOME HAND LOTION
SIMILAR TO
SKINNY'S.
MOST OF
THE WOMEN I WORKED
WITH WERE GRATEFUL
OR PLEASANTLY
SURPRISED.
IT BECAME
ONE OF THOSE
UNSPOKEN THINGS.
IF SOMEONE
WAS IN A BIND
AT 2 AM,
THEY KNEW
WHERE TO GO,
AND NO ONE
MADE A BIG DEAL
OUT OF IT. THAT
CHANGED AFTER
ONE INTERACTION
AT THE GATE.
I WAS
CHECKING PAPERWORK
WITH ANOTHER GUARD
WHEN A CO-WORKER,
I'LL CALL
HER MARA,
DROVE UP
LOOKING FLUSTERED
AND SAID SHE
NEEDED TO LEAVE
EARLY TO BUY
SUPPLIES.
WITHOUT THINKING
MUCH ABOUT IT,
I TOLD
MY CO-WORKER
WHERE IN MY BAG
THE SUPPLIES WERE
AND OFFERED HER OPTIONS.
SHE TOOK
THEM, BARELY
THANKED ME,
AND DROVE OFF.
THE MOMENT
FELT OFF,
BUT I DIDN'T
THINK MUCH OF IT
AND WENT BACK TO
WORK.
THE FOLLOWING
WEEK, I
WAS PULLED INTO
HR AND
TOLD A COMPLAINT
HAD BEEN FILED
SAYING I MADE
A FEMALE CO-WORKER
FEEL UNCOMFORTABLE
AND
UNSAFE, HEARING
THAT MADE MY
STOMACH DROP.
HR
REVIEWED THE
CAMERA FOOTAGE,
LISTENED TO
MY EXPLANATION,
AND ULTIMATELY
SAID I
HADN'T DONE ANYTHING
WRONG, BUT
ADVISED ME TO
KEEP MY DISTANCE
FROM MARA.
EVEN SO,
WORD SPREAD
FAST BY
THE NEXT FEW
SHIFTS.
PEOPLE WERE
WHISPERING, SIDE-EYEING
ME, AND
I COULD TELL A
STORY WAS CIRCULATING
THAT I WAS
WEIRD, OR
CREEPY.
THAT WORD
HAS FOLLOWED
ME, MOST
OF MY LIFE
BECAUSE OF HOW
I LOOK, AND
IT HIT HARDER
THAN I EXPECTED.
SO I
MADE A DECISION.
IF CARRYING
THOSE ITEMS
COULD BE TWISTED
INTO SOMETHING INAPPROPRIATE,
I WAS DONE.
I REMOVED
ALL THE PERSONAL
CARE PRODUCTS
FROM MY BAG
AND LEFT THEM WITH
HR.
WHEN CO-WORKERS
NOTICED AND
ASKED WHY I
STOPPED, I
DIDN'T SUGARCOAT
IT.
I TOLD THEM
EXACTLY WHAT
HAPPENED AND
SAID THEY WERE FREE
TO CONFIRM IT
WITH MANAGEMENT IF
THEY WANTED.
THE ATMOSPHERE
SHIFTED ALMOST
IMMEDIATELY.
PEOPLE WERE
ANGRY, NOT
AT ME, BUT
AT MARA. SHE
BECAME DISTANT,
AVOIDED, AND
OPENLY UPSET,
EVENTUALLY CONFRONTING
ME AND
SAYING I HAD TURNED
EVERYONE AGAINST
HER AND MADE
WORK UNBEARABLE.
SHE SAID
I SHOULD HAVE KEPT
QUIET AND
LET IT BLOW OVER.
I
TOLD HER I
WASN'T WILLING TO
SILENTLY CARRY
A LABEL THAT
COULD FOLLOW ME
FOR YEARS JUST
TO PROTECT
SOMEONE ELSE'S
COMFORT.
NOW THE
WORKPLACE FEELS
TENSE AND
I'M LEFT
WONDERING WHETHER
BEING HONEST
WAS NECESSARY
SELF-DEFENSE
OR
WHETHER TELLING
THE FULL STORY
CAUSED DAMAGE
THAT CAN'T BE UNDONE.