I
SHARE A FLAT
IN BRIGHTON
WITH THREE OTHER
RENTERS.
AND
EACH BEDROOM
IS PAIRED WITH
ITS OWN
BATHROOM.
SINCE
THE FOURTH ROOM
IS EMPTY THIS
YEAR, THE
BATHROOM BESIDE
MY ROOM
IS ASSIGNED SOLELY
TO
ME.
UNFORTUNATELY,
MY NEWEST
FLATMATE
AND HER PARTNER
SEEM TO THINK
THAT ASSIGNED
SIMPLY
MEANS FREE
FOR ANYONE WHO
WANDERS
BY.
THEY USE
IT CONSTANTLY,
NEVER TOUCH
THE SOAP,
AND LEAVE
THE EXTRACTOR
FAN RUNNING
FOR
DAYS.
THE
FAN DOESN'T
HAVE A TIMER,
OVERHEATS
EASILY, AND
OUR LETTING
AGENT WARNED
US MONTHS AGO
THAT IT'S A GENUINE
FIRE RISK
WHEN LEFT ON
TOO
LONG.
EVERY
TIME I'VE
CONTACTED HER,
IT'S BEEN
ABOUT SOMETHING
HAZARDOUS
OR INCONSIDERATE,
TUCKING
LOUDLY BENEATH
MY WINDOW
AT 1AM,
TURNING
THE RADIATORS
UP TO THE MID
-THIRTIES, LEAVING
THE DRYER
FULL OF
LINT, OR
LETTING CIGARETTE
SMOKE DRIFT
THROUGH THE
CORRIDOR.
I DIDN'T
WANT TO NAG,
BUT SHE
LEFT ME NO
CHOICE.
BEFORE
LEAVING FOR
A TWO -WEEK
WINTER BREAK,
I TAPED
A SMALL NOTE
TO THE MIRROR
REMINDING HER
TO PLEASE TURN
THE FAN OFF
AND WASH HER
HANDS IF
SHE
USED THE
BATHROOM AT
DAWN THE
NEXT MORNING
SHE
SWISHED EVERYTHING
OFF ONLY
TO TURN
THE FAN BACK
ON IMMEDIATELY
AFTERWARD
WITHOUT TOUCHING
THE SINK
THAT
WAS THE MOMENT
I DECIDED
I WASN'T
LEAVING ANY
OF MY BELONGINGS
WITHIN REACH
WHILE I WAS
AWAY SO
I PACKED UP
EVERYTHING SKINCARE
TOWELS
CLEANING
SPRAYS
AND YES
THE
TOILET PAPER
IT'S
MY BATHROOM
STOCKED
WITH MY SUPPLIES
AND
I WASN'T
GOING TO PAY FOR
HER AND HER BOYFRIEND
TO BURN
THROUGH EVERYTHING
WHILE IGNORING
THE MOST
BASIC
HYGIENE.
A FEW
HOURS AFTER
MY TRAIN
LEFT THE STATION,
MY PHONE
LIT UP WITH
FRANTIC
MESSAGES.
APPARENTLY
THEY HAD
WALKED INTO
MY BATHROOM,
FOUND
THE EMPTY HOLDER,
AND
SPIRALED.
THEY ACCUSED
ME OF BEING
CHILDISH,
OF MAKING
THE FLAT
UNCOMFORTABLE, AND
OF ACTING LIKE
I OWN THE
PLACE.
THE
IRONY?
THAT BATHROOM
ACTUALLY IS
A SIGN TO
ME.
THEY WERE
NEVER SUPPOSED
TO BE USING
IT AT
ALL.
NOW
THEY'RE STOMPING
AROUND TELLING
OUR OTHER FLATMATE
THAT I'VE SABOTAGED
THE SHARED
ATMOSPHERE.
WHILE
I'M SITTING HERE
WONDERING IF
I SIMPLY PROTECTED
MY SPACE
FROM TWO
PEOPLE WHO
WERE NEVER ENTITLED
TO IT
IN THE FIRST
PLACE.
SO WAS
I WRONG TO
CLEAR OUT MY
OWN BATHROOM
BEFORE LEAVING
OR IS THIS
JUST THE REACTION
OF TWO
PEOPLE
WHO LOST ACCESS
TO SOMETHING
THEY SHOULD NEVER
HAVE BEEN
USING?