I'M 24
AND RECENTLY
STARTED MY
FIRST FULL -TIME
JOB.
OUR TEAM
HAS A VOLUNTARY
SUNSHINE POT
WHERE EVERYONE
CHIPS IN
A LITTLE EACH MONTH
FOR THINGS LIKE
FAREWELL
CUPCAKES, SMALL
CELEBRATIONS,
OR THE OCCASIONAL
TREAT.
IT SOUNDED HARMLESS
ENOUGH, SO
I AGREED TO
JOIN WHEN MY
CO -WORKER PRIYA
ASKED.
SHE'S THE
ONE WHO COLLECTS
THE MONEY AND
BUYS THINGS FOR
THE
GROUP.
ABOUT A
MONTH IN, I
ASKED IF SHE
COULD SEND ME
A SIMPLE SUMMARY
OF WHAT HAD BEEN
COVERED WITH THE
FUND SO
FAR.
NOT
BECAUSE I SUSPECTED
ANYTHING JUST
BECAUSE I'M TRYING
TO TRACK MY
SPENDING BETTER
AND
I GREW UP BEING
TOLD TO PAY ATTENTION
TO WHERE MY
MONEY GOES SHE
SAID SHE'D SEND
IT LATER SHE
DIDN'T A
FEW DAYS LATER
INSTEAD
OF THE SUMMARY
SHE
MESSAGED ME
REMINDING ME
MY NEXT CONTRIBUTION
WAS DUE
I
REPLIED ASKING
AGAIN FOR
THE BREAKDOWN NO
ANSWER I
SENT A FOLLOW
-UP THE NEXT DAY
STILL
NOTHING SHE
WAS ACTIVE IN
OUR WORK CHAT
TALKING ABOUT
WEEKEND PLANS
AND PROJECT UPDATES
JUST
IGNORING ANYTHING
I ASKED ABOUT
THE
FUND.
LAST WEEK
SHE CAME OVER
TO MY DESK,
SMILING,
AND SAID,
HEY, JUST
NEED YOUR MONTHLY
CONTRIBUTION.
I CALMLY
TOLD HER I'D
BE HAPPY TO
SEND IT AS SOON
AS SHE LET ME
KNOW WHAT THE FUND
HAD PAID FOR SO
FAR.
HER EXPRESSION
CHANGED
IMMEDIATELY.
SHE SAID
I WAS MAKING THIS
WAY TOO FORMAL
AND THAT EVERYONE
ELSE WAS FINE
WITHOUT A DETAILED
LIST.
I TRIED
TO EXPLAIN I
WASN'T ACCUSING HER
OF
ANYTHING.
I JUST
NEEDED IT FOR
MY OWN
BUDGETING.
BUT SHE
INTERRUPTED ME
AND WALKED
OFF.
NOW TWO
CO -WORKERS
HAVE HINTED
THAT I'M BEING DRAMATIC
AND CREATING
EXTRA
HASSLE.
ONCE SAID
I SHOULD
JUST TRUST
PRIYA AND STOP
NITPICKING.
I'M STARTING
TO FEEL AWKWARD
ABOUT THE WHOLE
THING, BUT
I STILL FEEL
LIKE ASKING WHERE
MY OWN MONEY
IS GOING IS
REASONABLE.
SO WAS
I WRONG FOR
REFUSING TO
KEEP CONTRIBUTING
UNTIL SHE
SHOWS ME WHAT
THE FUND IS ACTUALLY
BEING USED
FOR?