I'M 28
AND WAS DIAGNOSED
WITH NARCISSISTIC
PERSONALITY DISORDER
AT 16.
SOMETHING
I'VE WORKED ON
IN THERAPY FOR
YEARS BUT CHOICE.
I WAS NOT
A GOOD PERSON
IN HIGH SCHOOL.
I'VE OWNED
THAT, APOLOGIZED
WHERE I
COULD, AND
I ACTIVELY WORK
ON CORRECTING HARMFUL
BEHAVIOR.
I RECENTLY
JOINED A
NEW, SMALL
FRIEND GROUP,
AND AFTER
I FELT SAFE
ENOUGH TO SHARE
MY DIAGNOSIS,
ONE
FRIEND, RIA,
STARTED QUESTIONING
NEARLY EVERYTHING
I SAID. IT
WASN'T SUBTLE,
IF I EMPATHIZE
WITH AN UPSET FRIEND.
END.
SHE'D ASK
IF I GENUINELY
CARED OR
WAS PERFORMING EMPATHY.
IF I
COMPLIMENTED
HER OUTFIT, SHE'D
ASK IF IT WAS
MY REAL OPINION
OR IF I WAS
SCORING POINTS.
WHEN I
CONGRATULATED
HER ON A PROMOTION,
SHE ASKED
IF I WAS IMPLYING
SHE HADN'T BEEN
CONFIDENT BEFORE.
ALMOST EVERY
INTERACTION ENDED
WITH SOME VERSION
OF, IS
THAT YOU TALKING,
OR THE DISORDER?
I ASKED
HER TO STOP.
OTHER FRIENDS
ASKED HER TO
STOP.
SHE DISMISSED
IT AS JUST
CHECKING, WHILE
I WAS LEFT OVER
ANALYZING EVERY
SENTENCE I
SPOKE.
THE FINAL
STRAW CAME DURING
A PREGAME AT
MY PLACE WHEN
SOMEONE CANCELLED
PLANS LAST MINUTE
AND I SAID
I FELT FRUSTRATED
BECAUSE IT
HAPPENS OFTEN
AND FEELS DISRESPECTFUL.
RHEA IMMEDIATELY
SAID, BUT
ARE YOU REASONABLY
UPSET?
OR IS THE
DISORDER FEELING
ENTITLED TO
OTHER PEOPLE'S
TIME?
I SNAPPED. I
TOLD HER THAT
I ALREADY QUESTION
MYSELF CONSTANTLY
TO AVOID HURTING
PEOPLE.
THAT I
WASN'T A CASE
STUDY.
AND THAT SHE
WAS TAKING YEARS
OF WORK AND
THROWING IT IN MY
FACE.
I ASKED
HER WHY SHE EVEN
WANTED TO BE AROUND
ME IF SHE BELIEVED
EVERY WORD I
SAID WAS MANIPULATION.
SHE RESPONDED
THAT MY REACTION
PROVED HER
POINT AND THAT
I WASN'T AS HEALED
AS I THOUGHT. THE
NIGHT ENDED AWKWARDLY.
THE GROUP IS
NOW SPLIT. AND
SOME PEOPLE THINK
I SHOULD SIMPLY
ACCEPT EXTRA
SCRUTINY BECAUSE
OF MY DIAGNOSIS.
EVEN
THOUGH I'VE ALREADY
SPENT YEARS
HOLDING MYSELF
ACCOUNTABLE.