AFTER A
LONG, EXHAUSTING
SHIFT, I
FINALLY GOT HOME
TO OUR SMALL,
DRAFTY
APARTMENT IN
A COLD MOUNTAIN
TOWN AND TOLD
MY PARTNER, EVAN,
THAT I WAS
GOING TO TAKE A
QUICK SHOWER BEFORE
WE SETTLED IN
FOR THE NIGHT. THE
HOUSE WAS FREEZING
BECAUSE THE OLD
HEATER HADN'T
BEEN TURNED ON YET.
AND I
WAS LOOKING FORWARD
TO THOSE FEW
WARM MINUTES MORE
THAN ANYTHING. I
BARELY HAD TIME
TO RINSE BEFORE
I HAD SHAMPOO
WORKED INTO MY
HAIR WHEN THE
BATHROOM DOOR SUDDENLY
FLEW
OPEN.
EVAN STOOD
THERE PANICKED,
APOLOGIZING
OVER AND OVER,
SAYING HE
NEEDED THE BATHROOM
IMMEDIATELY AND
THAT IT WASN'T OPTIONAL.
I TRIED
TO LAUGH IT OFF
AT FIRST AND
TOLD HIM I JUST
CLOSED THE CURTAIN
AND HE COULD USE
THE TOILET. BUT
HIS TONE CHANGED
FAST HE
INSISTED I
HAD TO GET OUT
RIGHT NOW. ACTING
LIKE I WAS BEING
UNREASONABLE FOR
EVEN SUGGESTING
OTHERWISE.
FOR CONTEXT,
WE'VE LIVED
TOGETHER FOR
OVER TWO YEARS
AND ARE GENERALLY
COMFORTABLE WITH
EACH OTHER. BUT
WE STILL HAVE
BOUNDARIES.
THIS BEING
A BIG ONE, EVAN
HAS A DIGESTIVE
CONDITION THAT
MAKES BATHROOM EMERGENCIES
SUDDEN AND
INTENSE.
SO I
UNDERSTAND THAT
WHEN HE HAS TO
GO, IT'S
URGENT.
STILL, WHAT
BOTHERED ME
WAS HOW NON-NEGOTIABLE
IT BECAME. I
ENDED UP STEPPING
OUT OF THE SHOWER
MID-WASH, WATER
DRIPPING OFF
ME, SHAMPOO
STILL IN MY
HAIR, FREEZING
IN THE HALLWAY
WHILE HE LOCKED
THE BATHROOM DOOR
BEHIND HIM.
I STOOD
THERE SHIVERING,
BAREFOOT
ON COLD FLOORS,
FEELING RIDICULOUS
AND STRANGELY
EMBARRASSED, WAITING
FOR HIM TO FINISH
WHILE MY HAIR
DRIED STIFF
AND SOAPY.
IT WASN'T
A MASSIVE CRISIS
IN THE GRAND
SCHEME OF THINGS,
BUT THE
LONGER I STOOD
THERE, THE
MORE IT SANK
IN HOW UNCOMFORTABLE
AND UNNECESSARY
IT FELT.
I COULDN'T
SHAKE THE FEELING
THAT I'D BEEN TREATED
LIKE AN INCONVENIENCE
INSTEAD OF A
PARTNER.
ESPECIALLY WHEN
THERE WERE OTHER WAYS
THE SITUATION
COULD HAVE BEEN
HANDLED WITH A
LITTLE MORE CONSIDERATION.
I KEEP
REPLAYING
IT IN MY HEAD
AND WONDERING IF
I'M OVERREACTING.
OR IF
IT REALLY WAS AN
UNREASONABLE THING
TO ASK SOMEONE
YOU LIVE WITH TO
ABANDON A SHOWER
LIKE THAT
JUST SO YOU CAN
USE THE TOILET.