AFTER OUR
MOTHER DIED NEARLY
SIX YEARS
AGO, OUR
FAMILY FROZE
IN THAT MOMENT,
ESPECIALLY
MY YOUNGER
SISTER, MARA,
WHO WAS STILL
IN HIGH SCHOOL
WHILE I WAS ALREADY
LIVING ON MY
OWN.
OUR FATHER,
DANIEL, CENTERED
HIS ENTIRE LIFE
AROUND PROTECTING
HER PAIN.
EVEN YEARS
LATER, EVERY
TIME HE TRIED
TO DATE, MARA
WOULD SPIRAL, CRYING,
ACCUSING HIM
OF ERASING OUR
MOM, BEGGING
HIM TO STOP,
AND EACH TIME,
HE DID. IT,
RECENTLY, DANIEL
BEGAN SEEING
A WOMAN NAMED
CLAIRE, A
DIVORCED TEACHER
WITH TWO SONS,
AND FOR
THE FIRST TIME
HE SEEMED GENUINELY
ALIVE AGAIN,
WHEN HE SUGGESTED
SPENDING THE
HOLIDAYS TOGETHER,
MARA SHUT IT
DOWN, CLAIMING
THE HOUSE
WAS HER SAFE
PLACE AND
FULL OF MEMORIES
THAT COULDN'T
BE SHARED, THEN
I LEARNED, THROUGH
A FAMILY CHAT,
THAT SHE PLANNED
TO MOVE BACK IN
AFTER COLLEGE,
A PLAN
SHE'D NEVER MENTIONED
UNTIL CLAIRE
ENTERED THE PICTURE,
FRUSTRATED
AND EXHAUSTED,
I ACCUSE HER
OF USING OUR
MOTHER'S DEATH
TO CONTROL HIM
AND ACTING AS
IF SHE WERE THE ONLY
ONE WHO WHO
LOST
HER WHILE
THE REST OF US
WERE EXPECTED TO
STAY FROZEN FOREVER.
DANIEL TOLD
ME TO STOP.
MARA LEFT
THE CHAT, AND
LATER I WAS
LABELED HEARTLESS
FOR ATTACKING
HER GRIEF.
NOW MY
FATHER WANTS
ME TO APOLOGIZE,
BUT IT
FEELS LIKE ONCE
AGAIN, HIS
HAPPINESS IS
BEING SACRIFICED,
AND I'M
THE ONLY ONE
WILLING TO SAY
IT OUT LOUD.