MY GIRLFRIEND
BARELY SHOWERS.
MAYBE ONCE
A WEEK, TWICE
IF I'M LUCKY.
WE GO TO
THE GYM TOGETHER.
AND I
CAN ALWAYS TELL
SHE SWEATS.
BUT SHE
INSISTS SHE
DOESN'T.
I'VE TRIED
TO IGNORE IT
AT FIRST. BUT
THE SMELL IS AFFECTING
OUR INTIMACY.
I USED
TO LOVE BEING CLOSE
TO HER. BUT
NOW I AVOID
GETTING PHYSICALLY
AFFECTIONATE
BECAUSE IT'S JUST
OVERWHELMING.
I'VE TRIED
DROPPING HINTS.
LIKE SUGGESTING
WE SHOWER
TOGETHER.
BUT SHE REFUSES.
SAYING THERE'S
ONLY ROOM FOR
ONE IN THE SHOWER.
ONE NIGHT,
SHE INVITED
ME TO LIE DOWN
NEXT TO HER
ON THE FLOOR AND
TALK ABOUT TRAVEL
PLANS.
I LASTED
LESS THAN A
MINUTE BEFORE MAKING
AN EXCUSE TO
LEAVE BECAUSE I
COULDN'T HANDLE BEING
THAT CLOSE
WITHOUT GAGGING
SLIGHTLY.
AFTER MONTHS
OF AWKWARD
HINTS AND FRUSTRATION,
I FINALLY
TOLD HER DIRECTLY,
I KNOW
YOU SAY YOU DON'T
SWEAT, BUT
I CAN SMELL IT.
I'D REALLY
APPRECIATE IT
IF YOU SHOWERED
MORE OFTEN. SHE
COMPLETELY LOST
IT, ACCUSING
ME OF THINKING
SHE'S DISGUSTING
AND SAYING I
WAS ATTACKING HER.
NOW OUR
RELATIONSHIP FEELS
STRAINED,
AND I'M UNSURE
HOW TO FIX
IT.
AM I
WRONG FOR EXPECTING
A PARTNER TO
PRACTICE BASIC
HYGIENE AND
TAKE CARE OF THEMSELVES?