I'M
A 27-YEAR-OLD
GUY, AND
MY YOUNGER BROTHER,
WHO'S 24,
RUNS A
SMALL CAFE
THAT SPECIALIZES
IN CUSTOM DESSERTS
FOR EVENTS.
LATELY,
HE'S BEEN OVERWHELMED
BECAUSE TWO
STAFF MEMBERS
QUIT RIGHT BEFORE
PEAK WEDDING
SEASON.
TO HELP
HIM STAY AFLOAT,
I OFFERED
TO PREP SOME
FILLINGS AT
HOME, THINGS
LIKE PASTRY
CREAM AND
FRUIT PRESERVES,
AND BRING
THEM OVER SO
HE COULD FOCUS
ON ASSEMBLING
AND DECORATING
CAKES FOR
PAYING CLIENTS.
THE
PROBLEM IS MY
PARTNER, WHO'S
25, EVERY
SINGLE TIME I'VE
MADE THESE FILLINGS.
SHE'S DIPPED
HER BARE FINGERS
STRAIGHT INTO
THE CONTAINERS TO
TASTE THEM.
NOT ONCE
OR TWICE, BUT
REPEATEDLY.
EACH TIME
IT HAPPENS, THE
ENTIRE BATCH
BECOMES UNUSABLE,
WHICH MEANS
I HAVE TO THROW
IT OUT AND START
OVER.
I'VE EXPLAINED
CALMLY THAT
THIS FOOD IS
FOR CUSTOMERS,
NOT OUR
KITCHEN TABLE,
AND THAT IF SHE
REALLY WANTS A
TASTE, SHE
CAN USE A CLEAN
SPOON AND
TAKE SOME FROM THE
SIDE.
SHE BRUSHES
IT OFF, SAYS
USING HER
FINGERS FEELS
NOSTALGIC, AND
SULKS LIKE I'M
RUINING SOMETHING
SENTIMENTAL FOR
HER.
EARLIER TODAY,
THINGS CAME
TO A HEAD.
I WAS
RUSHING TO FINISH
A CHOCOLATE CUSTARD
BECAUSE MY
BROTHER WAS LATE
ON A LARGE WEDDING
ORDER AND
STRESSED OUT
OF HIS MIND
BEFORE
I JUMPED IN
THE SHOWER. I
EXPLICITLY TOLD
MY PARTNER
NOT TO TOUCH
IT AND
IF SHE ABSOLUTELY
COULDN'T RESIST
TO
PLEASE USE A
UTENSIL.
WHEN I
CAME BACK,
I SAW HER
STANDING AT
THE COUNTER WITH
HER FINGERS IN
THE BOWL AGAIN. LICKING
THEM LIKE NOTHING
I'D SAID MATTERED.
I SNAPPED.
AFTER THE
FIFTH RUINED BASH,
I LOST
MY TEMPER
AND YELLED FOR
HER TO STOP EATING
THE FOOD I WAS
MAKING BECAUSE
IT WASN'T
FOR HER AND SHE
WAS RUINING SOMETHING
MEANT FOR OTHER
PEOPLE.
SHE
IMMEDIATELY
BURST INTO
TEARS AND
ACCUSED ME OF
SHAMING HER AND
ATTACKING HER
EVEN
THOUGH I NEVER MENTIONED
HER BODY OR
EATING HABITS ONLY
THE FACT THAT
SHE WAS CONTAMINATING
FOOD THAT WASN'T
HERS TO TOUCH
I
KNOW I RAISED
MY VOICE AND
I HATE THAT IT
ESCALATED LIKE
THAT BUT
I ALSO FEEL
LIKE MY BOUNDARIES
AND THE PRESSURE
I WAS UNDER
WERE COMPLETELY IGNORED
WAS I
WRONG FOR REACTING
THE WAY I DID
AFTER BEING PUSHED
OVER THE SAME
LINE AGAIN AND
AGAIN