I WAS
RELAXING IN
THE LIVING ROOM ONE
EVENING, WATCHING
A SERIES, WHEN
MY 15-YEAR-OLD
NIECE, WHO
LIVES WITH ME,
CAME IN AND
ASKED WHAT I WAS
WATCHING.
SHE IMMEDIATELY
LIT UP AND
TOLD ME SHE
HAD A SHOW I
HAD TO SEE, SAYING
THE OPENING SCENES
WERE SOME OF
THE BEST TELEVISION
EVER MADE.
I AGREED
TO GIVE IT A
TRY AND STARTED
QUEUING IT UP.
AND WHILE
IT PLAYED, SHE
STAYED RIGHT THERE,
EXCITEDLY
TALKING THROUGH EVERY
MOMENT, POINTING
OUT DETAILS,
EXPLAINING
CHARACTERS,
AND TELLING
ME WHY EACH SCENE
MATTERED.
BY
THE TIME WE
FINISHED THE OPENING
SHE
ASKED ME TO
PAUSE IT AND WANTED
TO KNOW WHAT I THOUGHT
I
HESITATED AND
SAID I DIDN'T
REALLY HAVE ANY
ORIGINAL THOUGHTS
YET BECAUSE
I HADN'T
HAD A CHANCE TO
JUST WATCH AND
PROCESS IT ON
MY OWN I
EXPLAINED THAT
HEARING EVERYTHING
IN ADVANCE MADE
IT HARD FOR ME
TO FORM MY OWN
REACTION SHE
IMMEDIATELY GOT
UPSET STOOD
UP AND
WALKED DOWN THE
HALLWAY SAYING
I COULD HAVE AT
LEAST PRETENDED TO
CARE I
TOLD HER THAT
I GENUINELY WANTED
TO CARE AND
THAT I PROBABLY WOULD
HAVE ENJOYED IT
EVEN MORE IF
I'D
BEEN ABLE TO EXPERIENCE
IT QUIETLY
QUIETLY FIRST SHE
SHUT HERSELF IN
HER ROOM AFTER
THAT.
AND THE
WHOLE HOUSE FELT
TENSE.
I WASN'T
TRYING TO DISMISS
HER OR HER
INTERESTS.
BUT NOW
I'M WONDERING IF
I HANDLED THE
MOMENT BADLY
AND HURT HER
FEELINGS MORE
THAN I REALIZED.