I'M
A WOMAN IN MY
LATE 20S,
AND FOR
OVER A DECADE
MY CLOSEST
FRIEND, LENA,
AND I WERE INSEPARABLE
IN EVERY SENSE.
DAILY
CALLS, SHARED
ROUTINES, HOLIDAYS
TOGETHER, CONSTANT
PLANS, THE
KIND OF BOND
EVERYONE CHOKED
WITHOUT LAST
MARRIAGES.
ABOUT HALF
A YEAR AGO, LENA
STARTED DATING
EVAN, AND
AT FIRST I WAS
GENUINELY EXCITED
FOR HER.
FULLY
EXPECTING SOME
SCHEDULE SHIFTS
BECAUSE OF
THE HONEYMOON PHASE.
I
DIDN'T COMPLAIN
WHEN SHE BEGAN
CANCELING ON
ME EVEN
WHEN IT HAPPENED
REPEATEDLY
AND ALWAYS
AT THE LAST MINUTE
BUT AFTER
MONTHS OF
BEING PUSHED ASIDE,
I FINALLY TOLD
HER GENTLY
THAT
IT HURT TO FEEL
LIKE I WAS NO
LONGER A PRIORITY
SHE APOLOGIZED
AND PROMISED
TO DO BETTER
AND
FOR A BRIEF
STRETCH IT
SEEMED LIKE THINGS
WERE IMPROVING
UNTIL
I SAW ONLINE
THAT SHE'D
GONE TO A TASTING
EVENT THE SAME
WEEKEND SHE
TOLD ME SHE
WAS TOO OVERWHELMED
TO COME TO A
DINNER WE PLANNED
WEEKS EARLIER
I
TRIED TO KEEP
THINGS LIGHT WHEN
I MENTIONED IT,
BUT SHE
IGNORED ME FOR
DAYS AND BRUSHED
IT OFF WITH A
VAGUE EXPLANATION
NATION.
I SWALLOWED
MY FEELINGS
AGAIN, NOT
WANTING TO SEEM
NEEDY, UNTIL
I LEARNED FROM
SOMEONE ELSE
THAT SHE WAS PLANNING
A BIRTHDAY GATHERING
AND I WASN'T
INVITED.
DESPITE NEVER
MISSING ONE
IN ALL THE YEARS
WE'D BEEN FRIENDS.
WHEN I
FINALLY ASKED
HER OUTRIGHT IF
I'D DONE SOMETHING
WRONG OR
IF SHE WAS UPSET
WITH ME. SHE
TOLD ME SHE
NEEDED DISTANCE
AND SAID I'D
BEEN TOO INTENSE,
WHICH FELT LIKE
A SLAP AFTER
ALL.
THE PATIENCE
AND RESTRAINT I'D
SHOWN.
I ASKED
FOR CLARITY, SHE
SHUT THE CONVERSATION
DOWN.
WENT SILENT
FOR NEARLY TWO
WEEKS.
AND WHEN I
SENT ONE LAST
MESSAGE SAYING
I LOVED HER
AND AND WANTED TO UNDERSTAND
WHAT HAPPENED.
SHE BLOCKED
ME ENTIRELY.
I'M GRIEVING
SOMEONE WHO'S
STILL ALIVE. REPLAYING
EVERY INTERACTION
TO FIGURE
OUT WHAT I DID
WRONG.
AND WONDERING
IF ASKING FOR
HONESTY FROM
THE PERSON WHO
ONCE CALLED ME
FAMILY REALLY
MAKES ME THE
VILLAIN
HERE.