I RECENTLY
STARTED A
JOB WHERE THE
SCHEDULE RUNS
10 DAYS ON
AND 10 DAYS
OFF.
IT WAS
MY FIRST FULL
STRETCH.
AND SINCE
I LIVE ABOUT
AN HOUR AND A
HALF FROM THE
SITE.
I ALWAYS
DRIVE
IN.
A LOT OF
THE OTHERS COME
FROM DIFFERENT PARTS
OF ANOTHER
COUNTRY.
SO MOST
OF THEM
FLY.
ABOUT HALFWAY
THROUGH THE
SHIFT.
A GUY
I'D NEVER MET
BEFORE JOINED
OUR
TEAM.
HE WAS A
CONSTANT
SMOKER.
ALWAYS STEPPING
OUT FOR
CIGARETTES.
WHEN OUR
ROTATION WRAPPED
UP.
SOMEONE ASKED
IF I COULD TAKE
HIM TO THE AIRPORT
BECAUSE HE
KNEW I HAD MY
CAR WITH
ME.
I
TOLD THEM I
COULDN'T AND
THEN I LEFT
WHAT I
DIDN'T SAY WAS
THAT I DIDN'T WANT
MY CAR TO END
UP SMELLING LIKE
SMOKE AND
I ALSO DIDN'T
WANT TO BECOME THE
PERSON EVERYONE
AUTOMATICALLY RELIES
ON FOR AIRPORT
RIDES EVERY
TIME WE FINISH
A SHIFT NOW,
I'VE HEARD PEOPLE
ARE TALKING ABOUT
IT AND
APPARENTLY HE'S
ANNOYED WITH ME
FOR NOT TAKING
HIM I
STILL BELIEVE
I HAD THE RIGHT
TO SAY NO,
BUT DOES
THAT MAKE ME
THE BAD
GUY?