YESTERDAY
I WENT
TO MY GRANDPARENTS'
HOUSE TO HELP
THEM SET UP
THEIR NEW
PHONES.
IT
WAS SUPPOSED TO
BE SIMPLE
AND
HARMLESS.
MY NANA
WAS STRUGGLING
TO READ THE
SCREEN, SO
WE CALLED CUSTOMER
SUPPORT AND
I STARTED SHOWING
HER HOW TO
MAKE THE FONT
BIGGER.
SHE WAS
ASKING QUESTIONS,
TRYING
TO UNDERSTAND,
CLEARLY OVERWHELMED
BY DOING
HER
BEST.
THAT'S
WHEN MY GRANDPA'S
MOOD
SHIFTED.
HE
STARTED SNAPPING
AT HER,
SHUSHING
HER EVERY
TIME SHE TRIED
TO
SPEAK.
AT FIRST
I BRUSHED
IT
OFF.
THIS
IS HOW HE'S ALWAYS
BEEN.
IN.
SHORT -TEMPERED,
EASILY IRRITATED,
ALWAYS NEEDING
CONTROL OF
THE
ROOM.
BUT THEN,
WHILE I
WAS CALMLY
EXPLAINING
A SETTING, HE
LEANED IN
AND TOLD ME
TO SHUT
UP.
I SAID
NO.
THAT WAS
ENOUGH TO SET
HIM
OFF.
HE STOOD
UP, YANKED
OFF HIS JACKET,
AND STARTED
YELLING THAT
I NEEDED TO
GET OUT OF HIS
HOUSE.
HE THREATENED
TO CALL THE
POLICE.
MY NANA
GRABBED MY
ARM, BEGGING
ME TO STAY
WITH HER, CLEARLY
SCARED AND
CAUGHT IN THE MIDDLE
LIKE SHE ALWAYS
IS.
WHILE HE
WAS SHOUTING,
SOMETHING IN
ME HE FINALLY
BROKE.
YEARS
OF WATCHING
HIM BULLY PEOPLE,
EXPLODE
WITHOUT WARNING,
AND THEN
PLAY THE VICTIM
CAME RUSHING
OUT.
I TOLD
HIM THE TRUTH,
THAT HE'S
CRUEL, THAT
HE'S A BULLY,
AND THAT THIS
IS EXACTLY
WHY NONE OF
HIS GRANDCHILDREN
CALL HIM
OR WANT A RELATIONSHIP
WITH
HIM.
THE ROOM WENT
SILENT.
LATER,
I FOUND
OUT HE TOLD
THE FAMILY HIS
VERSION OF
THE
STORY.
AN AUNT TEXTED
ME, DEMANDING
I APOLOGIZE
BECAUSE
HE'S OLD
AND HE
DIDN'T MEAN
IT.
BUT
THIS ISN'T
A ONE -TIME
SLIP.
THIS
IS A PATTERN
THAT'S LASTED
DECADES.
EVERY
GRANDCHILD
HAS TRIED
TO LIVE WITH HIM
AT SOME
POINT.
EVERY
EVERY SINGLE ONE
OF US WAS EVENTUALLY
THROWN
OUT.
SOMETIMES
FOR MISSING
A CURFEW
WE COULDN'T
PHYSICALLY
MEET.
SOMETIMES
FOR NOT
TALKING
ENOUGH.
SOMETIMES
FOR REASONS
SO SMALL
THEY BARELY MADE
SENSE.
HE CONSTANTLY
COMPLAINS
THAT NO ONE
CALLS
HIM.
THAT
WE'RE WASTING THE
CHANCE TO
LEARN FROM HIS
WISDOM, WHILE
IGNORING THE
FEAR AND DAMAGE
HE LEAVES
BEHIND.
HE BELIEVES
RESPECT
IS
AUTOMATIC.
HE BELIEVES
BEING A
GRANDFATHER ENTITLES
HIM TO ACCESS,
OBEDIENCE,
AND
SILENCE.
ALL I
DID WAS SAY
OUT LOUD WHAT
EVERYONE ELSE
HAS QUIETLY
LEARNED THE
HARD
WAY.