I'M
24, AND
EVERY WINTER
MY FAMILY
IN DORSET
HAS A TRADITION
WHERE WE
ALL SEND OUT
HOLIDAY LISTS
FILLED WITH
LINKS AND
NOTES AND
NO ONE BUYS
DUPLICATES.
MY
MOTHER MANAGES
THE LIST
AND UPDATES
EVERYONE WHENEVER
SOMETHING GETS
PURCHASED.
I
HAVE FINISHED
ALL MY SHOPPING
WEEKS BEFORE
THE LISTS
WENT
OUT.
AND
ONE OF THE THINGS
I BOUGHT FOR
MY FATHER
WAS A CAST
IRON BRITTLE
SET HE'S
BEEN HINTING
IT FOR
AGES.
MY
GRANDMOTHER,
WHO I'LL
CALL MARJORIE,
HAS ALWAYS
BEEN
INTENSE.
SHE'S
IN HER LATE 70S
SHARP
AS A BLADE
BUT EXTREMELY
CONTROLLING
SHE
WAS RAISED IN
AN ERA WHERE
CHAOS WAS
NORMAL AND
IT SHOWS IN
HOW SHE MICROMANAGES
EVERYTHING FROM
WHO CARVES
THE ROAST TO
WHICH CHAIRS PEOPLE
SIT
IN MY
FATHER STILL
FREEZES UP
WHEN SHE RAISES
HER VOICE
WHEN
SHE'S CHEERFUL
SHE'S GENUINELY
FUNNY BUT
THOSE MOMENTS
ARE RARE AFTER
THE LISTS
WENT OUT MY
MOTHER MARK
THE GRIDDLE
SET IS ALREADY
PURCHASED
SO NO
ONE ELSE WOULD
BUY IT SHE
SENT THE USUAL
UPDATE TO
OUR GROUP
CHAT.
A FEW
DAYS LATER,
MARJORIE
CALLED MY FATHER
AND DEMANDED
TO SPEAK TO
MY
MOTHER.
SHE
PROUDLY ANNOUNCED
SHE HAD BOUGHT
HIM THE GRIDDLE
SET, PLUS
TWO OTHER
ITEMS THAT
WERE ALSO ALREADY
MARKED AS
PURCHASED.
MY MOTHER
GENTLY REMINDED
HER THAT ALL
THREE GIFTS
HAD BEEN CROSSED
OFF DAYS
EARLIER.
MARJORIE
IMMEDIATELY INSISTED
THAT SHE
HAD NEVER RECEIVED
ANY SUCH
NOTIFICATION
AND
SAID THAT
EVERYONE
ELSE SHOULD
RETURN THEIR
ITEMS
INSTEAD.
RETURNING
HERS, APPARENTLY,
WAS NOT
AN
OPTION.
I DECIDED
I AM NOT
RETURNING THE
GIFT I CHOSE
FOR MY
DAD.
I
PICKED IT
MYSELF, LONG
BEFORE ANY
LISTS WENT
OUT.
AND I
KNOW HE'LL LOVE
IT, SINCE
I LIVE WITH
MY
PARENTS.
HE'LL
GET MINE WEEKS
BEFORE MARJORIE
EVEN ARRIVES
FOR THE HOLIDAY
VISIT.
I'M
AWARE THAT
WHEN SHE FINDS
OUT, SHE'LL
LIKELY RETREAT
INTO SILENCE
FOR
MONTHS.
MAKING
A DRAMATIC
PRODUCTION
OUT OF BEING
WRONGED
BECAUSE SHE DOES
THIS EVERY
TIME ANYONE
CHALLENGES
HER.
THE PART
THAT MAKES ME
HESITATE IS
THAT SHE REALLY
DOES STRUGGLE
WITH
TECHNOLOGY.
SHE
CALLS MY
FATHER CONSTANTLY
FOR HELP
ADJUSTING SETTINGS,
OPENING
FILES, EVEN
FINDING HER
EMAIL.
IT
IS GENUINELY
POSSIBLE
SHE NEVER
SAW THE UPDATED
LIST AND
SINCE RETURNING
THINGS TAKES
HER MUCH
LONGER
NOW.
I UNDERSTAND
WHY SHE'D
PREFER NOT
TO DEAL WITH
THAT.
BUT AT
THE SAME TIME,
SHE
REFUSES
TO ACKNOWLEDGE ANYONE
ELSE'S
EFFORT.
SHE SIMPLY
EXPECTS THE
WORLD TO
REORGANIZE
ITSELF AROUND
HER
CHOICES.
THAT'S
WHAT SHE HAS ALWAYS
DONE.
MISKEEPING
MY GIFT
THE RIGHT
CHOICE.
OR DID
I JUST LIGHT
THE MASH FOR
ANOTHER ONE
OF HER DRAMATIC
STORMS?