I'M 32
AND 7 MONTHS
PREGNANT WITH
A BABY GIRL.
MY HUSBAND,
33, AND
I FINALLY AGREED
ON THE NAME
MARGOT.
IT FELT
CLASSIC, ELEGANT,
AND PERFECT
FOR HER. AT
MY BABY SHOWER,
I EXCITEDLY
SHARED THE NAME
WITH FAMILY. MY
YOUNGER SISTER
IMMEDIATELY STARTED
CRITICIZING IT.
SHE CLAIMED
IT WAS OLD-FASHIONED
AND INSISTED OUR
DAUGHTER WOULD GET
TEASED FOR HAVING
A NAME. LIKE
THAT, IRONICALLY,
SHE ONCE
TRIED TO NAME
HER OWN DAUGHTER
SOMETHING UNUSUAL
AND COMPLICATED.
AND
HER HUSBAND OVERRULED
HER.
HER
COMMENTS DIDN'T
STOP THERE SHE
CONTINUED MAKING
SNIDE REMARKS
DURING THE PARTY
AND LATER BOMBARDED
ME WITH MESSAGES
ON SOCIAL
MEDIA
DEMANDING
THAT WE CHANGE
THE NAME AFTER
A WHILE WE
ASKED HER TO
LEAVE THE SHOWER
AND
I BLOCKED HER
ON SOCIAL MEDIA
TO PREVENT FURTHER
HARASSMENT MARGO
FEELS PERFECT
FOR OUR DAUGHTER
AND
I DON'T WANT TO
CHANGE IT BUT
MY SISTER KEEPS
INSISTING
IT'S A TERRIBLE
CHOICE AM
I WRONG FOR
IGNORING HER OPINIONS
AND KEEPING THE
NAME WE LOVE