I'M A
SINGLE DAD IN
MY EARLY 50S
RAISING MY 13-YEAR-OLD
SON ON MY OWN.
WE LIVE
ACROSS THE COUNTRY
FROM MY PARENTS.
AND WHILE
DISTANCE HELPS,
IT DOESN'T
ERASE THE HISTORY.
GROWING UP,
MY PARENTS,
ESPECIALLY MY
FATHER, USED
MONEY AS LEVERAGE,
PRAISE AS
CURRENCY, AND
GUILT AS DISCIPLINE.
NOTHING WAS
EVER JUST GIVEN.
EVERYTHING CAME
WITH STRINGS, REMINDERS,
AND UNSPOKEN
DEBTS.
I SWORE
I WOULD NEVER LET
MY CHILD GROW
UP CARRYING THAT
SAME EMOTIONAL
WEIGHT.
IRONICALLY, AS
GRANDPARENTS, MY
PARENTS HAVE BEEN
FAR KINDER
AND MORE GENEROUS
THAN THEY EVER
WERE AS PARENTS.
MY SON
IS THEIR ONLY
GRANDCHILD,
AND THAT FACT
ALONE SEEMS
TO MAGNIFY
EVERYTHING THEY
DO.
EARLIER THIS
MONTH, MY
FATHER ASKED
WHAT MY SON MIGHT
WANT FOR CHRISTMAS.
I SENT
A THOUGHTFUL LIST
WITH A WIDE RANGE
OF IDEAS. BOOKS,
CLOTHES, HOBBY
SUPPLIES, AND,
ALMOST
AS AN AFTERTHOUGHT,
A NEWLY RELEASED
GAMING CONSOLE.
A FEW DAYS
LATER, MY
FATHER CALLED
BACK AND ASKED
WHETHER MY SON
WOULD PREFER SEVERAL
SMALLER GIFTS
OR ONE BIG
ONE.
MY
SON EXCITED
BUT POLITE
CHOSE ONE
BIGGER GIFT
MY FATHER
INSISTED ON
HANDLING IT
THE COORDINATED
DELIVERY QUIETLY
AND
THE PACKAGE IS
NOW HIDDEN IN
MY CLOSET WAITING
TO BE WRAPPED
THEN
CAME THE PHONE CALL
THAT CHANGED EVERYTHING
WHAT
STARTED AS
A NORMAL CONVERSATION
SUDDENLY
TURNED SHARP
AND UNCOMFORTABLE MY
FATHER BEGAN
LOUDLY REPEATING
HOW HE HAD
SPENT EVERYTHING
ON MY SON'S
GIFT OVER
AND OVER HE
SAID I NEEDED
TO MAKE SURE MY
SON UNDERSTOOD
HOW MUCH MONEY
IT COST COST
HOW
MUCH OF A SACRIFICE
IT WAS AND
HOW HE
HAD DRAINED HIS
SAVINGS BECAUSE
OF IT HE
EVEN SAID SOMETHING
ALONG THE LINES
OF HE
SHOULD KNOW WHAT
IT COSTS PEOPLE
WHEN HE ASKS
FOR THINGS LIKE
THAT MY
STOMACH DROPPED
THIS WAS
PAINFULLY FAMILIAR
THE
SAME TONE
THE SAME
GUILT THE
SAME MANIPULATION
DRESSED UP
AS GENEROSITY THE
REALITY IS
MY PARENTS ARE
NOT STRUGGLING
THEY
ARE RETIRED BUT
FINANCIALLY SECURE
RECEIVE
A VERY COMFORTABLE
INCOME OWN
THEIR HOME OUTRIGHT
TRAVEL
FREQUENTLY
AND
REGULARLY SPEND
SIMILAR AMOUNTS
ON NON-ESSENTIAL
LUXURIES.
BUYING THIS
GIFT WAS ENTIRELY
THEIR CHOICE.
FROM A
LIST THEY REQUESTED,
NO ONE
PRESSURED THEM.
YET SUDDENLY,
THE GIFT HAD
BECOME A LESSON
IN OBLIGATION. I
COULD ALREADY HEAR
THE ECHOES OF
MY OWN CHILDHOOD
FORMING AROUND
MY SON. AND
I PANICKED.
NOW I'M
TORN APART. PART
OF ME WANTS TO
QUIETLY SEND
MY PARENTS A
CHECK COVERING THE
FULL COST OF
THE GIFT. EVEN
THOUGH THAT WOULD SERIOUSLY
STRAIN MY
OWN BUDGET AS
A SINGLE PARENT.
ANOTHER PART
OF ME WANTS
TO RETURN THE
GIFT ENTIRELY
AND PUT DISTANCE
BETWEEN MY
SON AND THIS
PATTERN,
EVEN IF
IT MEANS HE RECEIVES
NOTHING FROM
HIS GRANDPARENTS THIS
YEAR.
HE DOESN'T
KNOW WHAT THEY BOUGHT
HIM YET, BUT
I KNOW THAT ONCE
GUILT ENTERS
THE PICTURE, IT
NEVER REALLY
LEAVES.
I DON'T
WANT HIS JOY POISONED
BY SOMEONE ELSE'S
NEED FOR CONTROL.
SO NOW
I'M STARING AT
A WRAPPED BOX
THAT FEELS HEAVIER
THAN IT SHOULD.
WONDERING IF
PROTECTING MY
CHILD EMOTIONALLY
MEANS BLOWING
UP CHRISTMAS
ALL OVER AGAIN.