I'M
32M.
MY GIRLFRIEND
IS
30F.
EARLIER THIS
YEAR I MESSED
UP PRETTY BADLY
IN A
RELATIONSHIP.
AND AS PART
OF MAKING THINGS
RIGHT I TOLD
HER I'D COVER THE
ENTIRE COST
OF A 7 DAY
CRUISE FOR THE
TWO
OF
US.
THE BASE
FARE.
TAXES.
FEES.
EVERYTHING.
WHAT WE DIDN'T
DISCUSS WAS THE
AUTOMATIC GRATUITIES
THE CRUISE LINE
CHARGES.
AROUND $110
PER
PERSON.
I DIDN'T
SAY I'D COVER
THOSE.
BUT ONCE
ON BOARD I
TOLD HER I'D USE
MY ON BOARD CREDIT
TO TAKE CARE
OF HER PORTION
AND SEND HER THE
MONEY
FOR IT
HERE'S
WHERE THINGS WENT
SIDEWAYS I
HAD 150
IN
SHIP CREDIT
FROM A BOOKING
PROMOTION PLUS
ANOTHER 200
CREDIT
FROM MY
CREDIT CARD
I PAY
A HEFTY
YEARLY FEE FOR
THAT BENEFIT SO
I HAD 350
TOTAL
IN ONBOARD
CREDIT I
TOLD HER I
HAD CREDITS
AND WOULD USE THEM
FOR THE GRATUITIES
WHILE I
WAS AT GUEST SERVICES
SHE
SAW THE FULL
AMOUNT AND GOT
GENUINELY ANGRY
SHE
ACCUSED ME
OF HIDING THE
TOTAL FROM HER
AND SAID SINCE
WE WERE ON THIS
TRIP AS A COUPLE
I
SHOULD HAVE SPLIT
THE CREDITS 50
-50.
SHE FELT
THAT BY NOT DOING
SO, I
WAS BEING
SELFISH.
I EXPLAINED
THAT THESE WEREN'T
FREE
CREDITS.
ONE CAME
FROM MY CREDIT
CARD PERKS
THAT I PAY A
LOT
FOR.
AND HONESTLY,
I ALREADY
PAY THE ENTIRE
CRUISE FARE
AND HER GRATUITY
CHARGES.
I DIDN'T
FEEL LIKE THE REMAINING
CREDIT WAS
AUTOMATICALLY SOMETHING
SHE WAS ENTITLED
TO.
SHE STILL
THINKS I WAS
WRONG FOR NOT
OFFERING TO DIVIDE
IT
EVENLY.
I FEEL
LIKE I ALREADY
COVERED THE
MAJOR
EXPENSES.
AND THE CREDITS
WERE TIED TO
MY CARD AND
MY
BOOKING.
SO WAS
I BEING
UNFAIR?
FAIR, OR
WAS KEEPING THE
FULL CREDIT REASONABLE
UNDER THE
CIRCUMSTANCES?