DAY
OFF?
MY WIFE
AND I HOST
THANKSGIVING
AND CHRISTMAS
WITHOUT
FAIL.
NOT
POTLUCK
STYLE, NOT
CASUAL DROP
-INS, FULL,
TRADITIONAL,
FAMILY
DINNERS,
THE KIND
THAT TAKE WEEKS
OF
PLANNING.
MY
WIFE HANDLES
EVERYTHING, COORDINATING
SCHEDULES,
SHOPPING,
COOKING, CLEANING,
DECORATING,
I HELP,
BUT LET'S
BE HONEST, SHE
CARRIES THE
WEIGHT OF
IT.
WE DO
THIS BECAUSE
FAMILY MATTERS
TO US,
AND
BECAUSE IT
MATTERS ESPECIALLY
TO MY
MOM HAVING
EVERYONE TOGETHER
NEAR THE
ACTUAL HOLIDAY
IS THE ONE
THING SHE LOOKS
FORWARD TO
ALL YEAR THIS
YEAR WE
DID WHAT WE ALWAYS
DO WE
PICKED A DATE
CLOSE TO CHRISTMAS
SO EVERYONE
COULD ATTEND
INVITATIONS
WENT OUT
PLANS
WERE SET
THEN
MY BROTHER
CALLED HE
TOLD ME HE
AND HIS WIFE
COULDN'T MAKE
IT NOT
BECAUSE OF
ILLNESS NOT
TRAVEL ISSUES
NOT
BECAUSE OF
AN EMERGENCY
BUT
BECAUSE HIS
WIFE MIGHT HAVE
A LONG WORK
WEEK STARTING
SUNDAY
AND WANTED SATURDAY
COMPLETELY.
FREE TO
REST.
AND THEN
CAME THE
KICKER.
THEY SAID
WE'D NEED TO
MOVE CHRISTMAS
DINNER TO
JANUARY
3RD.
OVER A
WEEK AFTER
CHRISTMAS.
THAT WAS,
ACCORDING
TO THEM,
THE NEXT
DAY THAT WORKED
FOR
THEM.
IT ALSO HAPPENED
TO BE A DAY
MY WIFE AND
I WERE OFF
WORK.
I ASKED
WHAT EXACTLY WAS
STOPPING THEM
FROM COMING ON
THE ORIGINAL
DATE.
THE
ANSWER DIDN'T
CHANGE.
THEY JUST
DIDN'T WANT TO
GIVE UP THEIR
SATURDAY.
SO
WE TRIED TO
COMPROMISE.
WE
TOLD THEM THEY
DIDN'T HAVE TO
COME
EARLY.
THEY WOULDN'T
HAVE TO
HELP.
DINNER WOULD
ALREADY BE
MADE.
THEY COULD
SHOW UP IN
THE EVENING EAT
OPEN
GIFTS
STAY
FOR A BIT
AND LEAVE
EARLY ZERO
EFFORT REQUIRED
THEY
STILL SAID
NO INSTEAD
THE
EXPECTATION
WAS THAT
MY WIFE WOULD
REDO THE ENTIRE
HOLIDAY
REPLAN
RESHUFFLE
REHOST
AFTER
CHRISTMAS
JUST
SO ONE COUPLE
WOULDN'T BE MILDLY
INCONVENIENCED
MEANWHILE
MY
MOM WOULD ONCE
AGAIN HAVE
TO SWALLOW HER
DISAPPOINTMENT ABOUT
NOT HAVING CHRISTMAS
TOGETHER WHEN
IT
ACTUALLY MATTERS
TO HER THAT'S
WHEN I FINALLY
SNAPPED BECAUSE
AT WHAT
POINT IS
BEING FLEXIBLE,
TURN INTO
EVERYONE ELSE
REARRANGES
THEIR LIVES FOR
YOU.
AT WHAT
POINT DOES
MY WIFE'S
TIME, EFFORT,
AND EXHAUSTION
GET FACTORED
IN?
AT WHAT
POINT DOES MY
MOM'S FEELINGS
COUNT JUST
AS MUCH AS
SOMEONE WANTING
A DAY TO
RELAX?
I
TOLD MY BROTHER
THAT MOVING CHRISTMAS
TO JANUARY
WASN'T
HAPPENING.
THAT IF
THEY WANTED TO
COME, EVEN
BRIEFLY, WE'D
LOVE TO HAVE
THEM.
BUT WE
WERE NOT CANCELING
CHRISTMAS FOR
EVERYONE ELSE
BECAUSE THEY
DIDN'T FEEL
LIKE SHOWING
UP.
NOW
I'M BEING PAINTED
AS
UNREASONABLE.
IF I'M DEMANDING
TOO
MUCH.
AS IF
WANTING TO CELEBRATE
CHRISTMAS AROUND
CHRISTMAS
IS SOME OUTRAGEOUS
EXPECTATION.
SO
HERE I AM,
WONDERING
WHEN HOSTING,
PLANNING,
AND CARING
ABOUT FAMILY
SOMEHOW BECAME
LESS IMPORTANT
THAN SOMEONE
ELSE'S DESIRE
TO KEEP THEIR
WEEKEND
COMPLETELY
FREE.