I'M A
23 -YEAR
-OLD TOUR GUIDE
FROM ROMANIA
WHO LEADS GROUPS
AROUND
PORTUGAL.
ON A
RECENT TRIP,
A SOLO TRAVELER
IN HER LATE
30S REPEATEDLY
OVERSLEPT
DESPITE CLEAR
INSTRUCTIONS.
EACH DAY,
I PROVIDE THE
GROUP WITH PRINTED
SCHEDULES, ANNOUNCE
DEPARTURE TIMES
THE NIGHT BEFORE,
AND SHARE
MY PHONE NUMBER
IN CASE ANYONE
NEEDS A
REMINDER.
ON THE FIRST
MORNING, SHE
WAS 15 MINUTES
LATE FOR A
DAY TRIP TO
SINTRA, WHICH
I EXCUSED,
BUT I REMINDED
EVERYONE THAT
I CANNOT WAIT
BEYOND 20
MINUTES WITHOUT
PRIOR
NOTICE.
THE FOLLOWING
MORNING, SHE
WAS 30 MINUTES
LATE DESPITE
MY CALLS,
AND SHE
BARELY MANAGED
TO CATCH THE
BUS DUE TO A
LAST -MINUTE HOTEL
ISSUE.
I REMINDED
THE GROUP AGAIN
THAT WAKING UP
ON TIME IS
EACH PERSON'S
RESPONSIBILITY.
THAT EVENING,
SHE ASKED
ME TO KNOCK ON
HER DOOR THE NEXT
DAY, BUT
I EXPLAINED THAT
I COULDN'T WAKE
EVERY TOURIST
AND THAT ALARMS
SHOULD BE SET
INDIVIDUALLY.
ON THE
THIRD DAY, DURING
A TRIP TO COIMBRA,
SHE DIDN'T
SHOW
UP.
I WAITED 20
MINUTES PAST
THE SCHEDULED DEPARTURE
TIME, CALLED
HER TWICE WITH
NO ANSWER, AND
EVENTUALLY LEFT
WITH THE REST OF
THE
GROUP.
AN HOUR
LATER, SHE
CALLED IN A PANIC,
SCREAMING
THAT I HAD RUINED
HER LIFE, DEMANDED
A FULL REFUND,
AND THREATENED
TO SUE THE TOUR
AGENCY FOR
EMOTIONAL
DISTRESS.
SHE EVEN
POSTED SCATHING
REVIEWS ACROSS
MULTIPLE TRAVEL
SITES, TAGGING
ME PERSONALLY
AND CLAIMING
I'D ABANDONED
A VULNERABLE WOMAN
WHICH CAUSED
THE AGENCY TO
GET DOZENS
OF ANGRY EMAILS
AND NEARLY LOST
ME FUTURE
CONTRACTS.
I HAD
WARNED HER MULTIPLE
TIMES
THAT I COULDN'T
BE RESPONSIBLE FOR
WAKING
HER.
SO I
WANT TO KNOW IF
LEAVING HER BEHIND,
EVEN KNOWING
THIS COULD ESCALATE,
WAS
UNREASONABLE.