I'D PLANNED
WHAT I THOUGHT WOULD
BE A SIMPLE NIGHT
OUT WITH A SMALL
GROUP OF
CLASSMATES.
FIVE OF
US MEETING UP
AT A LOCAL
FESTIVAL.
PARTWAY THROUGH,
ONE CLASSMATE'S
COWORKER JOINED
US.
EVERYTHING SEEMED
FINE, AND
AFTERWARD WE
HEADED TO GET DINNER
BEFORE A MOVIE
WE'D ALREADY DECIDED
TO
SEE.
DURING DINNER,
I NOTICED
THE COWORKER
TEXTING SOMEONE
WITH A BIG
GRIN.
MY CLASSMATE
GLANCED AT THE
PHONE AND LOOKED
A BIT UNSETTLED,
WHICH I
MENTALLY
BOOKMARKED.
WHEN DINNER
FINISHED, WE
WALKED TO THE
THEATER, BOUGHT
TICKETS, AND
CHOSE OUR
SEATS.
WHEN I WENT
TO SIT IN THE SPOT
I'D PAID FOR,
ONE OF
THE CLASSMATES STOPPED
ME AND SAID,
OH, THAT
SEAT'S FOR SOMEONE
ELSE.
I ASKED
WHO, AND
THEY WOULDN'T
ANSWER.
THAT'S WHEN THE
PIECES
CLICKED.
I ASKED,
IS THAT SEAT
FOR
LONNIE?
QUOTE, A
FORMER TEAMMATE
I'D BRIEFLY GONE
OUT WITH MONTHS
AGO.
THINGS ENDED
QUIETLY, NO
HARD
FEELINGS.
BUT JUST
THE WEEK BEFORE
SHE TOLD ME
HANGING OUT AGAIN
WOULD FEEL TOO
EMOTIONALLY
COMPLICATED.
EVERYONE IN
THE GROUP KNEW
THIS.
THEY FINALLY
ADMITTED
YES.
THE SEAT WAS FOR
HER.
I ASKED
WHY NO ONE THOUGHT
TO TELL
ME.
AND
AGAIN.
SILENCE.
ONE CLASSMATE
WHISPERED THAT
THEY'D ONLY FOUND
OUT MINUTES EARLIER
AND HADN'T
BEEN PART OF THE
PLAN.
IT TURNED
OUT THE CO -WORKER
HAD INVITED
LONNIE WITHOUT
MENTIONING I
WOULD BE
THERE.
THAT WAS WHO HE'D
BEEN TEXTING DURING
DINNER.
NO ONE
WOULD MAKE EYE
CONTACT.
I SAT
FOR A SECOND
AND REALIZED THAT
IF LONNIE SHOWED
UP UNAWARE I'D
BE
THERE.
WE'D BOTH
FEEL AWKWARD
THE ENTIRE
FILM.
I ALSO
FELT STUNG
THAT THE GROUP HAD
ARRANGED THIS
WITHOUT WARNING
ME.
SO I
GOT UP AND
LEFT.
WHEN SOMEONE
ASKED WHERE I
WAS
GOING.
I JUST
SAID.
BEDROOM, AND
THEN I CALLED A
CLOSE FRIEND TO
PICK ME
UP.
NO ONE
FROM THE GROUP TEXTED
OR CALLED
AFTERWARD.
LATER I
HEARD THEY SAID
I'D
OVERREACTED.
BUT THEY'D
BLINDSIDED BOTH
ME AND LONNIE,
WHO LIKELY
HAD NO IDEA
I'D BE PART OF
THE
OUTING.
I'M NOT
EXPECTING APOLOGIES,
BUT NOBODY
HAS EVEN ACKNOWLEDGED
HOW OFF -PUTTING
THE SITUATION
WAS.
GIVEN ALL
THAT, WAS
LEAVING REALLY
THE WRONG
CALL?