I'M 23
AND HAVE BEEN
LIVING IN THE SAME
CITY FOR A
FEW YEARS NOW.
I'VE BEEN
WITH MY PARTNER,
LIAM,
25,
FOR JUST OVER
TWO YEARS.
WE LIVE
TOGETHER, SHARE
A ROUTINE, AND
USUALLY ATTEND
SOCIAL EVENTS
AS A UNIT.
NOT BECAUSE
WE'RE GLUED TO
EACH OTHER, BUT
BECAUSE OUR LIVES
ARE GENUINELY INTERTWINED.
MY FRIEND
HANNAH, 23,
AND I HAVE
KNOWN EACH OTHER
SINCE OUR LATE
TEENS, BACK
WHEN WE WERE CLASSMATES
AND BONDED
OVER COMPLAINING ABOUT
SCHOOL AND DREAMING
ABOUT INDEPENDENCE.
WE'VE HAD
MINOR DISAGREEMENTS
BEFORE, BUT
NOTHING THAT EVER
HINTED AT WHAT
HAPPENED HERE. HANNAH
THREW HERSELF
A BIG BIRTHDAY
PARTY AT
A RENTED VENUE
IN THE CITY.
IT
WAS CLEARLY PLANNED
TO FEEL IMPORTANT.
PRINTED SEATING
CHARTS.
ASSIGNED
TABLES.
DECORATIONS
EVERYWHERE.
AROUND 35
PEOPLE WERE
INVITED.
WEEKS EARLIER,
I RSVP'D
FOR BOTH ME
AND LIAM. WHEN
WE ARRIVED AND
CHECKED THE SEATING
LIST, I
FELT MY STOMACH
DROP.
I WAS ASSIGNED
TO HANNAH'S TABLE
WITH HER CLOSEST
FRIENDS.
FRONT AND
CENTER.
LIAM, MEANWHILE,
WAS SEATED
ON THE OPPOSITE SIDE
OF THE ROOM WITH
PEOPLE HE DIDN'T
KNOW AT ALL. AT
FIRST, I
GENUINELY ASSUMED
IT WAS A MISTAKE.
I PULLED
HANNAH ASIDE
QUIETLY, EXPECTING
HER TO APOLOGIZE
AND FIX
IT.
INSTEAD, SHE
TOLD ME IT WAS
INTENTIONAL.
SHE SAID
SHE DIDN'T WANT
COUPLES STUCK
TOGETHER AND
WANTED PEOPLE
TO SOCIALIZE
MORE.
THAT
EXPLANATION
COLLAPSED
INSTANTLY
WHEN I LOOKED
AROUND AND REALIZED
EVERY OTHER COUPLE,
SOME
WHO HAD BEEN DATING
ONLY A FEW MONTHS,
WAS SEATED
TOGETHER.
WHEN I POINTED
THIS OUT,
SHE FINALLY
ADMITTED THE
TRUTH.
SHE THOUGHT
LIAM WOULD DRAG
THE ENERGY DOWN
AND SAID
I'D BE MORE FUN
WITHOUT HIM AROUND.
FOR CONTEXT,
LIAM IS
QUIET BUT KIND,
POLITE, AND
HAS NEVER CAUSED
TENSION AT
ANY GATHERING.
ONCE THE DINNER
STARTED, THE
AWKWARDNESS
BECAME IMPOSSIBLE
TO IGNORE.
LIAM SAT
STIFFLY
AT HIS TABLE, SMILING
TOO HARD,
CLEARLY AWARE
THAT HE WAS THE
ONLY PERSON
SEPARATED FROM
THEIR PARTNER. HE
TRIED TO JOKE
ABOUT IT WHEN
HE CAUGHT MY EYE,
BUT I COULD
TELL HE WAS EMBARRASSED
AND UNCOMFORTABLE. IT
FELT LESS LIKE
A SEATING CHOICE
AND MORE LIKE A
PUBLIC STATEMENT ABOUT
HOW UNWELCOME
HE WAS. I
CONFRONTED HANNAH
AGAIN, STILL
PRIVATELY, AND
TOLD HER THAT
DELIBERATELY SINGLING
US OUT,
ESPECIALLY WHILE
SEEING EVERYONE
ELSE WITH THEIR
PARTNERS, WAS
HURTFUL AND
UNNECESSARY.
I ALSO
SAID HER COMMENTS
ABOUT LIAM WERE
UNFAIR.
SHE ROLLED
HER EYES, CALLED
ME IT WAS HER
BIRTHDAY, AND
SAID I WAS BEING
DRAMATIC AND
SELFISH.
I DIDN'T
CAUSE A SCENE.
WE STAYED, WE
ATE, SMILED,
AND CLAPPED
AT THE RIGHT MOMENTS.
BUT I WAS
QUIETER THAN
USUAL, AND
THE NIGHT FELT
HEAVY INSTEAD
OF CELEBRATORY.
SINCE THEN,
HANNAH HAS
BEEN FLOODING MY
PHONE WITH MESSAGES
ACCUSING ME
OF RUINING HER
BIRTHDAY, EMBARRASSING
HER,
AND MAKING
EVERYTHING ABOUT
MY RELATIONSHIP.
SOME MUTUAL
FRIENDS AGREE
WITH HER AND
SAY I SHOULD HAVE
KEPT MY FEELINGS
TO MYSELF FOR
THE SAKE OF
THE
PARTY.
OTHERS THINK
WHAT SHE DID WAS
INTENTIONAL AND
CRUEL AND
THAT I WAS RIGHT
TO SAY SOMETHING.
I DIDN'T
WANT TO CREATE DRAMA,
BUT I ALSO
DIDN'T WANT TO
SILENTLY ACCEPT
MY PARTNER
BEING PUBLICLY
EXCLUDED AND
JUDGED.
I'M STILL
TORN AND
I KEEP REPLAYING
THE NIGHT IN MY HEAD,
WONDERING
IF I CROSS
A LINE OR
IF I SIMPLY REFUSE
TO STAY QUIET
WHEN I SHOULD HAVE.