I'M A WOMAN
IN MY MID-THIRTIES,
AND A
FEW WEEKS AGO
I HOSTED
WHAT WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE A LOW-KEY
JOINT BIRTHDAY
DINNER AT MY HOME.
IN OUR
FAMILY, BIRTHDAYS
ARE OFTEN
GROUPED TOGETHER
TO KEEP THINGS
SIMPLE, AND
THIS ONE WAS MEANT
TO CELEBRATE ME
AND MY HUSBAND'S
YOUNGER COUSIN,
WHO
HAD JUST TURNED
26.
THE HOUSE
WAS ALREADY TENSE
BEFORE ANYONE
ARRIVED,
SINCE MY
HUSBAND'S PARENTS
HAVE BEEN LIVING
WITH US FOR NEARLY
THREE YEARS
WHILE LOOKING FOR
THE RIGHT
PLACE, WHICH
HAS QUIETLY TURNED
OUR HOME INTO
A PRESSURE COOKER
OF UNSPOKEN
EXPECTATIONS.
BARELY FIVE
MINUTES AFTER
GUESTS WALKED
IN, MY
MOTHER-IN-LAW
ABRUPTLY ANNOUNCED
IT WAS TIME
TO EAT. I
HEADED INTO THE
KITCHEN TO SERVE
FOOD, RELIEVED
TO ESCAPE THE
NOISE FOR A
MOMENT.
WHILE I
WAS GONE, MY
SISTER-IN-LAW
APPARENTLY DECIDED
THAT THIS WAS
THE PERFECT TIME
FOR A MAJOR REVEAL.
I HEARD
MUFFLED VOICES
FROM THE LIVING
ROOM, THEN
A SHARP GASP,
FOLLOWED BY
MY MOTHER-IN-LAW
NEARLY SCREAMING
IN DISBELIEF.
I DIDN'T
SEE THE MOMENT
ITSELF, BUT
IT DIDN'T TAKE A
GENIUS TO
REALIZE A PREGNANCY
HAD JUST
BEEN ANNOUNCED. BY
THE TIME MY
MOTHER-IN-LAW
RUSHED INTO THE
KITCHEN WAVING
A SMALL BOX
LIKE IT WAS A
HOLY RELIC.
THE MOMENT
HAD ALREADY PEAKED.
I CONGRATULATED
HER CALMLY AND
WENT BACK TO THE
LIVING ROOM, WHERE
I POLITELY ASKED
MY BROTHER-IN-LAW
A FEW QUESTIONS
ABOUT TIMELINES
AND PLANS.
THE PARTY
MOVED ON. CAKE
WAS CUT. PEOPLE
LAUGHED.
I THOUGHT THAT
WAS THE END OF
IT.
IT WASN'T.
ALMOST TWO
HOURS LATER,
MY SISTER-IN-LAW
SUDDENLY BURST
INTO TEARS
AND ANNOUNCED SHE
WANTED TO LEAVE IMMEDIATELY.
THE ROOM
FROZE.
AS THEY WALKED
OUT, I
OVERHEARD MY
MOTHER-IN-LAW
MUTTER SOMETHING ABOUT
HOW SOME
PEOPLE JUST DON'T
SHOW EMOTION. MOTION.
WHEN SHE
RETURNED, I
ASKED WHAT HAD
HAPPENED, AND
THAT'S WHEN I
WAS TOLD THE TRUTH.
MY SISTER-IN-LAW
FELT DEVASTATED
BECAUSE SHE
BELIEVED NO ONE
HAD BEEN EXCITED
ENOUGH ABOUT
HER PREGNANCY.
I TRIED
TO EXPLAIN THAT
I HADN'T EVEN BEEN
PRESENT WHEN THE
ANNOUNCEMENT HAPPENED,
THAT IT HAD BEEN
FRAMED AS A
GIFT TO HER PARENTS,
AND THAT
THIS GATHERING
HAD BEEN BILLED
AS A BIRTHDAY CELEBRATION.
I GENTLY
POINTED OUT
THAT BIG ANNOUNCEMENTS
ARE USUALLY PLANNED
AROUND EVENTS LIKE
THAT.
NOT DROPPED
INTO THEM, I
WAS IMMEDIATELY SHUT
DOWN.
I WAS
TOLD IT WASN'T
SELFISH.
THAT I
SHOULD HAVE REACTED
BETTER.
AND THAT I'D
SOMEHOW MADE
A MOMENT ABOUT MYSELF.
WHAT MADE
EVERYTHING UGLIER
WAS THE UNSPOKEN
HISTORY.
THIS SAME
WOMAN HAS
A PATTERN OF
MAKING CRUEL
JOKES THAT
EVERYONE PRETENDS
NOT TO HEAR. SHE
REGULARLY COMMENTS
ON MY MOTHER-IN-LAW'S
WEIGHT, HER
LACK OF INCOME,
EVEN ONCE
JOKE THAT SHE'D
BE FREE LABOR
FOR THE BABY'S
ROOM BECAUSE SHE
HAD NOTHING BETTER
TO DO. THESE
REMARKS ARE
ALWAYS EXCUSED,
NEVER CORRECTED,
AND YET SOMEHOW,
I WAS EXPECTED
TO PERFORM JOY
ON COMMAND. A
FEW DAYS LATER,
I FOUND
OUT MY IN-LAWS
DECIDED TO
SKIP THE HOLIDAYS
WITH US ENTIRELY
AND SPEND
THEM WITH HER INSTEAD.
NO CONVERSATION,
NO RESOLUTION,
JUST DISTANCE
AND SILENCE.
I DON'T
HATE HER, AND
I DON'T RESENT
THE PREGNANCY ITSELF,
BUT I ALSO
DON'T BELIEVE EXCITEMENT
SHOULD BE DEMANDED,
ESPECIALLY
WHEN IT'S
ANNOUNCED IN THE
MIDDLE OF SOMEONE
ELSE'S CELEBRATION
AND FOLLOWED
BY EMOTIONAL
FALLOUT.
I KEEP REPLAYING
THE NIGHT IN MY HEAD,
WONDERING IF
I TRULY FAILED
SOME UNSPOKEN
FAMILY TEST,
OR IF I
WAS SIMPLY PUNISHED
FOR NOT PRETENDING
HARD ENOUGH.