ALCOHOL
HAS ALWAYS
BEEN A SENSITIVE
SUBJECT FOR
ME.
I GREW
UP WATCHING MY
FATHER DRINK
HIMSELF INTO
SOMEONE UNRECOGNIZABLE,
AND THAT
EXPERIENCE SHAPED
MY ENTIRE VIEW
OF IT. I'VE
NEVER TOUCHED ALCOHOL,
AND I GENUINELY
DON'T UNDERSTAND
WHY SO MANY
PEOPLE ACT LIKE
THEY CAN'T RELAX,
LAUGH,
OR CELEBRATE
WITHOUT IT.
TO ME, IT'S
NOT FUN. IT'S
TRIGGERING, UNCOMFORTABLE,
AND EXHAUSTING.
MY HUSBAND'S
FAMILY, ON
THE OTHER HAND,
TREATS DRINKING
LIKE A PERSONALITY
TRAIT.
EVERY HOLIDAY
IS SOAKED IN
WINE.
COCKTAILS.
AND JUST
ONE MORE. I'VE
SWALLOWED MY
DISCOMFORT FOR
YEARS TO KEEP
THE PEACE. SITTING
QUIETLY WHILE
BOTTLES EMPTIED
AND CONVERSATIONS
GOT LOUDER
AND SLOPPIER.
I'VE NEVER
MADE IT AN ISSUE
BEFORE.
THIS YEAR
WAS DIFFERENT. FOR
THE FIRST TIME,
CHRISTMAS WAS
BEING HOSTED
AT OUR HOUSE.
I WAS ACTUALLY
EXCITED.
I THOUGHT MAYBE
THIS COULD FINALLY
BE A CALM,
MEANINGFUL
HOLIDAY.
FOCUSED ON
FOOD, CONVERSATION,
AND FAMILY
INSTEAD OF ALCOHOL.
SO I
MADE A DECISION.
NO ALCOHOL IN
MY HOME ON
CHRISTMAS.
I
DIDN'T YELL
IT FROM THE ROOFTOPS
OR MAKE A DRAMATIC
ANNOUNCEMENT.
I
SIMPLY DECIDED
THAT IF I WAS
HOSTING, THIS
WAS THE BOUNDARY.
THE FALLOUT
WAS IMMEDIATE. MY
HUSBAND'S SISTER
CALLED TO ASK
WHAT SHE COULD BRING.
SHE SOUNDED
CHEERFUL, ALMOST
SMUG,
AS SHE DESCRIBED
A FESTIVE
CHRISTMAS MARTINI
SHE WAS DYING
TO MAKE. WHEN
I TOLD HER,
CALMLY, THAT
THERE WOULDN'T BE ALCOHOL
THIS YEAR,
THE TONE
OF THE CALL SHIFTED
INSTANTLY.
SHE WENT
COLD, SHORT
ANSWERS, AWKWARD
SILENCE.
THEN SHE
HUNG UP. WITHIN
HOURS, I
STARTED GETTING TEXTS.
ARE YOU SERIOUS?
THAT'S
SO LAME. IT'S
CHRISTMAS.
LIGHTEN UP.
SOME RELATIVES
HINTED I
WAS BEING CONTROLLING.
OTHERS
FLAT OUT MOCKED
THE IDEA. I
DIDN'T RESPOND.
I WASN'T
ASKING ANYONE
TO QUIT DRINKING
FOREVER.
I WAS ASKING
FOR ONE DAY
OF RESPECT IN
MY OWN HOME.
THEN
CAME THE REAL SLAP
IN THE FACE.
I FOUND
OUT MY SISTER-IN-LAW
HAD DECIDED
TO HOST AN
ALTERNATIVE CHRISTMAS
GATHERING AT
HER HOUSE. ONE
WHERE ALCOHOL
WOULD BE FLOWING
FREELY.
AND ALMOST
EVERYONE CHOSE
TO GO THERE INSTEAD.
JUST LIKE
THAT, MY
CHRISTMAS DINNER
WAS ABANDONED. NOT
BECAUSE OF TRAVEL.
NOT BECAUSE
OF SCHEDULING.
BUT BECAUSE THEY DIDN'T
WANT TO BE SOBER
FOR A FEW HOURS.
I FELT
HUMILIATED,
REJECTED, LIKE
I HAD DRAWN A
LINE AND EVERYONE
DELIBERATELY STEPPED
OVER IT JUST
TO PROVE THEY COULD.
MY HUSBAND
DIDN'T OFFEND
ME.
INSTEAD, HE
TOLD ME HE SPOKE
TO HIS SISTER
AND THAT WE WERE
INVITED TO HER
GATHERING.
HE SAID
I SHOULD STOP MAKING
THIS AN ISSUE,
THAT I WAS BEING
DRAMATIC, AND
THAT IT WASN'T
WORTH THE TENSION.
IN OTHER
WORDS, GIVE
IN, GO
ALONG, AND
PRETEND NONE
OF THIS HURT.
I REFUSED.
NOW HE'S
FURIOUS.
HE SAYS
I'M FORCING HIM
TO MISS CHRISTMAS
WITH HIS FAMILY,
THAT
I'M PUNISHING
HIM FOR SOMETHING
THAT ISN'T
THAT SERIOUS AND
THAT I'M CHOOSING
MY ISSUES
OVER EVERYONE
ELSE'S HAPPINESS.
HE KEEPS
REPEATING THAT
I'M RUINING CHRISTMAS,
COMPLETELY
IGNORING THE
FACT THAT I
WAS THE ONE PUSHED
ASIDE IN
THE FIRST PLACE.
ALL I
WANTED WAS ONE
PEACEFUL HOLIDAY
IN MY OWN HOME,
WITHOUT ALCOHOL,
WITHOUT ANXIETY,
WITHOUT OLD
WOUNDS BEING
REOPENED.
INSTEAD, I'M
BEING TREATED LIKE
THE VILLAIN FOR
DARING TO ASK
FOR IT.