FOR THE
PAST SEVERAL
YEARS, I,
41F,
HAVE TAKEN
ON THE ROLE OF
HOSTING A SMALL
BUT MEANINGFUL CHRISTMAS
DINNER AT
MY HOME WITH MY
HUSBAND.
IT'S NEVER
BEEN A HUGE
GATHERING, USUALLY
JUST US,
MY CHILDHOOD
FRIEND AND
HER BOYFRIEND, AND
OCCASIONALLY MY
MOTHER-IN-LAW,
BUT IT'S
SOMETHING I PUT
A LOT OF TIME,
MONEY, AND
EMOTIONAL ENERGY
INTO.
I PLAN
THE MENU WEEKS
IN ADVANCE, BUDGET
CAREFULLY, AND
TRY TO MAKE IT
A WARM, STRESS-FREE
TRADITION EVERYONE
CAN ENJOY.
JOY.
ABOUT THREE
YEARS AGO,
MY BROTHER-IN-LAW
MOVED IN WITH
US.
AT FIRST,
THINGS WERE
MOSTLY FINE,
BUT A RECURRING
ISSUE QUICKLY
SURFACED.
FOOD.
THE FIRST
CHRISTMAS HE
LIVED WITH US,
JUST TWO
DAYS BEFORE THE
DINNER, I
WENT TO CHECK ON
THE HAM I HAD
BOUGHT SPECIFICALLY
FOR CHRISTMAS
AND
DISCOVERED THAT
HALF OF IT WAS
GONE.
I WAS SHOCKED
WHEN I
BROUGHT IT UP. HE
SHRUGGED AND
SAID HE THOUGHT
HE WAS PART OF
EVERYONE, SO
HE DIDN'T SEE
THE PROBLEM. THE
THING IS, WHILE
HE LIVES WITH
US, HE
DOESN'T ACTUALLY
PARTICIPATE IN
THE HOLIDAY AT
ALL.
HE STAYS
IN HIS ROOM
THE ENTIRE TIME
AND ONLY COMES
OUT ONCE THE
GUESTS HAVE LEFT.
AFTER THAT
INCIDENT, I
TRIED TO BE PROACTIVE.
THE FOLLOWING
TWO YEARS,
I VERY CLEARLY
TOLD HIM,
PLEASE DON'T
OPEN OR TAKE
THE HAM BEFORE
CHRISTMAS DINNER.
IT'S MEANT
FOR EVERYONE, AND
IT ISN'T VERY
BIG.
I BUY A
SMALL, EXPENSIVE
HOLIDAY
HAM, NOT
A MASSIVE ONE,
BECAUSE WE'RE
A SMALL GROUP.
EACH YEAR,
HE ACKNOWLEDGED
ME, AND
EACH YEAR, HE
STILL HELPED HIMSELF
ANYWAY.
HE NEVER
TOLD ME, NEVER
ASKED, AND
NEVER REPLACED
IT.
I'D ONLY FIND
OUT AT THE WORST
POSSIBLE MOMENT
RIGHT
BEFORE HOSTING
WHEN I
REALIZED HALF
THE MAIN DISH
WAS MISSING AGAIN
THIS
PROBLEM DOESN'T
STOP WITH HOLIDAYS
ON
A REGULAR BASIS
WHEN
HE NEEDS GROCERIES
HE'LL
GIVE US A LIST
AND HIS CREDIT
CARD AND
WE'LL PICK UP
EXACTLY WHAT
HE ASKS FOR
DESPITE
THAT HE
CONTINUES TO
EAT FOOD MY
HUSBAND AND
I BUY FOR OURSELVES
ESPECIALLY
ITEMS
I SPECIFICALLY
PURCHASE
FOR MY OWN
MEALS IT'S
REACHED THE POINT
WHERE I FEEL
LIKE I CAN'T
RELY ON ANYTHING
STAYING STAYING WHERE
I PUT IT. EVEN
AFTER REPEATED
CONVERSATIONS.
NOW, WITH
ANOTHER CHRISTMAS
COMING UP,
I'M EXHAUSTED
JUST THINKING
ABOUT REPEATING
THE SAME CYCLE.
I HAVE A
MINI FRIDGE IN
MY HOME OFFICE.
AND I'M
SERIOUSLY CONSIDERING
STORING
THE HOLIDAY
FOOD THERE SO
IT WON'T DISAPPEAR
BEFORE CHRISTMAS.
EH, BUT
PART OF ME FEELS
RESENTFUL
THAT I EVEN HAVE
TO DO THIS IN
MY OWN HOUSE.
IT FEELS
PETTY, SECRETIVE,
AND UNFAIR,
BUT I'M ALSO
TIRED OF BEING
IGNORED AND
HAVING MY EFFORTS
UNDERMINED
YEAR AFTER YEAR.
SO, AM
I WRONG FOR
WANTING TO HIDE
THE CHRISTMAS FOOD
DOES IT ACTUALLY
MAKES IT TO
THE TABLE THIS
TIME?