I WAS
AT A CROWDED
SUPERMARKET
I'LL CALL FRESH
MEADOW MARKET,
ONE OF
THOSE BIG-NAME
CHAINS THAT
FEELS A LOT LIKE
EVERY OTHER ONE.
WHEN THIS
SURPRISINGLY DRAMATIC
SITUATION
UNFOLDED,
I WAS SHOPPING
WITH TWO CLOSE
RELATIVES WHO
HELPED TAKE CARE
OF ME. AND
THE STORE WAS
ABSOLUTE CHAOS.
EVERY CHECKOUT
LANE BACKED
UP.
CARTS WEDGED
AT ODD ANGLES.
PEOPLE SIGHING
LOUDLY LIKE
IT WAS A COMPETITIVE
SPORT.
SEEING HOW
BAD THE LINES
WERE, THEY
ASKED ME TO STAND
IN ONE OF THE SHORTER
ONES WHILE
THEY RUSHED BACK
TO GRAB THE SINGLE
THING.
WE'D FORGOTTEN.
THIS IS SOMETHING
WE'VE DONE BEFORE
WITHOUT ISSUE,
AND I'VE
ALWAYS HANDLED
IT THE SAME WAY.
IF IT SOMEHOW
BECOMES MY
TURN AND THEY'RE
NOT BACK YET,
I STEP ASIDE
AND LET THE
NEXT SHOPPER
GO SO I DON'T
SLOW ANYTHING DOWN
OR HOLD ANYONE
HOSTAGE WITH
AN
EMPTY CART.
WHILE I WAS
WAITING THERE QUIETLY,
HOLDING
NOTHING AND
BOTHERING NO ONE,
THE MAN
BEHIND ME
SUDDENLY LOST
IT.
HE ACCUSED
ME, LOUDLY,
OF BEING RUDE,
DISRESPECTFUL, AND
CUTTING THE LINE,
INSISTING
THAT YOU'RE ONLY ALLOWED
TO QUEUE UP
AFTER EVERY SINGLE
ITEM IS
ALREADY
IN YOUR POSSESSION.
HE DIDN'T
EXPLAIN WHY
THIS WAS APPARENTLY
A SACRED RULE.
JUST SPOKE
WITH THE CONFIDENCE
OF SOMEONE DELIVERING
A MORAL VERDICT.
THE TENSION
FELT ABSURDLY
HIGH.
LIKE I'D
VIOLATED SOME
ANCIENT GROCERY
CODE RATHER
THAN JUST STANDING
STILL IN A PUBLIC
SPACE.
THERE ARE
NO POSTED RULES
AT FRESH MEADOW
MARKET ABOUT
THIS.
AND I WASN'T
BLOCKING THE CASHIER
OR PREVENTING THE
LINE FROM MOVING.
YET HE
ACTED LIKE I'D
PERSONALLY SABOTAGED
HIS ENTIRE AFTERNOON.
TO MAKE
MATTERS MORE
INTENSE.
MY RELATIVES
WEREN'T WANDERING
AIMLESSLY OR
ADDING A DOZEN
THINGS TO THE
CART.
THEY HAD
GONE STRAIGHT TO
THE PET AISLE TO
GRAB A MASSIVE
BAG OF CANINE
HARVEST PRIME
BLEND DOG FOOD
AND
A SMALLER POUCH
OF UP JOY
VARIETY BITES
BOTH
FROM THE SAME
SECTION AND
BOTH IMPOSSIBLE
TO CARRY BY
HAND THE
KIBBLE ALONE
WAS HEAVY
ENOUGH TO JUSTIFY
THE CART AND
IT HONESTLY NEVER
CROSSED OUR
MINDS THAT FORGETTING
ONE BULKY
ITEM MEANT
WE SHOULD ABANDON
OUR SPOT
AND RESTART THE
WHOLE PROCESS
FROM THE BACK
OF THE LINE LIKE
WE'D COMMITTED SOME
KIND OF RETAIL
SIN STILL
AFTER
BEING PUBLICLY
SCOLDED BY
A STRANGER WHO
SEEMED PERSONALLY
OFFENDED BY
MY PRESENCE I'VE
BEEN WONDERING EVER
SINCE DID
I ACTUALLY DO
SOMETHING WRONG
HERE OR
WAS THIS JUST
MISPLACED
HOLIDAY STRESS
EXPLODING IN
AISLE 7.