MY PARTNER
AND I USUALLY
GO TO MY EXTENDED
FAMILY'S
THANKSGIVING.
MY PARENTS,
SIBLINGS,
AND THEIR KIDS.
THERE ARE ABOUT
25 PEOPLE
IN TOTAL.
BUT IT'S JUST
THE THREE OF US.
INCLUDING OUR
SIX-MONTH-OLD
BABY.
THIS YEAR,
MY BROTHER SAID
HE'D HANDLE THE
TURKEY AND HAM
BECAUSE HE BOUGHT
A NEW SMOKER.
HE SPENT
AROUND $450
ON
MEAT AND TOLD
EVERYONE ELSE
TO BRING SIDES.
I OFFERED
TO MAKE STUFFING.
THE NEXT
DAY, MY
SISTER SENT
A GROUP CHAT
MESSAGE SAYING
EVERY EVERY FAMILY
UNIT HAD
TO SPEND AT
LEAST $150
ON FOOD
OR
CHIP IN TO
COVER MY BROTHER'S
MEAT.
IT FELT
SUDDEN, CONTROLLING,
AND LIKE A
STRICT RULE RATHER
THAN A SUGGESTION.
LATER, SHE
ESCALATED
IT, BASICALLY
ISSUING AN
ULTIMATUM.
OPTION 1. BRING
ENOUGH FOOD
FOR THE WHOLE GROUP.
OPTION 2.
PAY $150
TO MY
BROTHER FOR MEAT.
OPTION 3.
PAY $300
TOWARD DAD'S
HEATING BILL. I
WAS SHOCKED AND
FRUSTRATED.
IT FELT
LIKE MY PARTICIPATION
IN THANKSGIVING
WAS BEING
TURNED INTO A
FINANCIAL TEST
IN RESPONSE. I
TEXTED.
IT OPTION
FOUR DON'T
COME I
LOVE MY FAMILY
BUT THIS
YEAR IT FEELS
LIKE A RIDICULOUS
MONEY TRAP
SHOULD
I JUST STAY
HOME AND AVOID
THE STRESS OR
WOULD THAT MAKE ME
THE BAD GUY