I'M A
31-YEAR-OLD
WOMAN WHO HAS
BEEN FINANCIALLY
ON HER OWN
SINCE FINISHING
UNIVERSITY.
I WORKED
NEARLY FULL-TIME
WHILE STUDYING,
PAID OFF
MY LOANS WITHOUT
HELP, AND
ONLY RECENTLY
STARTED PUTTING
MONEY ASIDE
TO BUY A SMALL
APARTMENT.
WHEN I WAS
YOUNGER, MY
GUARDIANS WERE
VERY CLEAR THAT
ONCE I FINISHED
SECONDARY SCHOOL,
I NEEDED
TO STAND ON
MY OWN FEET.
BECAUSE OF
THAT, I
PASSED ON POSTGRADUATE
PROGRAMS
I WAS INTERESTED
IN AND
FOCUSED ON
SURVIVING AND
STABILIZING.
MYSELF
INSTEAD, MY
YOUNGER COUSIN,
WHO IS 23,
HAS HAD A
VERY DIFFERENT PATH.
HE'S BRILLIANT,
GENUINELY GIFTED
ACADEMICALLY,
AND EARNED A
FULL MERIT SCHOLARSHIP
TO A TOP
PUBLIC UNIVERSITY.
HE GRADUATED
WITH HONORS
AND WAS RECENTLY
ACCEPTED INTO
A HIGHLY SELECTIVE
POSTGRADUATE
PROGRAM IN
A
MAJOR EUROPEAN
CITY.
IT'S AN INCREDIBLE
OPPORTUNITY,
BUT THE TUITION
AND LIVING COSTS
ARE STEEP, EVEN
WITH PARTIAL FUNDING
AND A SMALL
STIPEND.
LAST MONTH,
MY AUNT AND
UNCLE SAT
ME DOWN AND
ASKED IF I COULD
CONTRIBUTE ABOUT
12,000
EUROS TO HELP
COVER HIS FIRST
YEAR.
THEY SAID
THEY WOULD PUT IN
A SIMILAR AMOUNT
AND THAT HE'D TAKE
OUT LOANS FOR
THE REST. I SAID
NO.
I'VE SPENT
MORE THAN A DECADE
BUILDING MYSELF
UP FROM NOTHING
AND I'M
FINALLY CLOSE
TO SOMETHING RESEMBLING
SECURITY.
I DIDN'T
FEEL ABLE TO
DERAIL THAT,
ESPECIALLY
WHEN I'D
BEEN TOLD GROWING
UP THAT THERE
WAS NO SAFETY
NET FOR ME.
THAT'S WHEN
MY AUNT SNAPPED
AND SAID THEY WOULD
JUST USE MY
OTHER SAVINGS
INSTEAD.
I WAS
COMPLETELY CONFUSED.
AFTER SOME
PUSHING, SHE
ADMITTED THEY HAD
QUIETLY SET
ASIDE ROUGHLY
30,000
EUROS YEARS AGO
IN MY NAME
INTENDED
FOR A FUTURE
ENGAGEMENT OR
WEDDING I
HAD NEVER BEEN
TOLD THIS MONEY
EXISTED NOT
WHEN I WAS CHOOSING
BETWEEN DEGREES
NOT
WHEN I WAS STRUGGLING
TO PAY RENT
AND NOT
NOW WHILE I'M
TRYING TO BUY A
HOME WHEN
I ASKED WHY
I'D NEVER BEEN
GIVEN THE CHANCE
TO USE IT
OR EVEN KNOW ABOUT
IT SHE
SAID IT WAS ALWAYS
MEANT FOR A
SPECIFIC PURPOSE
AND
SINCE I WASN'T
PARTNERED OR
PLANNING A CEREMONY
THEY
FELT IT MADE SENSE
TO GIVE IT
TO SOMEONE WHO
NEEDED IT MORE
RIGHT NOW I
FELT BLINDSIDED
AND DISMISSED
I
TOLD THEM IT HURT
TO LEARN THERE HAD
BEEN HELP AVAILABLE ALL
ALONG.
JUST NOT
FOR THE LIFE CHOICES
I MADE. MY
COUSIN LATER
REACHED OUT
AND SAID HE HAD
NO IDEA
THE MONEY HAD
BEEN EARMARKED
FOR ME AND DIDN'T.
ASK FOR
IT, HE
UNDERSTANDS WHY
I'M UPSET, BUT
HE'S FOCUSED ON
SCHOOL AND
ASSUMED EVERYONE
WAS ON THE SAME
PAGE.
I'M PROUD
OF HIM, AND
I KNOW THIS ISN'T
HIS FAULT. STILL,
I CAN'T
SHAKE THE FEELING
THAT I'M BEING
PENALIZED FOR
BEING PRACTICAL,
INDEPENDENT,
AND QUIET
ABOUT MY STRUGGLES,
WHILE DECISIONS
ABOUT MY
FUTURE WERE
MADE WITHOUT ME
EVEN BEING IN
THE ROOM.