I'M A MAN
IN MY MID-THIRTIES,
RECENTLY
LAID OFF
FROM MY JOB
IN TECH, AND
ACTIVELY TRYING
TO GET BACK ON
MY FEET. APPLICATIONS,
INTERVIEWS, FOLLOW-UPS,
IT'S ALL HAPPENING,
JUST NOT
AS FAST AS
ANYONE WOULD LIKE.
I DON'T HIDE
IT, BUT I
ALSO DON'T
WANT IT DRAGGED INTO
EVERY CONVERSATION,
ESPECIALLY DURING
THE HOLIDAYS
WHEN EMOTIONS ALREADY
RUN HIGH. THIS
HAPPENED AT A
CHRISTMAS DINNER
HOSTED BY
MY MOTHER AT
MY GRANDPARENTS' HOUSE.
THE GUEST
LIST WAS A
USUAL MIX
OF CLOSE FAMILY.
FAMILY.
MY MOM,
MY AUNT,
HER HUSBAND,
COUSINS, AND
MY UNCLE, MY
MOTHER'S OLDER
BROTHER, WHO
HAS ALWAYS ENJOYED
BEING THE LOUDEST
VOICE IN THE ROOM.
I SHOWED UP
EARLY, BROUGHT
A NICE BOTTLE
OF WINE AND
A HOMEMADE DESSERT,
HELPED IN
THE KITCHEN, AND
DID MY BEST
TO BE PLEASANT
AND LOW MAINTENANCE.
I JUST
WANTED ONE CALM
EVENING WHERE
I WASN'T REDUCED
TO MY EMPLOYMENT
STATUS.
THAT DIDN'T
LAST ALMOST AS
SOON AS WE SAT
DOWN.
MY UNCLE
STARTED IN.
FIRST IT
WAS A CASUAL
JAB ABOUT
WHEN I WAS JOINING
THE WORKFORCE AGAIN.
I SMILED
TIGHTLY AND
SAID, I
WAS INTERVIEWING.
VIEWING.
HE LAUGHED
AND KEPT GOING.
THROUGHOUT DINNER,
HE MADE COMMENT
AFTER COMMENT.
ABOUT ME
BEING ON A PAID
VACATION.
ABOUT SANTA
BRINGING ME A
JOB APPLICATION.
ABOUT HOW
I MUST ENJOY
SLEEPING IN
WHILE EVERYONE ELSE
WORKS.
EACH TIME,
PEOPLE JUGGLED
AWKWARDLY.
NO ONE TOLD
HIM TO STOP.
MY MOM
AVOIDED EYE
CONTACT.
MY AUNT
SMILED LIKE
IT WAS HARMLESS
TEASING.
BY THE FIFTH
REMARK, MY
CHEST WAS TIGHT
AND MY APPETITE
WAS GONE.
I FINALLY
SAID, CALMLY
AND CLEARLY,
THAT I'D REALLY
APPRECIATE IT
IF HE DROPPED IT
BECAUSE I WAS THERE
TO CELEBRATE CHRISTMAS.
NOT TO
BE PUBLICLY MOCKED.
HE ROLLED
HIS EYES AND
TOLD ME IT WAS
JUST JOKES
AND THAT I NEEDED
TO TOUGHEN UP.
SOMETHING ABOUT
HEARING THAT,
AFTER MONTHS
OF STRESS,
REJECTION
EMAILS, AND
SELF-DOUBT,
HIT HARDER
THAN I EXPECTED.
I STOOD
UP, SAID
A BRIEF MERRY
CHRISTMAS.
EVERYONE GRABBED
MY COAT
AND WALKED
OUT INTO THE
COLD WITHOUT
MAKING A SCENE.
I DROVE
HOME SHAKING,
HALF FROM
ANGER AND HALF
FROM EMBARRASSMENT.
LATER THAT
NIGHT, MY
MOTHER CALLED
ME UPSET, SAYING
I HUMILIATED
HER, THAT
I SHOULD HAVE JUST
IGNORED HER BROTHER
BECAUSE HE'S
ALWAYS BEEN LIKE
THAT, AND THAT
MY LEAVING
MADE THE WHOLE
DINNER UNCOMFORTABLE.
NOT ONCE
DID SHE ASK
HOW I WAS DOING
OR WHY IT HURT
SO MUCH. NOW
I'M BEING TREATED
LIKE THE PROBLEM
FOR REFUSING TO
SIT THERE AND
BE THE FAMILY PUNCHLINE
ON CHRISTMAS.
AND I CAN'T
STOP WONDERING IF
PROTECTING MY
DIGNITY REALLY
MADE ME THE
VILLAIN.