I'M A
COLLEGE STUDENT
IN MY EARLY
20S,
AND FOR
THE PAST FEW
WEEKS MY UNCLE
AND HIS TEENAGE
DAUGHTER HAVE
BEEN STAYING WITH
MY FAMILY WHILE
THEIR
PLACE IS BEING
RENOVATED.
BECAUSE OF
SPACE, MY
COUSIN, WHO'S
IN HER EARLY TEENS,
HAS BEEN
SLEEPING IN
MY BEDROOM. BEFORE
THEY ARRIVED,
MY MOM ASKED
ME TO PUT AWAY
ANY BOOKS SHE
FELT WERE INAPPROPRIATE
FOR SOMEONE
THAT AGE. I
COMPLIED AND
LOCKED SEVERAL NOVELS
IN A SMALL DRAWER,
BUT THERE WASN'T
ENOUGH ROOM FOR
EVERYTHING, SO
I HAD TO MAKE
JUDGMENT CALLS
ABOUT WHAT STAYED
OUT.
I LEFT
A FEW DYSTOPIAN
NOVELS ON
MY SHELF, INCLUDING
ONE I'D STUDIED
YEARS AGO FOR
A LITERATURE EXAM.
THAT PARTICULAR
BOOK WAS
FILLED WITH MY OLD
NOTES AND MESSY
ANNOTATIONS
FROM WHEN I WAS
A TEENAGER. MYSELF.
AND I HONESTLY
DIDN'T THINK
IT WOULD INTEREST HER
AT ALL. BETWEEN
THE DENSE THEMES
AND MY BORDERLINE
ILLEGIBLE HANDWRITING,
IT DIDN'T
SEEM LIKE SOMETHING
SHE'D PICK UP
CASUALLY.
I WAS
WRONG.
ONE AFTERNOON
I CAME HOME
TO FIND OUT MY
COUSIN HAD BEEN
READING IT. AND
MY UNCLE HAD
DISCOVERED THIS
AND IMMEDIATELY SHUT
IT DOWN, TELLING
HER SHE WAS FAR
TOO YOUNG FOR
THAT KIND OF MATERIAL.
THEN HE
TURNED ON ME.
HE ACCUSED
ME OF BEING IRRESPONSIBLE
AND CARELESS,
SAYING
THAT BY LEAVING
THE BOOK ON MY
SHELF I HAD
EXPOSED HER
TO SOMETHING INAPPROPRIATE
AND THAT
IT
WAS MY FAULT
FOR NOT LOCKING
IT AWAY LIKE THE
OTHERS.
I DIDN'T
INTEND FOR HER
TO READ IT, AND
I GENUINELY THOUGHT
I'D TAKEN REASONABLE
PRECAUTIONS GIVEN
THE LIMITED SPACE
I HAD. STILL,
HIS REACTION
MADE ME SECOND
GUESS MYSELF.
WAS I
ACTUALLY WRONG
FOR LEAVING THAT
BOOK OUT, OR
WAS THIS AN OVERREACTION
TO SOMETHING I
COULDN'T REALISTICALLY
CONTROL?