I'VE
NEVER ENJOYED
BIG BIRTHDAY PRODUCTIONS
AND EVERYONE CLOSE
TO ME KNOWS I
PREFER SOMETHING QUIET.
BUT
DESPITE REPEATEDLY
SAYING THIS,
MY SISTER
LENA, WHO
THRIVES ON
GRAND GESTURES,
STARTED
ACTING SUSPICIOUS
IN THE WEEKS
LEADING UP
TO MY BIRTHDAY, DODGING
QUESTIONS AND
TEASING PLANS I
EXPLICITLY ASKED
HER NOT TO MAKE.
THE
NIGHT BEFORE, A
FRIEND ACCIDENTALLY
REVEALED
THERE WAS A FULL-BLOWN
PARTY PLANNED
AT OUR PARENTS'
HOUSE WITH EXTENDED
FAMILY, CO-WORKERS,
HERS.
AND, TO
MY SHOCK, MY
EX, WHOM
I BROKE UP WITH
ONLY WEEKS EARLIER
AFTER A PAINFUL
ENDING AND
HAVE CLEARLY ASKED
TO AVOID ENTIRELY
WHEN
I CONFRONTED LENA,
SHE ADMITTED
THE PARTY WASN'T
JUST FOR MY BIRTHDAY
AT ALL BUT
A CALCULATED ATTEMPT
TO FORCE A
REUNION,
SAYING IT
WOULD BE GOOD
FOR EVERYONE
AND THAT I'D
EVENTUALLY THANK
HER.
EVEN ACCUSING
ME OF BEING
UNGRATEFUL AND
DRAMATIC FOR
OBJECTING,
FEELING
BLINDSIDED
AND FURIOUS
AT THE IDEA
OF BEING AMBUSHED
INTO EMOTIONAL RECONCILIATION
ON MY
OWN
BIRTHDAY, I
TURNED OFF MY
PHONE THE NEXT
DAY AND SPENT
IT QUIETLY WITH
A CLOSE FRIEND
INSTEAD.
ONLY TO
RETURN TO A
FLOOD OF ANGRY
MESSAGES ACCUSING
ME OF HUMILIATING
MY SISTER AND
RUINING SOMETHING
SHE CLAIMS
WAS DONE FROM
THE HEART, LEAVING
ME WONDERING IF
I WAS TRULY WRONG
FOR CHOOSING
MY OWN
PEACE OVER A
PARTY THAT WAS
NEVER REALLY ABOUT
ME IN THE FIRST
PLACE.