I'M
A WOMAN IN
MY EARLY 20S,
AND
FOR MOST
OF MY LIFE
MY OLDER SIBLING
HAS BEEN
PROTECTED AND
EXCUSED
BY OUR REMAINING
PARENT.
NO
MATTER WHAT
HE DID, THAT
PATTERN FINALLY
EXPLODED
INTO A FULL
FAMILY RIFT
WHEN A CUSTODY
CASE DRAGGED
ALL OF US
INTO
COURT.
YEARS
AGO, MY
SIBLING WAS
IN A LONG -TERM
RELATIONSHIP WITH
HIS PARTNER,
AND THEY
HAD A YOUNG
CHILD
TOGETHER.
DURING
THAT RELATIONSHIP,
I BECAME
VERY CLOSE
TO HIS PARTNER
AND DEEPLY INVOLVED
IN THE CHILD'S
LIFE.
EVEN
AFTER THEY
SEPARATED, I
STAYED
PRESENT.
HELPING WITH
CHILDCARE, SCHOOL
ROUTINES,
AND EMOTIONAL
SUPPORT,
ESSENTIALLY
BECOMING
ONE OF
THE FEW STABLE
ADULTS THE
CHILD COULD RELY
ON.
WHEN
THE CHILD
WAS STILL A
TODDLER, MY
SIBLING WALKED
AWAY, HE
MOVED OUT,
STOPPED
CONTRIBUTING
FINANCIALLY,
RARELY CHECKED
IN, AND
EVENTUALLY VANISHED
ALTOGETHER AFTER
STARTING A
NEW
RELATIONSHIP.
HIS FORMER
PARTNER STRUGGLED,
BUT SHE CARRIED
EVERYTHING ALONE
AND BUILT
A STABLE LIFE
FOR HER CHILD
WITHOUT
HIM.
FOR
YEARS, MY
SIBLING WOULD
DISAPPEAR FOR
LONG STRETCHES,
OFFERING
NO CONSISTENCY
AND NO
REAL
SUPPORT.
COURT.
THEN, SUDDENLY,
HE CAME
BACK, INSTEAD
OF APOLOGIZING
OR TRYING TO
REBUILD TRUST
SLOWLY.
HE DEMANDED
PERSONAL
INFORMATION
AND THREATENED
LEGAL
ACTION.
HIS FORMER
PARTNER HAD
RELOCATED
TO PROTECT HER
STABILITY AND
ASKED ME NOT
TO SHARE HER
DETAILS, WHICH
I
RESPECTED.
WHEN
MY SIBLING
CONFRONTED ME,
I REFUSED,
TELLING HIM
THAT IF HE TRULY
WANTED TO
BE INVOLVED, HE
NEEDED TO
TAKE RESPONSIBILITY
AND
FOLLOW PROPER
LEGAL
STEPS.
HE
ACCUSED ME
OF BETRAYAL AND
CLAIMED I WAS
CHOOSING AN
OUTSIDER OVER
FAMILY.
EVENTUALLY,
HE LOCATED
HER ON HIS
OWN AND FILED
FOR CUSTODY,
DEMANDING
FAR MORE
RESPONSIBILITY
THAN
HE HAD EVER
SHOWN
BEFORE.
I WAS
ASKED TO
TESTIFY, AND
I TOLD THE
TRUTH, THAT
HE HAD BEEN
ABSENT FOR
YEARS, THAT
THE CHILD'S
OTHER PARENT
HAD BEEN THE
ONLY CONSISTENT
CAREGIVER,
AND
THAT HIS SUDDEN
RETURN COINCIDED
WITH HIS DESIRE
TO PRESENT
A POLISHED
IMAGE.
THE
COURT LIMITED
HIS REQUEST,
PRIORITIZING
THE CHILD'S
STABILITY.
SINCE
THEN, MY
SIBLING HAS
CUT INTO ME
RELENTLESSLY,
INSISTING
I SHOULD HAVE LIED
OR STAYED
SILENT.
OUR PARENT
AGREES, TELLING
ME I RUINED
HIS CHANCE
AT REDEMPTION
AND THAT LOYALTY
SHOULD COME
BEFORE
HONESTY.
EVEN
WHEN A CHILD'S
WELL -BEING IS
INVOLVED, I
DON'T REGRET PROTECTING
A CHILD
WHO NEEDED STABILITY,
BUT BEING
FROZEN OUT
AND BLAMED BY
MY OWN FAMILY
HAS LEFT
ME WONDERING HOW
TELLING THE
TRUTH TURNED
ME
INTO THE
VILLAIN.