DURING A
TRIP TO ANOTHER
CITY TO
VISIT MY PARTNER
AND HIS RELATIVES.
HE DECIDED
THAT MY FINAL
NIGHT SHOULD BE
CELEBRATED WITH
A BIG FAMILY DINNER.
HE PICKED
A TRENDY ALL-YOU-CAN-EAT
GRILL AND SUSHI
SPOT CALLED
FIRE KOI
TABLE.
A PLACE
HE RAVED ABOUT.
AND INVITED
FOUR OF
HIS RELATIVES ALONG
WITHOUT REALLY
ASKING HOW
I FELT ABOUT
IT.
THE DEAL
WAS ONE OF THOSE
FIXED PRICE MENUS
WHERE YOU COOK
EVERYTHING YOURSELF.
AND ANYTHING
LEFT ON
THE TABLE COSTS
EXTRA.
I'VE NEVER
BEEN A BIG RED
MEAT PERSON.
I MOSTLY
EAT POULTRY
AND SEAFOOD AND
AVOID CERTAIN MEATS
ALTOGETHER.
STILL, I
DIDN'T COMPLAIN
AND ORDERED WHAT
I KNEW I'D ACTUALLY
FINISH.
GRILLED CHICKEN,
SHRIMP, RICE,
AND VEGETABLES.
WHILE WE
WERE COOKING, MY
PARTNER KEPT
LOADING THE GRILL
WITH BEEF CUTS
AND SEVERAL PLATES
OF MEAT I
DON'T NORMALLY EAT.
I STUCK
TO MY FOOD
AND FINISHED EVERYTHING
I ORDERED. WHEN
HE OFFERED ME
BEEF, I
TRIED A BIT TO
BE POLITE. WHEN
HE PUSHED A
DIFFERENT MEAT,
I HESITATED,
BUT THE LOOK
HE GAVE ME MADE
IT FEEL LIKE
REFUSING WASN'T
AN OPTION. SO
I FORCED DOWN
A SMALL PIECE.
HE EVEN
TRIED TO PASS
MORE OF IT OFF
AS SOMETHING ELSE
AND
THAT'S WHEN I
FINALLY SAID
I WAS FULL AND
STOPPED FROM
THAT MOMENT ON
HIS ENERGY
COMPLETELY CHANGED
THE DRIVE
BACK WAS SILENT
TENSE
AND
UNCOMFORTABLE THEN
HE SNAPPED TELLING
ME HE'D SPENT
NEARLY 300
ON
DINNER AND
THAT ALL I'D EATEN
WAS A FEW
BITES
OF CHEAP FOOD
HE ACCUSED
ME OF BEING
UNGRATEFUL AND
WASTING HIS MONEY
EVEN
THOUGH I HADN'T
ORDERED THE EXPENSIVE
ITEMS
HADN'T
ASKED FOR THE RESTAURANT
AND
HADN'T LEFT ANYTHING
UNEATEN ON
MY PLATE. I
PAID ATTENTION
TO WHAT I ORDERED,
FINISHED EVERY
BITE, AND
NEVER ASKED FOR
MORE THAN I COULD
HANDLE.
HE CHOSE
THE PLACE, HE
INVITED THE
GROUP, AND
HE ORDERED MOST
OF THE FOOD
THAT INFLATED
THE BILL. STILL,
SOMEHOW, I
WAS THE PROBLEM
FOR NOT EATING
THINGS I NEVER
WANTED IN
THE FIRST PLACE.