I'M
A MAN IN
MY LATE 30S
LIVING WITH MY
WIFE IN A
QUIET EUROPEAN
CITY.
AND
FROM THE VERY
BEGINNING OF
OUR RELATIONSHIP
WE BUILD
OUR LIFE AROUND
RESTRAINT, PLANNING,
AND THE IDEA
THAT FREEDOM
LATER WAS
WORTH SACRIFICE
NOW.
WE
LIVE MODESTLY,
SAVE
AGGRESSIVELY, AVOID
UNNECESSARY LUXURIES,
AND TREAT
BIRTHDAYS
AS SMALL
BUT MEANINGFUL
MOMENTS
WHERE WE
BUY EACH OTHER
SOMETHING PERSONAL
FROM OUR
OWN
ACCOUNTS.
SOMETHING
THAT FEELS
INTENTIONAL
RATHER THAN
INDULGENT.
A
FEW MONTHS BEFORE
MY BIRTHDAY,
MY WIFE
SHYLY ADMITTED
SHE'D BEEN
DREAMING ABOUT
AN EXPENSIVE
BEAUTY GADGET
SHE KEPT
SEEING
ONLINE.
IT
WAS FAR OUTSIDE
OUR USUAL
HABITS.
AND WHILE
I DIDN'T FORBID
IT, I
SUGGESTED SHE
DO WHAT WE ALWAYS
DO WHEN TEMPTATION
HITS.
WAIT
A COUPLE OF
WEEKS AND
SEE IF THE DESIRE
FADES.
SHE
NEVER MENTIONED
IT
AGAIN.
AND I
ASSUMED THE
URGE HAD
PASSED.
JUST LIKE
IT USUALLY
DOES.
ON
MY BIRTHDAY,
SHE HANDED
ME A LARGE,
CAREFULLY
WRAPPED
BOX.
THE MOMENT
I OPENED IT,
MY STOMACH
DROPPED.
INSIDE WAS
THE EXACT ITEM
SHE'D WANTED
FOR
HERSELF.
SOMETHING I
WOULD NEVER USE
AND HAD NEVER
SHOWN INTEREST
IN.
I DIDN'T
SAY ANYTHING RIGHT
AWAY.
INSTEAD,
I HANDED
IT TO HER
QUIETLY.
WATCHING
HER EYES LIGHT
UP AS SHE
RAN HER FINGERS
OVER
IT.
ADMIRED
THE
FINISH.
AND SMILED
IN A WAY
THAT FELT DEEPLY
FAMILIAR.
LIKE
SOMEONE FINALLY
HOLDING
SOMETHING THEY'D
LONG IMAGINED
OWNING.
THAT
WAS WHEN I SAID
IT.
SOFTLY
BUT
PLAINLY.
THAT IT
DIDN'T FEEL LIKE
THE GIFT WAS
ACTUALLY MEANT
FOR
ME.
THE ROOM WENT
COLD.
HER EXCITEMENT
VANISHED.
HER FACE
FELL.
AND SHE
ASKED WHY
I WOULD EVEN SAY
SOMETHING LIKE
THAT.
AFTER
A LONG,
HEAVY
SILENCE.
SHE
WALKED INTO
THE BEDROOM
AND SHUT THE
DOOR, LEAVING
THE UNOPENED
BOX SITTING
ALONE ON
THE SOFA, UNTOUCHED
THROUGH THE NIGHT,
LIKE A REMINDER
OF A CELEBRATION
THAT SOMEHOW
TURNED INTO
A QUIET STANDOFF
NEITHER OF
US KNEW HOW
TO
RESOLVE.