I'M AN 18-YEAR-OLD
WOMAN LIVING
IN A SMALL
COASTAL TOWN
IN A DIFFERENT COUNTRY
FROM WHERE I GREW
UP.
AND THE
WEEK BEFORE WINTER
BREAK COMPLETELY
UNRAVELED
ME, BETWEEN
FINAL EXAMS
AND UNIVERSITY
APPLICATION DEADLINES.
MY SLEEP
TURNED CHAOTIC,
VIVID NIGHTMARES,
WAKING UP
EVERY HOUR,
AND THEN CRASHING
SO HARD
IT FELT LIKE BEING
KNOCKED UNCONSCIOUS.
ONE MORNING
I WOKE UP TO
THE KIND OF ACCIDENT
I HADN'T HAD
SINCE CHILDHOOD.
I'D WET
THE BED. IT
IMMEDIATELY DRAGGED
ME BACK TO BEING
A KID, WHEN
MY PARENTS TREATED
STRESS-RELATED
ACCIDENTS LIKE
MORAL FAILURES.
EVEN NORMAL
BATHROOM NEEDS
WERE FRAMED AS
INCONVENIENCES
TO THEM. SO
I LEARNED EARLY
TO HIDE EVERYTHING.
I STRIPPED
THE SHEETS AT
DAWN.
RAN THE
WASHING MACHINE
BEFORE ANYONE
WOKE UP.
AND PRETENDED
NOTHING HAPPENED.
A FEW DAYS
LATER.
I WAS VENTING
WITH TWO CLOSE FRIENDS
AT A CAFE NEAR
CAMPUS.
WE WERE
SPIRALING TOGETHER
ABOUT APPLICATION
FEES.
DEADLINES.
AND THE PRESSURE
TO NOT MESS UP
OUR FUTURES. ONE
FRIEND ADMITTED
STRESS HAD
GOTTEN SO BAD
HER HAIR WAS
THINNING.
THE CONVERSATION
TURNED INTO
A SORT OF GALLOWS
HUMOR CONFESSIONAL.
EACH OF
US SHARING SOMETHING
HUMILIATING
BUT REAL. I
FINALLY JOKED,
HALF LAUGHING
AND HALF MORTIFIED,
THAT I'D BEEN
SO STRESSED
I'D HAD A NIGHTTIME
ACCIDENT.
IT FELT
SAFE SAYING IT
THERE, LIKE
RELEASING A
SECRET INTO
A ROOM WHERE
IT WOULDN'T BE WEAPONIZED.
I DIDN'T
KNOW ONE OF THOSE FRIENDS
WOULD TELL HER MOTHER,
A PEDIATRIC
PHYSICIAN WHO
WORKS AT A PRIVATE
CLINIC.
HER MOM
PANICKED OUT
OF CONCERN AND
CALLED MY PARENTS
DIRECTLY.
THAT'S WHEN
EVERYTHING EXPLODED.
MY PARENTS
WEREN'T WORRIED
ABOUT MY HEALTH
OR STRESS. THEY
WERE FURIOUS THAT
I'D MADE THEM LOOK
BAD BY
NOT TELLING THEM
FIRST WHEN
I TRIED TO EXPLAIN
THAT
I WAS SCARED
OF BEING SHAMED
OR PUNISHED. THEY
SNAPPED BACK
THAT I COULDN'T
HAVE BEEN THAT SCARED
IF I WAS WILLING
TO TALK TO OTHER
PEOPLE'S PARENTS.
THE IRONY
WAS CRUSHING.
MY FRIEND'S
MOM HAD RESPONDED
WITH CALM,
KINDNESS,
AND ACTUAL
CONCERN, WHILE
MY OWN PARENTS
WERE LIVID.
NOW THEY'VE
BANNED ME FROM
SEEING THAT FRIEND
OUTSIDE OF
SCHOOL UNLESS
I APOLOGIZE
TO HER MOTHER
AND
TELL HER I
MADE THE WHOLE THING
UP FOR ATTENTION.
THEY WANT
ME TO REWRITE REALITY
TO PROTECT
THEIR IMAGE.
I REFUSE.
I WON'T
LIE ABOUT MY
BODY OR MY
STRESS TO MAKE
THEM MORE COMFORTABLE.
ESPECIALLY AFTER
YEARS OF
BEING TAUGHT TO
HIDE ANYTHING VULNERABLE.
TERRIBLE.
I DIDN'T
CHOOSE FOR THIS TO
SPREAD, BUT
I DID CHOOSE TO
TELL THE TRUTH,
AND I STILL
BELIEVE THAT SHOULD
BE MY RIGHT.
SO AM
I WRONG FOR
REFUSING TO LIE
AND TAKING THE
FALLOUT INSTEAD?