I'M A 26-YEAR-OLD
WOMAN WHO RECENTLY
MOVED IN
WITH MY PARTNER.
A 30-YEAR-OLD
MAN I'VE BEEN
DATING FOR JUST
OVER FIVE MONTHS.
AND THIS
CHRISTMAS FEELS
LIKE IT'S TURNING
INTO AN EMOTIONAL
MINEFIELD.
UNTIL NOW,
MY FAMILY'S
HOLIDAYS HAVE
ALWAYS BEEN SPLIT
BECAUSE MY PARENTS
DIVORCED YEARS
AGO.
THE ROUTINE
WAS PREDICTABLE.
A QUIET
MEAL WITH MY
FATHER AT ONE
HOUSE.
THEN LATER
DRINKS, GIFTS,
AND FORCED
CHEER WITH MY
MOTHER AT ANOTHER.
MY SIBLINGS,
BOTH IN
THEIR 20S,
STUCK TO
THIS SYSTEM TOO.
WHILE THEIR PARTNERS
ALWAYS SPEND
CHRISTMAS ELSEWHERE
WITH THEIR OWN
FAMILIES, IT
WASN'T PERFECT,
BUT IT WAS FAMILIAR.
THIS YEAR
CHANGED EVERYTHING.
MY PARTNER'S
PARENTS INVITED
US TO THEIR HOME
OUTSIDE THE
CITY AND EVEN
EXTENDED AN
OPEN INVITATION
TO
MY ENTIRE FAMILY
FOR CHRISTMAS
DINNER.
IT FELT
LIKE A BIG STEP
FOR US AS A
COUPLE, ESPECIALLY
SINCE WE'VE
JUST STARTED BUILDING
A LIFE TOGETHER.
I TRIED
TO INCLUDE MY
SIDE OF THE FAMILY
SO NO ONE
WOULD FEEL LEFT OUT.
BUT WHEN
I INVITED MY
MOTHER AND SIBLINGS,
SHE SHUT
IT DOWN IMMEDIATELY.
IMMEDIATELY SHE
SAID CHRISTMAS
HAD NEVER BEEN
DONE THIS WAY
AND INSISTED
IT SHOULD BE SPENT
AT HER HOUSE
JUST
LIKE ALWAYS
WITH
HER CHILDREN UNDER
ONE ROOF
THE
TONE MADE IT
CLEAR THAT MY
GROWING INDEPENDENCE
WASN'T WELCOME
TRYING
TO KEEP THE PEACE
I
CAME UP WITH A
COMPROMISE I
INVITED MY
FATHER TO JOIN
US AT MY PARTNER'S
FAMILY DINNER
THINKING
MY SIBLINGS
COULD STAY WITH
MY MOTHER AND
I'D STOP BY
FOR DRINKS AND
PRESENTS BEFORE
HEADING OUT
MY MOTHER
AGREED ON THE
SURFACE BUT
HER DISAPPOINTMENT WAS
OBVIOUS WHEN
I MENTIONED THAT
NEXT YEAR WE
COULD DO CHRISTMAS
HER WAY SHE
BRUSHED IT
OFF SAYING
SHE DOESN'T
PLAN THAT FAR
AHEAD WHICH
SOMEHOW MADE
IT FEEL HEAVIER
LIKE
A QUIET WARNING
THAT TIME IS
RUNNING OUT THEN
JUST
A DAY BEFORE
CHRISTMAS EVE
EVERYTHING
COLLAPSED
MY
FATHER CANCELED
AT THE LAST MINUTE
SAYING
YOU WANTED TO
BE ALONE THIS
YEAR BECAUSE HE
HAD TO WORK EARLY
THE NEXT MORNING
SUDDENLY
I WAS
LEFT STARING
AT AN IMPOSSIBLE
CHOICE
CANCEL
ON MY PARTNER'S
FAMILY WHO
HAD ALREADY PLANNED
AND WELCOMED ME
OR GO
THROUGH WITH IT
AND RISK THIS BEING
ONE OF THE LAST
CHRISTMASES I
EVER SPEND AWAY
FROM MY PARENTS
THE
GUILT IS CRUSHING
AND THE
DECORATIONS AND
LIGHTS JUST MAKE
IT WORSE LIKE
THEY'RE MOCKING ME
FOR GROWING UP
SO
NOW I'M TORN
BETWEEN TRADITION
AND THE FUTURE
I'M TRYING TO
BUILD BETWEEN
MY PARENTS
EXPECTATIONS AND
MY OWN HAPPINESS
AM
I REALLY THE
VILLAIN HERE FOR
CHANGING HOW CHRISTMAS
LOOKS AND CHOOSING
TO SPEND IT
WITH THE PERSON
I LOVE