WAS I
WRONG TO BE UPSET?
I'LL CHANGE
IDENTIFYING DETAILS,
BUT KEEP
THE SITUATION THE
SAME.
FOR MY BIRTHDAY,
TWO CLOSE
FRIENDS PLANNED
WHAT THEY FRAMED
AS A SURPRISE
OUTING.
I WAS DROPPED
OFF AT A CAFE
IN A NEARBY
CITY WITH
NO IDEA WHAT
WAS HAPPENING. ONLY
TO FIND THEM
WAITING FOR ME
INSIDE.
THEY HAD ARRANGED
A BIRTHDAY BRUNCH
DEAL THAT INCLUDED
FOOD AND
DRINKS.
BROUGHT FLOWERS,
A SMALL
DESSERT, AND
A WRAPPED GIFT.
AND AFTERWARD
WE WALKED TO
A DESSERT SHOP
NEARBY.
ONE OF
THEM COVERED THE
BILL AT THE RESTAURANT.
AND THE
WHOLE DAY FELT
LIKE A THOUGHTFUL
BIRTHDAY TREAT
THAT I HADN'T BEEN
ASKED TO PLAN
OR BUDGET. FOUR,
ABOUT TWO
WEEKS LATER, THAT
SAME FRIEND
SENT ME A PAYMENT
REQUEST FOR
MY SHARE OF
THE BRUNCH AND DESSERT.
ROUGHLY $50.
WITHOUT ANY
MESSAGE OR
EXPLANATION.
THAT'S WHAT
THREW ME OFF.
IT WASN'T
ABOUT THE MONEY
ITSELF.
I COULD AFFORD
IT AND WOULD HAVE
PAID WITHOUT ISSUE
IF IT HAD BEEN
DISCUSSED AHEAD
OF TIME. WHAT
BOTHERED ME WAS
THAT THIS HAD BEEN
PRESENTED AS
A SURPRISE. AND
IN MY EXPERIENCE,
WHEN SOMEONE
PLANS A SURPRISE
BIRTHDAY OUTING,
IT USUALLY
MEANS EITHER
THEY'RE COVERING
IT OR THEY CLEARLY
COMMUNICATE COSTS
IN ADVANCE. I
BROUGHT IT UP CALMLY
AND EXPLAINED
THAT I WAS OKAY
PAYING.
BUT THAT
THE SURPRISE CHARGE
FELT AWKWARD
AND CONFUSING.
SHE IMMEDIATELY
GOT DEFENSIVE
AND SAID SHE
HAD SIMPLY FORGOTTEN
TO PAY FOR ME
AT THE TIME.
THAT I
SHOULDN'T HAVE ASSUMED
IT WAS COVERED.
AND NOT EXPECTING
THAT MADE ME
UNGRATEFUL CONSIDERING
SHE'D ALREADY
DONE A LOT BY
ORGANIZING THE
DAY,
BRINGING GIFTS,
AND TRAVELING
TO SEE ME.
SHE ALSO
SAID THAT WHETHER
A SURPRISE MEANS
IT'S PAID FOR
IS SUBJECTIVE AND
THAT OTHER PEOPLE
AGREED
WITH HER. I
TRIED TO EXPLAIN
THAT MY DISCOMFORT
WASN'T ABOUT
WANTING MORE,
BUT ABOUT
THE MISMATCH
BETWEEN HOW THE
DAY WAS FRAMED
AND WHAT HAPPENED
AFTERWARD.
TO ME,
PLANNING SOMETHING
WITHOUT MY
INPUT AND
THEN CHARGING ME
LATER FELT LIKE
OFFERING A GIFT
AND THEN ASKING
TO BE REIMBURSED.
IT LEFT
ME FEELING LIKE
SHE WANTED THE
CREDIT FOR DOING
SOMETHING SPECIAL
WITHOUT ACTUALLY
FOLLOWING
THROUGH ON
WHAT THAT IMPLIED.
WE TALKED
IT OUT, BUT
SHE DIDN'T ACKNOWLEDGE
ANY FAULT
OR SEE WHERE I
WAS COMING FROM
AT ALL. THAT'S
WHAT'S STILL BOTHERING
ME.
IT'S HARD
FOR ME TO BELIEVE
SHE SHE TRULY DOESN'T
UNDERSTAND WHY
THIS FELL OFF.
ESPECIALLY SINCE
I WASN'T RUDE
OR DEMANDING. NOW
I'M STUCK WONDERING
IF I MISSED SOME
PERSPECTIVE HERE.
OR IF I'M
JUSTIFIED IN
FEELING UNCOMFORTABLE
ABOUT BEING
CHARGED FOR
A BIRTHDAY SURPRISE
I DIDN'T
ASK
FOR.