I'M
MARK, 42M,
AND I
LIVE WITH MY
DAUGHTER LILA,
17F,
AND MY STEPSON
EVAN,
14M.
EVAN'S
FATHER PASSED
WHEN HE
WAS YOUNG,
AND HE'S
BEEN WITH ME
EVER
SINCE.
HE'S
A THOUGHTFUL KID
WHO ENJOYS COMPANY,
BUT WHEN
HIS PERSONAL
SPACE IS
CROSSED, HE
RETREATS
INWARD IN
A WAY THAT'S
HARD TO PULL
HIM OUT
OF.
LILA,
ON THE OTHER
HAND, IS
ENDLESSLY SOCIAL
AND ALWAYS
SURROUNDED BY
FRIENDS.
SO
WHEN SHE ASKED
TO HOST A
SLEEPOVER
FOR FOUR
OF THEM, I
AGREED ON
TWO SIMPLE
CONDITIONS THEY
NEEDED TO
STAY OUT OF
EVAN'S ROOM
AND KEEP THE
NOISE DOWN
AFTER 11
SO EVERYONE
COULD REST
I
DIDN'T THINK
THIS WAS
RESTRICTIVE.
THEY'RE
NEARLY
ADULTS.
I TRUSTED
THEM BUT
AROUND 10
P .M
I WENT
UPSTAIRS JUST
TO MAKE SURE
EVERYTHING WAS
FINE AND
THAT'S WHEN I
FOUND ALL FIVE
GIRLS IN
EVAN'S ROOM
TWO
WERE SITTING RIGHT
ON HIS BED
ONE
WAS LEAFING
THROUGH HIS SKETCHBOOK
SOMETHING.
HE TREATS LIKE
IT'S PART OF
HIM.
ANOTHER
WAS POKING
AROUND HIS
SHELVES THEY
WERE LAUGHING
IN THIS STRANGE
UNCOMFORTABLE
WAY
AS
IF THEY KNEW
HE FELT CORNERED
EVAN
WASN'T SPEAKING
HE
WASN'T MOVING
TEARS
WERE ROLLING
DOWN HIS
FACE AND
HE DIDN'T RESPOND
WHEN I CALLED
HIS NAME
SEEING
HIM LIKE THAT
SHOOK ME
I
IMMEDIATELY TOLD
THE GIRLS TO
LEAVE HIS ROOM
LILA
TRIED TO
DEFEND IT AS
HARMLESS FUN
BUT
I TOLD HER
THOSE WERE THE
ONLY RULES
I SET AND
THEY HAD BEEN
IGNORED COMPLETELY
I
CALLED EACH
PARENT EXPLAINED
WHAT HAPPENED
AND
HAD THE GIRLS
PICKED UP THAT
NIGHT LILA
WAS FURIOUS
SHE
INSISTED I
I EMBARRASSED HER
AND MADE EVERYTHING
DRAMATIC.
I TOLD
HER WE WOULD
TALK THE NEXT
MORNING AND
ASK HER TO
GO TO HER
ROOM.
AFTER
SPENDING SOME
TIME COMFORTING
EVAN UNTIL
HE SAID HE
WANTED
SPACE.
I
WENT BACK TO
LILA'S
ROOM.
BUT SHE
REFUSED TO
SPEAK TO
ME.
NOW
THE HOUSE IS
QUIET.
BOTH KIDS
ARE LIKELY
ASLEEP.
AND I'M
SITTING HERE
WONDERING IF
STEPPING IN
SO FIRMLY
HELPED PROTECT
EVAN.
OR
IF I WENT TOO
FAR TRYING
TO KEEP THE
PEACE IN MY
OWN
HOME.