I HAVE
A FRIEND, LET'S
CALL HIM NATHAN,
WHO I'VE KNOWN
FOR OVER A
DECADE.
NATHAN HAS
ALWAYS BEEN A
SOLID FRIEND,
AND HE WAS
EVEN PART OF
MY OWN WEDDING
CELEBRATION.
HE'S BEEN
DATING HIS GIRLFRIEND,
EMMA, FOR
AROUND SIX YEARS,
AND SHE TRULY
BRINGS OUT THE
BEST IN
HIM.
A FEW WEEKS
AGO, NATHAN
CONFIDED
IN ME THAT HE
WAS PLANNING TO
PROPOSE TO
EMMA OVER THE
HOLIDAYS.
HE'S ARRANGING
FOR HIS PARENTS
TO UNEXPECTEDLY
VISIT
THEM EARLY ONE
MORNING WHILE
THEY'RE SPENDING
CHRISTMAS WITH
HER FAMILY, AND
HE WANTS TO
POP THE QUESTION
DURING THE GIFT
OPENING.
WITH BOTH FAMILIES
PRESENT, WHEN
WE WERE CHATTING
ABOUT THE PLANS,
NATHAN CASUALLY
MENTIONED THAT
HE HADN'T BOUGHT
ANY OTHER CHRISTMAS
PRESENTS FOR
EMMA BECAUSE HE
WAS
COUNTING THE ENGAGEMENT
AS HER
GIFT.
I TOLD HIM
THAT GETTING ENGAGED
AND EXCHANGING
GIFTS DON'T
HAVE TO BE MUTUALLY
EXCLUSIVE.
WHEN I GOT
ENGAGED, EVEN
THOUGH IT WASN'T
DURING A HOLIDAY,
I STILL
RECEIVED OTHER
THOUGHTFUL
GIFTS.
NATHAN ARGUED
THAT THE RING
ALONE WAS MORE
EXPENSIVE THAN
THE USUAL COMBINED
GIFTS HE
MIGHT GET
HER.
WHICH IS TRUE,
BUT HE WASN'T
STRETCHING HIS
BUDGET TO THE
LIMIT AND COULD
REASONABLY GET
A SMALLER GIFT
AS
WELL.
I
ALSO NOTED
THAT SINCE HE WANTED
THE PROPOSAL TO
BE A SURPRISE, NOT
HAVING ANY OTHER
GIFTS WOULD LIKELY
MAKE EMMA
SUSPICIOUS.
WE DEBATED
THIS A BIT
MORE.
NATHAN INSISTED
THAT GETTING
ENGAGED COUNTS
AS A
GIFT.
BUT I EXPLAINED
THAT EMMA WILL
LIKELY STILL
BUY HIM CHRISTMAS
PRESENTS SHE
KNOWS HE'LL
ENJOY.
AND THE
ENGAGEMENT ISN'T
THE SAME TYPE OF
EXCHANGE.
SHE'S NOT
MATERIALISTIC,
BUT SHE DOES
APPRECIATE THE
TRADITION OF
EXCHANGING GIFTS
AND THE THOUGHT BEHIND
THEM.
NATHAN SEEMED
FRUSTRATED BY
MY PERSPECTIVE
AND MENTIONED
HE PROBABLY WON'T
SHARE FURTHER DETAILS
WITH ME
BECAUSE OF OUR
DIFFERING
VIEWS.
I DON'T
WANT TO PUSH THE POINT
TOO HARD, BUT
I'M CURIOUS WHETHER
MY ADVICE REALLY
WAS OFF
BASE.