AFTER MY
PARTNER AND
I RETURNED FROM
OUR FIRST SHORT
TRIP SINCE OUR
NEWBORN TWINS
ARRIVED, WE
UNLOCKED OUR
HOME AND IMMEDIATELY
REALIZED
SOMETHING WAS
WRONG.
THE STUDY
WAS STRIPPED BARE,
AND THE
TWO HAND-CARVED
HARDWOOD PIECES
MY PARTNER
HAD INHERITED
FROM HER LATE
GRANDFATHER, OBJECTS
SHE TREASURED
MORE THAN ANYTHING
IN THE HOUSE,
WERE SIMPLY
GONE.
HER AUNT,
WHOM WE'D TRUSTED
WITH A SPARE KEY
ONLY FOR EMERGENCIES,
STOOD
THERE BEAMING
AND ANNOUNCED SHE'D
DONE US A FAVOR
BY DONATING
THE OLD, DUSTY
STUFF AND
REPLACING IT
WITH CHEAP BOXED
FURNITURE TO
GIVE THE ROOM A
FRESH START
AS IF SHE
HADN'T JUST ERASED
A PIECE OF MY
PARTNER'S HISTORY
WITHOUT PERMISSION
MY PARTNER
BROKE DOWN ON
THE SPOT AND
I TOLD HER AND
TO LEAVE DEMANDED
THE KEY BACK
AND CHANGED
THE LOCKS THE
NEXT DAY NOW
THE EXTENDED FAMILY
IS FLOODING US
WITH MESSAGES CALLING
ME CONTROLLING
AND CRUEL ACCUSING
ME OF ISOLATING
MY PARTNER
FROM HER FAMILY
AND PUNISHING
A GRANDMOTHER OVER
JUST FURNITURE
INSISTING
HER INTENTIONS WERE
PURE WHILE
MY PARTNER IS
STILL CRYING OVER
SOMETHING THAT
CAN NEVER BE REPLACED
SHE
AGREES WITH A
BAN BUT
THE PRESSURE
AND GUILT ARE
RELENTLESS, AND
I'M LEFT WONDERING
IF PROTECTING MY
PARTNER AT
OUR HOME MAKES
ME HEARTLESS,
OR
IF THIS BOUNDARY
WAS LONG OVERDUE.