I'M IN
MY LATE 30S
AND EXPECTING MY
SECOND CHILD,
A BABY
GIRL, AND
WHAT SHOULD BE A
JOYFUL, INTIMATE
TIME HAS
TURNED INTO A
SURPRISINGLY INTENSE
FAMILY STANDOFF.
MY SPOUSE
AND I ALREADY
HAVE A YOUNG SON,
AND THIS
PREGNANCY HAS
FELT SPECIAL
IN A DIFFERENT WAY.
MAYBE BECAUSE
WE'RE MORE SETTLED
NOW.
MAYBE BECAUSE
WE KNOW THIS
CHAPTER WON'T
LAST FOREVER. MONTHS
AGO, WHEN
RELATIVES CASUALLY
ASKED IF
WE HAD NAMES IN
MIND, WE
SHARED A SHORT
LIST, NOT
THINKING MUCH
OF IT. ONE
NAME IN PARTICULAR
STOOD OUT
TO US. IT'S
TIMELESS EXTREMELY
POPULAR
AND
HAS BEEN AROUND
FOREVER AT
THE TIME IT
WAS JUST A
FAVORITE NOT
A LOCKED-IN DECISION
THEN
MY PARTNER'S
SIBLING WHO
RECENTLY HAD
A BABY OF HER
OWN AND ISN'T
PLANNING ANOTHER CHILD
ANYTIME SOON
PULL
THIS ASIDE AND
SAID THAT THIS EXACT
NAME WAS
THE ONE SHE HAD
ALWAYS DREAMED
OF USING ONE
DAY
SHE
EXPLAINED THAT
SHE DIDN'T GET TO
CHOOSE HER OWN
BABY'S NAME
AND THAT THIS ONE
WAS SUPPOSED
TO BE FOR
A FUTURE DAUGHTER
SOMEDAY
MAYBE
SHE
ASKED US TO TAKE
IT OFF OUR LIST
AND PICK LITERALLY
ANYTHING ELSE.
INSISTING WE
WERE TAKING SOMETHING
MEANT FOR
HER.
WHAT SHE DIDN'T
KNOW AT FIRST
IS THAT THIS NAME
ALSO BELONGED
TO A WOMAN
IN MY FAMILY
SEVERAL GENERATIONS
BACK.
SOMEONE I
NEVER MET BUT
WHOSE NAME CARRIES
QUIET EMOTIONAL
WEIGHT.
WHEN I MENTIONED
IT TO A CLOSE
FAMILY MEMBER
ON MY SIDE,
THEY
TEARED UP IMMEDIATELY,
WHICH MADE
THE NAME FEEL SUDDENLY
MEANINGFUL IN
A WAY I HADN'T
EXPECTED.
SINCE THEN,
THE SITUATION
HAS EXPLODED.
OTHER RELATIVES
HAVE STARTED CALLING
WITH SUGGESTIONS,
FRAMING THEM
AS HELPFUL BUT
BUT CLEARLY TRYING
TO
STEER US AWAY.
THERE ARE WHISPERED
CONVERSATIONS, SAD
COMMENTS ABOUT
BEING INCONSIDERATE,
AND SUBTLE
IMPLICATIONS THAT
I'M SELFISH FOR
WANTING SOMETHING
THAT SOMEONE ELSE
CLAIMED, EVEN
THOUGH
NOTHING WAS EVER
OFFICIAL AND
THERE'S NO GUARANTEE
SHE'LL EVER USE
IT.
MY SPOUSE
IS FURIOUS ON
MY BEHALF AND
HAS DOUBLED DOWN,
SAYING
NO ONE GETS
TO RESERVE A
COMMON NAME
INDEFINITELY OR
DICTATE OUR CHOICES,
ESPECIALLY WHEN
THIS CHILD IS
ARRIVING SOON
AND HERS MAY
NEVER EXIST
STILL.
THE CONSTANT
PRESSURE, GUILT,
AND FAMILY
POLITICS ARE
WEARING ON ME,
AND WHAT
ONCE FELT EXCITING
NOW FEELS
HEAVY AND
CONFLICTED.
I CAN'T
SHAKE THE FEELING
THAT SHARING OUR
LIST AT ALL
WAS A MISTAKE. BUT
AM I ACTUALLY
WRONG FOR STILL
WANTING TO USE
THE NAME DESPITE
EVERYONE TELLING
ME I SHOULDN'T?