I'M A 27
-YEAR -OLD WOMAN
WORKING AT
A SMALL DESIGN
FIRM ABOUT
15 MINUTES
FROM MY
PLACE.
I USUALLY
KEEP TO MYSELF,
FINISH MY
WORK, AND
HEAD
HOME.
A FEW MONTHS
AGO, A
NEW COWORKER
NAMED LILA,
WHO'S AROUND
33, JOINED
OUR
TEAM.
WE WERE FRIENDLY
IN A SURFACE
-LEVEL WAY,
JUST NORMAL
OFFICE
CHATTER.
ONE AFTERNOON,
THERE WAS A HEAVY
DOWNPOUR, AND
AS I WAS GETTING
READY TO LEAVE,
SHE ASKED
IF I COULD DROP
HER AT A METRO
STATION A
COUPLE MINUTES OFF
MY
ROUTE.
ROUTE
SINCE IT WAS
PRACTICALLY ON
THE WAY I
SAID YES
I FIGURED
IT WAS A ONE
-TIME THING THE
NEXT DAY RIGHT
BEFORE CLOSING
SHE
SHOWED UP AT
MY DESK WITH
HER BAG AND
SAID READY
TO GO I
TOLD HER I
NEEDED TO STAY
LATE AND
SHE LOOKED PUZZLED
BEFORE HEADING OUT
AFTER
THAT SHE
STARTED ACTING
LIKE I WAS HER
BUILT -IN RIDE
SHE'D
STAND BY THE
DOOR AT CLOSING
TIME OR
MESSAGE ME
ASKING IF
I WAS HANGING OUT
NOW EVEN
THOUGH I NEVER SAID
I'D DRIVE HER REGULARLY
IF
I DIDN'T OFFER
SHE'D
BE CHILLY WITH
ME THE FOLLOWING
MORNING.
LAST WEEK,
SHE TEXTED
ME BEFORE THE
END OF THE DAY
ASKING IF
I COULD TAKE HER
TO A SHOPPING CENTER
AFTER
WORK.
ABOUT 20
MINUTES IN
THE OPPOSITE DIRECTION
OF WHERE I
LIVE, I
TOLD HER IT WAS
TOO FAR OUT
OF MY
WAY.
SHE REPLIED
WITH A CURT,
ALRIGHT
THEN.
THE NEXT
DAY SHE BARELY
SAID A WORD
TO ME, AND
ANOTHER COWORKER
MENTIONED SHE'D
BEEN TELLING PEOPLE
I PROMISED
TO HELP HER AND
THEN BACKED
OUT.
WHICH NEVER
HAPPENED.
ALL I DID
WAS GIVE HER ONE
RIDE DURING BAD
WEATHER.
I DON'T
MIND HELPING OCCASIONALLY,
BUT I DON'T
WANT SOMEONE ASSUMING
I'M RESPONSIBLE
FOR THEIR
TRANSPORTATION, ESPECIALLY
WHEN IT'S
INCONVENIENT AND
SHE NEVER OFFERS
TO CONTRIBUTE FOR
FUEL OR ANYTHING
LIKE
THAT.
A FRIEND
TOLD ME I WAS
TOO ACCOMMODATING
AT THE START, AND
ANOTHER SAID I
SHOULD'VE JUST DRIVEN
HER TO AVOID
TENSION.
I GENUINELY
DON'T THINK
I DID ANYTHING WRONG,
BUT NOW
IT FEELS AWKWARD
AT
WORK.