MY NIECE,
WHO I'LL
CALL LENA, IS
ONLY 7,
AND WATCHING
HER GROW UP
HAS STARTED TO
FEEL LESS LIKE
NORMAL BABYSITTING
AND MORE LIKE
WATCHING A
SLOW
MOTION CRISIS.
I HELP
OUT BY WATCHING
HER A FEW AFTERNOONS
A WEEK WHEN MY
BROTHER EVAN AND
HIS WIFE CLAIRE
ARE WORKING,
AND WHILE
LENA IS SWEET,
FUNNY, AND
INCREDIBLY AFFECTIONATE,
HER RELATIONSHIP
WITH FOOD
IS DEEPLY UNSETTLING.
SHE'S ALREADY
WELL OVER 130
POUNDS
AND BARELY TALLER
THAN MY SHOULDER
WHEN I SIT DOWN,
AND
SHE IS CONSTANTLY
ASKING TO
EAT.
SOMETIMES
MINUTES AFTER
FINISHING A
FULL MEAL. FOOD
SEEMS TO BE
THE ONLY COMFORT
SHE'S EVER BEEN
TAUGHT.
AT HOME,
HER PARENTS
HAVE NEVER ENFORCED
ANY BOUNDARIES
AROUND EATING. VEGETABLES
ARE COMPLETELY OPTIONAL,
AND IN PRACTICE,
NON-EXISTENT.
CLAIRE LIKES
TO JOKE THAT
KIDS KNOW THEIR
BODIES, EVEN
WHILE LAUGHING
ABOUT LENA DRINKING
SO MUCH.
MILK
SHE THROWS UP.
THEY REGULARLY
MAKE SEPARATE
MEALS JUST
FOR HER. ALWAYS
PROCESSED AND
FRIED, WHILE
THE ADULTS EAT
SOMETHING ELSE.
I'VE
WATCHED HER EAT
AN ENTIRE FAMILY-SIZED
BOX OF
SYRUP-BRANCHED
SAUSAGE PANCAKES
IN ONE DAY
FOLLOWED BY
DESSERT BECAUSE
SHE CRIED
FOR IT NO
ONE SAID NO
NO ONE
EVER DOES WHAT
MAKES THIS WORSE
IS THAT LENA
HAS ALREADY STARTED
TALKING ABOUT
BEING TEASED
AT SCHOOL SHE'S
NOT EVEN IN
SECOND GRADE YET
AND SHE
KNOWS SHE'S DIFFERENT
I'VE
TRIED, GENTLY,
TO OFFER
HEALTHIER OPTIONS
WHEN SHE'S WITH
ME BUT
SHE REFUSES
EVERYTHING THAT
ISN'T BREADED,
SWEET,
OR SOAKED
IN SAUCE AND
I HAVE NO AUTHORITY
TO PUSH IT
FURTHER BECAUSE
HER PARENTS
IMMEDIATELY UNDO
ANY LIMITS
I SET ONCE
DURING
A FAMILY
GATHERING SHE
ATE AN ENTIRE
LOAF OF GARLIC
BREAD MEANT
FOR 10 PEOPLE
WHILE MY BACK
WAS TURNED WHEN
I CHECKED LATER
THAT
BREAD ALONE HAD
MORE CALORIES
THAN MOST ADULTS
NEED IN A FULL
DAY I'M
EXHAUSTED WORRIED
AND
HONESTLY STARTING
TO FEEL RESENTFUL
WHICH
MAKES ME FEEL
AWFUL BECAUSE
NONE OF THIS IS
HER FAULT BOTH
OF HER PARENTS
ARE THIN DISMISSIVE
AND DEFENSIVE
AND
I KNOW BRINGING
THIS UP COULD
EXPLODE INTO
A HUGE FIGHT
BUT
STANDING BY
WHILE THEY LAUGH
IT OFF FEELS JUST
AS WRONG. I
DON'T WANT TO SHAME
THEM OR HER.
I WANT
TO PROTECT A
LITTLE GIRL WHO'S
BEING SET UP
FOR A LIFETIME OF
HEALTH ISSUES AND
CRUELTY FROM
OTHER
KIDS.
IF I FINALLY
TELL MY BROTHER
AND HIS WIFE
THAT THEIR APPROACH
TO FEEDING THEIR
CHILD IS HARMING
HER, WOULD
THAT MAKE ME
THE BAD GUY?