DURING
A WEEKEND
GOLF TRIP
IN RIVERTON,
I GRABBED
DINNER AT
A BUSY LITTLE
SHARE PLATE
SPOT WITH
TWO LONG -TIME
PALS.
WE
ALWAYS ORDER
THINGS FOR
THE TABLE, PICK
A FEW DISHES
EACH, AND
SPLIT EVERYTHING
WITHOUT
DRAMA.
ONE
FRIEND CAN'T
HANDLE SHELLFISH,
SO
WE KEPT THE
MENU SIMPLE
AND
SAFE.
WHEN THE
FOOD SHOWED UP,
ONE OF
THE DISHES WAS
THIS SMOOTH
BAKED PASTA
WITH THE PERFECT
CRUNCHY CHEESE
LAYER ON
TOP.
THE
PART EVERYONE
USUALLY HOPES
TO SNAG
A BIT OF, BEFORE
ANYONE ELSE
COULD EVEN REACH
OUT.
VICTOR
SCOOPED OUT
THE ENTIRE GOLDEN
CRUST AND
SLID IT ONTO
HIS PLATE
LIKE IT BELONGED
TO HIM ALONE
I
SAID SOMETHING
IN A PLAYFUL
TONE HALF
JOKING HALF
SERIOUS LIKE
WHOA
WHAT
IS THAT MOVE
WHO TAKES
ALL THE GOOD
STUFF HE
LEFT AWKWARDLY
SLICED
OFF PART
OF THE CRUST
HE'D TAKEN
AND
DROPPED IT BACK
IN THE SHARED
BOWL WHICH
HONESTLY JUST
MADE IT WEIRDER
I
FIGURED THAT
WAS THE END
OF IT BUT
THE NEXT DAY
ON THE COURSE
HE BROUGHT IT
UP AGAIN AND
SUDDENLY WE
WERE IN A FULL
-BLOWN ARGUMENT
OVER BAKED
CHEESE LIKE
IT WAS A NATIONAL
CRISIS.
SO
NOW I'M WONDERING,
WAS I
OUT OF LINE
FOR CALLING
HIM OUT, EVEN
LIGHTLY?