I'VE ALWAYS
BEEN VERY STRICT
ABOUT HOW I
END MY DAYS.
ONCE I
GET HOME FROM
MY JOB, CHANGE
OUT OF MY WORK
CLOTHES, SHOWER,
AND SWITCH
INTO MY COMFORTABLE
HOME CLOTHES,
MY DAY
IS DONE. THAT
USUALLY HAPPENS
AROUND EARLY
EVENING, AND
EVERYONE CLOSE
TO ME KNOWS
THAT ONCE I REACH
THAT POINT,
I
DON'T GO BACK OUT
UNLESS THERE'S
A REAL EMERGENCY.
I DON'T
ENJOY LEAVING THE
HOUSE AFTER I'VE
UNWOUND, AND
I ONLY MAKE EXCEPTIONS
FOR SERIOUS
SITUATIONS.
ONE NIGHT,
NOT LONG
AFTER I HAD
ALREADY CHANGED
AND SETTLED IN,
MY FRIEND
MARK CALLED ME
HE
ASKED IF I
COULD DRIVE HIS
PARTNER LENA
HOME
FROM HER EVENING
SPORTS PRACTICE
LATER THAT
NIGHT I
ASKED WHY HE
COULDN'T PICK HER
UP HIMSELF AND
HE EXPLAINED
THAT HIS SUPERVISOR
UNEXPECTEDLY
MADE
HIM STAY LATE
AT WORK DUE
TO ISSUES EARLIER
IN
THE DAY I
REMINDED HIM
THAT I WAS ALREADY
DONE FOR THE NIGHT
BUT HE
KEPT PUSHING
SAYING
IT WOULD BE QUICK
I STILL
REFUSED BECAUSE
TO ME THIS
DIDN'T FEEL URGENT
OR UNAVOIDABLE
A
FEW HOURS LATER
CLOSE
TO MIDNIGHT MARK
SHOWED UP AT
MY PLACE VISIBLY
FRUSTRATED HE
TOLD ME LENA
HAD ENDED UP
WAITING NEARLY TWO
HOURS UNTIL
HE WAS FINALLY
ABLE TO LEAVE
WORK AND GET
HER.
I ASKED
WHY SHE HADN'T
ARRANGED A RIDE
THROUGH A TAXI
OR A RIDE SHARE
SERVICE.
AND HE
SAID SHE DIDN'T
HAVE ONE SET UP.
THAT DIDN'T
SIT RIGHT WITH ME.
BECAUSE IT
FELT LIKE A LACK
OF PLANNING ON
THEIR PART RATHER
THAN SOMETHING I
WAS RESPONSIBLE FOR.
FIXING.
THE SITUATION
APPARENTLY CAUSED
A MAJOR ARGUMENT
BETWEEN THEM
AFTERWARD.
FROM MY
POINT OF VIEW.
THERE WAS NO
IMMEDIATE DANGER.
THE WEATHER
WAS MILD FOR
THE TIME OF YEAR.
AND IT WASN'T
RAINING OR PARTICULARLY
COLD.
GROWING UP.
I OFTEN WAITED
LONG STRETCHES
FOR RIDES
IN FAR WORSE
CONDITIONS, INCLUDING
HARSH WEATHER,
AND IT WAS
CONSIDERED NORMAL.
BECAUSE OF
THAT, I'M
STRUGGLING TO SEE
WHETHER I TRULY
DID SOMETHING WRONG
HERE OR IF I
WAS SIMPLY HOLDING
A BOUNDARY
I'VE ALWAYS BEEN
CLEAR ABOUT.