AFTER
CHRISTMAS DINNER,
WHEN THE LIGHTS
WERE LOW, THE
TREE WAS STILL
GLOWING, AND
EVERYONE WAS
SETTLED IN THAT
WARM, OVERSTUFFED,
SLIGHTLY CHAOTIC
HOLIDAY MOOD,
MY EXTENDED
FAMILY DECIDED
TO PLAY OUR
USUAL CHRISTMAS
GUESSING GAME.
IT'S SOMETHING
WE DO ALMOST
EVERY YEAR.
EVERYONE WRITES
A CHRISTMAS-RELATED
WORD OR
PHRASE ON A
SLIP OF PAPER.
SONGS,
TRADITIONS, CHARACTERS,
FOLKLORE, TOSSES
THEM INTO A BOWL,
AND THEN
WE RANDOMLY TAKE
ONE TO SOMEONE
ELSE'S FOREHEAD.
HEAD THE GOAL
ISN'T REALLY TO
WIN IT'S
TO DRAG IT OUT
AS LONG AS POSSIBLE
PEOPLE
ASK RIDICULOUS
YES OR
NO QUESTIONS
MISUNDERSTAND
THE
RULES ARGUE
OVER TECHNICALITIES
AND THE
WHOLE THING USUALLY
DISSOLVES
INTO LAUGHTER FOR
REFERENCE EARLIER
IN THE GAME
I HAD WRITTEN A
NICE LIST
WHICH MY
UNCLE ENDED UP
GUESSING AFTER
A LONG GOOFY
STRUGGLE SO
EVERYTHING WAS
NORMAL UNTIL
IT WAS MY TURN
AS
SOON AS THE PAPER
WENT ON MY FOREHEAD
THINGS
FELL OFF
ONE
COUSIN SQUINTED
AT ME AND SAID
GENUINELY CONFUSED
I
DON'T EVEN KNOW
WHAT THAT IS
ANOTHER
PERSON SHRUGGED
AND SAID THEY'D HEARD
OF IT BUT DIDN'T
REALLY
GET IT I'D
IMMEDIATELY SET
OFF ALARM BELLS
IN MY HEAD
BECAUSE
THIS WASN'T
SUPPOSED TO BE AN
OBSCURE TRIVIA
CONTEST THEN
IT CLICKED MY
BROTHER IS OBSESSED
WITH OBSCURE
CHRISTMAS
LORE NOT
SANTA NOT
REINDEER NOT
HALLMARK STUFF
HE'S
INTO THE DARK
OLD EUROPEAN
FOLKLORE EVERY
YEAR HE BRINGS
UP WEIRD TRADITIONS
NO ONE ASKED
ABOUT AND
THERE'S ONE CHARACTER
HE TALKS CONSTANTLY.
SO I
SAID, HALF
JOKING, I
THINK I KNOW WHOSE
WORD THIS IS.
HE DIDN'T
DENY IT. I
ASKED MY FIRST
QUESTION.
AM I SOMETHING
YOU CAN HOLD
IN YOUR HANDS?
QUOTE, EVERYONE
SAID NO.
MY UNCLE
ADDED, I
STILL DON'T KNOW
WHAT THAT IS. THAT
WAS ENOUGH. I
DIDN'T EVEN NEED
A SECOND QUESTION.
I IMMEDIATELY
SAID, AM
I THE KRAMPUS?
QUOTE, I
WAS RIGHT. THE
GAME ENDED INSTANTLY.
I'D BARELY
STARTED, AND
THE ROUND WAS
OVER BEFORE
ANYONE COULD
STALL, JOKE,
OR ARGUE
ABOUT TECHNICALITIES
INSTEAD
OF LAUGHTER
THERE
WAS A LONG PAUSE
AND
THEN MY BROTHER
GOT GENUINELY
UPSET HE
SAID I'D RUINED
THE FUN THAT
HE'D BEEN EXCITED
TO WATCH PEOPLE
STRUGGLE TO
FIGURE OUT KRAMPUS
AND
THAT I TOOK THE
FUN OUT OF IT
BY GUESSING SO
FAST HE MADE
IT CLEAR HE
FELT LIKE I'D
SPOILED A CHRISTMAS
MOMENT HE
WAS LOOKING FORWARD
TO NOW
I'M STUCK WONDERING
IF I ACTUALLY
GRINCHED THE GAME
BY WINNING TOO
EFFICIENTLY OR
IF IT'S UNREASONABLE
TO EXPECT
SOMEONE NOT
TO CONNECT THE
DOTS WHEN THE
ANSWER IS AN
OBSCURE CHRISTMAS
THEME AND
ONLY ONE ONE PERSON
IN THE ROOM IS
OBSESSED WITH.
SO DID
I RUIN CHRISTMAS
GAME NIGHT?
OR WAS THIS
JUST AN UNFORTUNATE
CASE OF
KNOWING YOUR FAMILY
TOO WELL?