I'M
A WOMAN IN
MY MID -TWENTIES
WHO MOVED COUNTRIES
FOR WORK
LAST YEAR
AND QUICKLY FORMED
AN INTENSE
FRIENDSHIP
WITH A
COLLEAGUE A
FEW YEARS OLDER
THAN
ME.
SOMEONE
CONFIDENT
AND OUTSPOKEN
WHO FELT LIKE
THE OPPOSITE
OF MY PEOPLE
-PLEASING, ANXIETY
-RIDDEN
SELF.
AND WHEN
MY LONG -TERM
RELATIONSHIP COLLAPSED
RIGHT IN
THE MIDDLE OF
THE MOVE, SHE
BECAME MY
EMOTIONAL
ANCHOR.
A PERSON
I TALKED TO
FOR HOURS,
WHO LISTENED
TO EVERY DETAIL,
GAVE BLUNT
MAKE -UP
CALLS, AND
MADE
ME FEEL LESS
ALONE WHILE
I SPENT WEEKS
COEXISTING
WITH MY
EX IN THE SAME
HOUSE WAITING
FOR HIM
TO FINALLY LEAVE
THE
COUNTRY.
THE NIGHT
I DROPPED HIM
OFF FOR GOOD
I WENT
STRAIGHT TO
HER PLACE WHERE
WE LAUGHED
DRANK
AND
TALKED LATE
INTO THE NIGHT
AND
SHE EVEN GAVE
ME A HANDWRITTEN
LETTER TELLING
ME SHE BELIEVED
IN ME AND
THAT I'D BE
OKAY.
WHICH
MADE THE CRASH
THAT CAME LATER
FEEL EVEN
WORSE BECAUSE
WHEN I RETURNED
TO MY NOW
EMPTY HOME
AND TEXTED
HER ABOUT ONE
SMALL LINGERING
ANNOYANCE
RELATED TO
MY EX SHE
ABRUPTLY TOLD
ME SHE COULDN'T
ENGAGE ANYMORE
AND THAT I
WAS SHARING TOO
MUCH.
A
SENTENCE THAT
HIT LIKE A PUNCH
TO THE CHEST
BECAUSE MY
EX HAD ENDED
OUR RELATIONSHIP
BY SAYING
I WAS
TOO MUCH,
SENDING ME
INTO A PANIC
SPIRAL WHERE
I COULDN'T
BREATHE AND IMMEDIATELY
FEARED I
WAS
ABOUT TO
LOSE HER
TOO.
SHE EXPLAINED
SHE'D NEARLY DESTROYED
ANOTHER CLOSE
FRIENDSHIP
BY LETTING
EMOTIONAL
DUMPING GO
ON TOO
LONG AND
WAS TRYING TO
PREVENT THAT
HERE.
AND ALTHOUGH
I UNDERSTOOD
LOGICALLY,
EMOTIONALLY
I WAS
SHATTERED, SO
I ASKED
IF WE COULD TALK
THE NEXT DAY,
THEN SENT
A CAREFUL,
APOLOGETIC
MESSAGE ACKNOWLEDGING
I
HADN'T REALIZED
HOW MUCH PRESSURE
I'D PUT ON
HER AND SAYING
I HOPE
WE COULD STILL
BE CLOSE,
ONLY
TO BE MET
WITH SILENCE,
DAYS OF
BEING LEFT ON
READ WHILE
UPCOMING GROUP
DINNERS,
WORK
FRIENDSHIPS,
AND SHARED
TRAVEL PLANS
LOOMED IN
THE BACKGROUND,
LEAVING
ME STUCK REPLAYING
HOW JUST HOURS
EARLIER SHE
WAS CHEERING
ME ON
AND NOW I WAS
ALONE AGAIN,
WONDERING
IF LEANING
TOO HARD
IN THE EXACT
MOMENT MY
LIFE CRACKED
OPEN COST
ME THE ONE
FRIENDSHIP
THAT
MADE THE
BREAKUP
SURVIVABLE.