EVERY CHRISTMAS,
MY SPOUSE
AND I HOST
THE HOLIDAY AT
OUR HOME SO
OUR YOUNG CHILDREN
CAN STAY PUT,
OPEN
THEIR GIFTS,
AND ENJOY
THE DAY WITHOUT
BEING DRAGGED AROUND.
WE'VE DONE
THIS FOR YEARS,
AND IT'S
BECOME THE EXPECTED
ROUTINE FOR
HER SIDE OF THE
FAMILY.
BOTH OF
US ARE LIFELONG
VEGETARIANS.
NOT PREACHY
OR CONFRONTATIONAL,
BUT DEEPLY
UNCOMFORTABLE WITH
THE REALITIES OF
THE MEAT INDUSTRY.
WE DON'T
STOP OTHERS FROM
EATING WHAT THEY
CHOOSE.
WE JUST
DRAW BOUNDARIES
IN OUR OWN HOME.
MOST
OF HER RELATIVES
ARE ALSO VEGETARIAN,
BUT HER
FATHER AND
ONE SIBLING AREN'T.
IN PAST
YEARS, THEY
HANDLED THIS
BY COOKING THEIR
TURKEY AT THEIR
OWN HOUSE AND
REHEATING IT IN
OUR MICROWAVE. THAT
WORKED FINE,
BECAUSE WE
NEVER USED
THE MICROWAVE OURSELVES
AND DIDN'T
REALLY CARE. THIS
YEAR, HOWEVER,
THE MICROWAVE
BROKE, AND
SINCE WE HAVE NO
USE FOR IT,
WE DIDN'T
REPLACE IT.
NOW MY FATHER-IN-LAW
INSISTS THAT
THE TURKEY EITHER
BE COOKED OR
REHEATED IN
OUR OVEN INSTEAD.
I SAID
NO.
I EXPLAINED
THAT WE DON'T
WANT OUR OVEN OR
OUR AIR FRYER
USED FOR
COOKING MEAT,
ESPECIALLY SOMETHING
AS PUNGENT
AS TURKEY, BECAUSE
THE SMELL
ALONE MAKES
US UNCOMFORTABLE.
I EVEN
OFFERED A COMPROMISE.
IT COULD BRING
THEIR OWN AIR
FRYER OR MAKE
OTHER ARRANGEMENTS.
THAT SUGGESTION
WAS DISMISSED
AS UNREASONABLE,
AND I
WAS TOLD WE
WERE PUTTING SILLY
BELIEFS AHEAD
OF THE CHRISTMAS
SPIRIT.
I'VE TRIED
TO BE CLEAR THAT
WE ARE NOT BANNING
MEAT FROM OUR HOUSE.
THEY ARE
FREE TO EAT WHATEVER
THEY WANT HERE.
WE'RE SIMPLY
ASKING THAT
OUR OWN APPLIANCES
NOT BE USED
TO COOK IT. THE
PUSHBACK HAS
GOTTEN SO INTENSE
THAT I'M
HONESTLY CONSIDERING
BUYING A
NEW MICROWAVE
JUST TO AVOID
THE CONFLICT
ENTIRELY EVEN
THOUGH IT FEELS
UNFAIR TO
HAVE TO DO THAT
SO
NOW I'M STUCK
WONDERING WHETHER
HOLDING THIS
BOUNDARY MAKES
ME UNREASONABLE OR
WHETHER IT'S OKAY
TO SAY NO
EVEN
AT CHRISTMAS