I'M A
36-YEAR-OLD
WOMAN MARRIED
TO A 41-YEAR-OLD
MAN.
AND WHILE
OUR RELATIONSHIP
IS SOLID,
NIGHTS IN
OUR APARTMENT HAVE
TURNED INTO SOMETHING
I GENUINELY
DREAD BECAUSE
OF HIS COMPLETE
LACK OF
CONSIDERATION.
ONCE THE
LIGHTS GO OUT,
I USUALLY
FALL ASLEEP
FIRST.
AND LIKE
CLOCKWORK,
HE COMES TO BED
LATER AND IMMEDIATELY
RELEASES
A SERIES OF
THUNDEROUS,
EYE-WATERING
FUMES UNDER
THE COVERS WITH
ZERO ATTEMPT TO
RESTRAIN THEM,
VENTILATE, OR
REMOVE HIMSELF,
TO THE POINT
WHERE I'M GAGGING,
WIDE
AWAKE AND
FORCED TO
FLEE THE BEDROOM
JUST TO BREATHE
WHAT
MAKES IT WORSE
IS THAT HIS DOCTOR
EXPLICITLY TOLD
HIM TO CUT OUT
CERTAIN FOODS
AND TAKE MEDICATION
FOR THE
ISSUE ADVICE
HE'S CHOSEN
TO IGNORE ENTIRELY
WHILE
I GO OUT OF
MY WAY TO LEAVE
THE ROOM IF
I SO MUCH AS
FEEL DISCOMFORT BECAUSE
I DON'T WANT TO
SUBJECT
HIM TO THE SAME
THING HE
INSISTS IT'S
NATURAL THAT
MARRIAGE MEANS
ACCEPTING EVERYTHING
YET
SOMEHOW HE
NEVER BEHAVED
THIS WAY BEFORE
WE LIVED TOGETHER
AND STILL MANAGES
TO CONTROL HIMSELF
EVERYWHERE
ELSE EXCEPT
THE ONE PLACE
I'M TRAPPED IN
HALF ASLEEP AND
NOW NOW I'M BEING
MADE TO FEEL
UNREASONABLE FOR
ASKING HIM TO
AT LEAST STEP
INTO ANOTHER ROOM
OR MAKE
ANY EFFORT AT
ALL.
SO AM
I REALLY THE VILLAIN
HERE FOR WANTING
BASIC RESPECT
AT A NIGHT
OF UNINTERRUPTED
SLEEP?