MY SON,
WHO'S 23,
MOVED BACK
HOME TO OUR
SMALL TOWN
AFTER FINISHING
A TRAINING PROGRAM
AND STARTING
A NEW JOB
NEARBY.
HE'S BEEN
CLOSE FRIENDS
WITH A YOUNG WOMAN
NAMED LILA,
21, AND
ALTHOUGH THEY WEREN'T
OFFICIALLY DATING,
THEY'D BEEN
TALKING DAILY
WHILE SHE LIVED
SEVERAL PROVINCES
AWAY.
EARLIER THIS
FALL, SHE
LEFT HER COLLEGE
PROGRAM AND
WAS STAYING WITH
A RELATIVE, BUT
WHEN THAT RELATIVE
TOLD HER SHE
NEEDED TO MOVE OUT,
SHE HAD
NOWHERE TO
GO.
MY SON
PLANS TO MOVE
INTO HIS OWN APARTMENT
IN FEBRUARY
AND HAD
ALREADY SAID SHE
COULD LIVE WITH
HIM
THEN WHILE SHE
LOOKS FOR WORK
BUT SHE
NEEDED A PLACE
MUCH SOONER
SO
THEY BOTH ASKED
IF SHE COULD STAY
WITH US FOR A
COUPLE OF MONTHS
I
SAID YES
I DON'T
CHARGE MY KIDS
RENT SO
IT FELT UNFAIR
TO CHARGE HER
EITHER ALL
I ASKED WAS
THAT THEY BE CONSIDERATE
AND HELP KEEP SHARED
SPACES CLEAN
LILA
MOVED IN RIGHT
AFTER HALLOWEEN
AND
HONESTLY SHE'S
BEEN KIND AND
EASY TO LIVE
WITH SHE'S
STILL APPLYING FOR
JOBS BUT
SHE'S TRIED TO
HELP OUT BY COOKING
DINNER MOST
NIGHTS I
TOLD HER SHE DIDN'T
NEED TO BUT
SHE INSISTED
AND SHE'S GENUINELY
A GREAT COOK
ABOUT
A WEEK IN
SHE WANTED
TO MAKE A SPECIFIC
DISH BUT
WE DIDN'T HAVE THE
INGREDIENTS I
OFFERED HER MY
DEBIT CARD SO
SHE COULD GRAB WHAT
SHE NEEDED THAT
TURNED INTO HER
ROUTINELY DOING
THE GROCERY RUNS
WHICH
I DIDN'T MIND
AT FIRST BECAUSE
SHE ALSO PICKED
UP THE BASICS
FOR THE HOUSE
THEN
THE TRIPS BECAME
MORE FREQUENT
THREE
SOMETIMES
FOUR TIMES
A WEEK AND
SHE STARTED BUYING
THINGS I
DON'T NORMALLY INCLUDE
IN MY GROCERY
BUDGET LIKE
SPECIALTY INGREDIENTS
FRESH
SEAFOOD AND
PRICIER CUTS
OF MEAT WITH
SIX PEOPLE IN
THE HOUSE THAT
ADDS UP FAST
ON SUNDAY
WHEN SHE
LEFT FOR ANOTHER
GROCERY RUN
I ASKED
HER TO PLEASE MAKE
SURE SHE GETS
EVERYTHING FOR
THE WEEK SO WE'RE
NOT CONSTANTLY
BUYING EXTRA
SUPPLIES SHE
SAID SHE WOULD
THE NEXT
NIGHT AFTER DINNER
SHE
TOLD MY SON
SHE WANTED TO
MAKE A FANCY ROAST
LATER IN THE
WEEK BUT WOULD
NEED TO GO BACK
TO THE
STORE MY
SON IMMEDIATELY
TURNED TO
ME AND SAID
CAN YOU
GIVE HER YOUR CARD
I
TOLD THEM NO
I EXPLAINED
I HAD ALREADY
PAID FOR THE
WEEK'S GROCERIES
AND ASKED HER
TO PLAN AHEAD I
ADDED THAT A
DISH LIKE THAT
IS TOO EXPENSIVE
RIGHT NOW
AND
MAYBE WE COULD
MAKE SOMETHING SIMILAR
FOR A HOLIDAY
MEAL I
ALSO SAID
THAT IF SHE WANTS
TO KEEP COOKING
WHICH
I APPRECIATE
I'LL NEED
TO PUT A SPENDING
LIMIT IN PLACE
I
TOLD HER I
WISHED I'D MENTIONED
IT EARLIER LILA
LOOKED EMBARRASSED
AND
MY SON LOOKED
ANNOYED LATER
HE TOLD ME
I MADE HER FEEL
UNWELCOME WHEN
SHE WAS JUST TRYING
TO DO SOMETHING
THOUGHTFUL I
SAID
I APPRECIATED
THE GESTURE
BUT
SHE'S BUYING EVERYTHING
WITH MY MONEY
AND
I SIMPLY CAN'T
AFFORD MULTIPLE
SPLURGES
EACH WEEK I
ALSO REMINDED
HIM THAT HE'S
WELCOME TO GIVE
HER MONEY IF
THIS MEANS SO
MUCH TO HIM
HE
SAID THEY'RE ONLY
HERE FOR
A FEW MORE WEEKS
AND ASKED
WHY I COULDN'T
JUST MAKE OUR
GUEST
HAPPY.
I'M HONESTLY
NOT SURE
IF I HANDLED IT
POORLY OR IF
I'M JUST PROTECTING
MY BUDGET