I'M IN
MY MID-TWENTIES
AND SHARE AN APARTMENT
WITH A HOUSEMATE
I'VE LIVED WITH FOR
A WHILE. EVER
SINCE I WAS
A TEENAGER, I'VE
SLEPT WITHOUT CLOTHES
BECAUSE I OVERHEAT
EASILY AND
IT'S THE ONLY WAY
I CAN ACTUALLY
REST TIME. CAREFUL
ABOUT IT,
ANYTIME I
LEAVE MY ROOM,
EVEN JUST
TO GRAB WATER
OR HEAD TO THE
SHOWER, I'M
DRESSED OR AT
LEAST COVERED,
AND WE BOTH
NORMALLY KNOCK
BEFORE ENTERING
EACH OTHER'S
ROOMS THIS ROUTINE
HAS NEVER
BEEN AN ISSUE.
AND HE'S
ALWAYS KNOWN HOW
I SLEEP. THE
PROBLEM STARTED
WHEN HE INVITED
HIS PARTNER
TO STAY OVER
FOR A FEW NIGHTS.
WE'VE ALL
HUNG OUT BEFORE
AND GENERALLY
GET ALONG, BUT
THIS WAS THE FIRST
TIME THEY STAYED
OVERNIGHT.
ONE NIGHT
WE CAME BACK LATE
AFTER DRINKING,
AND EVERYONE
WENT STRAIGHT
TO BED. AT
SOME POINT IN
THE MIDDLE OF THE NIGHT,
HIS PARTNER
GOT UP TO FIND
THE BATHROOM AND
ACCIDENTALLY OPENED
MY BEDROOM DOOR
INSTEAD.
SINCE IT'S
RIGHT NEXT TO
IT, I
WAS HALF ASLEEP
AND BARELY
REGISTERED IT
BEFORE THE DOOR
CLOSED AGAIN. THE
NEXT MORNING,
BOTH OF THEM
WERE UPSET WITH
ME.
SHE WAS
UNCOMFORTABLE BECAUSE
SHE SAW ME
NAKED AND
THEY SAID I
WAS WRONG FOR
SLEEPING THAT
WAY AT ALL WHEN
THERE WAS A GUEST
IN THE APARTMENT
THEY
TOLD ME I
SHOULD START WEARING
CLOTHES TO
BED SINCE SHE'LL
LIKELY BE STAYING
OVER MORE OFTEN
I
TOLD THEM I
UNDERSTOOD THE
SITUATION WAS
AWKWARD BUT
I WAS IN MY
OWN PRIVATE ROOM
AND THE
DOOR WAS ONLY
OPENED BY MISTAKE
I
DIDN'T THINK I
SHOULD HAVE TO CHANGE
HOW I SLEEP
IN MY OWN SPACE
SINCE
THEN THINGS
HAVE ESCALATED
MY HOUSEMATE
KEEPS BRINGING IT
UP AND
ONCE HE EVEN
OPENED MY DOOR
ON PURPOSE WHILE
I WAS SLEEPING TO
CHECK WHETHER I
I WAS NAKED. THAT
CROSSED A LINE
FOR ME. I
DON'T FEEL EMBARRASSED
ABOUT HIM SEEING
ME, BUT
IT FEELS INVASIVE
AND UNNECESSARY. ESPECIALLY
WHEN THE
ORIGINAL ISSUE
CAME FROM SOMEONE
ENTERING MY ROOM
WITHOUT KNOCKING.
I STILL
DON'T THINK IT'S
REASONABLE TO
EXPECT ME TO
CHANGE WHAT I
DO IN PRIVATE
JUST BECAUSE IT
MAKES
HIS PARTNER
UNCOMFORTABLE.