I'M A
PARENT IN MY
LATE 30S
WITH TWO DAUGHTERS.
ONE OLDER
AND NEUROTYPICAL
AND ONE YOUNGER
WHO IS AUTISTIC.
THIS SITUATION
INVOLVES
MY YOUNGER CHILD.
SHE STRUGGLES
A LOT SOCIALLY
AND, DESPITE
ONGOING THERAPY,
SHE CAN BE
BLUNT, DISRUPTIVE,
AND UNINTENTIONALLY
CRUEL BECAUSE
SHE DOESN'T
UNDERSTAND SOCIAL
CUES WELL.
AT HER SCHOOL,
THERE'S A STRICT
RULE.
IF BIRTHDAY
INVITATIONS
ARE HANDED OUT
IN CLASS AND
THE WHOLE CLASS
IS INVITED, NO
ONE CAN BE EXCLUDED.
RECENTLY A
BOY IN HER
CLASS SOMEONE
SHE HAS A
LONG HISTORY OF
CONFLICT WITH
WAS HANDING
OUT INVITATIONS
AT SCHOOL MY
DAUGHTER CAME HOME
IN TEARS CONVINCED
SHE WAS THE
ONLY CHILD
NOT INVITED
HER
SPECIAL EDUCATION
TEACHER CONTACTED
ME AND SAID
THE SCHOOL COULD
INTERVENE SINCE
THE RULE WAS
VIOLATED BUT
I CHOSE NOT
TO ESCALATE
IT I
EXPLAINED TO
MY DAUGHTER THAT
SHE AND THIS BOY
DON'T GET ALONG
ASK
WHY SHE EVEN
WANTED TO ATTEND
HIS PARTY
AND
POINTED OUT HOW
UPSET SHE
WOULD BE IF SHE
WERE FORCED TO
INVITE SOMEONE SHE
DISLIKED.
SHE HAD
A MELTDOWN AND
SAID IT WAS UNFAIR.
BUT MY PARTNER
AND I AGREE THAT
FORCING ANOTHER
CHILD TO
INCLUDE HER WASN'T
RIGHT.
EVEN IF
IT HURT. LATER,
A VIRTUAL
MEETING WITH
THE TEACHER AND
THE BOY'S PARENT
REVEALED FAR
MORE.
THE BOY'S PARENT
WAS CONFUSED,
EXPLAINING THAT
THE PARTY WAS
SMALL AND ONLY
FOR CLOSE FRIENDS,
NOT THE
ENTIRE CLASS.
WHEN QUESTIONED,
THE BOY ADMITTED
HE HAD DELIBERATELY
MADE IT
LOOK LIKE EVERYONE
WAS INVITED
AND LIED TO
MY DAUGHTER, TELLING
HER SHE ALONE
WAS EXCLUDED.
HE SAID
HE DID IT TO
HURT HER BECAUSE
OF A SERIOUS
BULLYING INCIDENT
BEFORE WINTER
BREAK.
ONE THAT
HE NEVER REPORTED
BECAUSE HE FELT
NOTHING EVER HAPPENED
WHEN MY DAUGHTER
WAS INVOLVED. HEARING
THIS WAS DEVASTATING.
I APOLOGIZED
IMMEDIATELY, ASKED
THE SCHOOL TO
FORMALLY DOCUMENT
AND ADDRESS MY
CHILD'S BEHAVIOR,
AND REQUESTED
THAT THEY NOT
EXPLAIN THE
LIE TO HER SO
I COULD HANDLE
IT MYSELF. NOW
I'M CONFLICTED.
PART OF ME
BELIEVES SHIELDING
HER FROM CONSEQUENCES
HASN'T
HELPED HER LEARN.
AND PART
OF ME WONDERS
IF ALLOWING HER
TO SIT WITH THIS
PAIN MAKES ME
A BAD PARENT
INSTEAD OF A
REALISTIC
ONE.