I'M HONESTLY
STILL STUNNED
WRITING THIS.
EARLIER TODAY,
THE WATER IN
OUR APARTMENT WAS
SHUT OFF FOR
A SHORT REPAIR. NOTHING
DRAMATIC, OUR
LANDLORD SAID
IT WOULD BE BACK
WITHIN THE HOUR.
IN THE MEANTIME,
WE STILL
HAD A SMALL COUNTERTOP
FILTER FOR
DRINKING WATER
AND PLENTY OF
HAND SANITIZER.
I USED
THE BATHROOM FIRST
AND, LIKE
A NORMAL PERSON,
WASHED MY
HANDS USING
A BIT OF THE FILTERED
WATER.
WHEN MY
PARTNER FINISHED
USING THE
BATHROOM, SHE
WALKED STRAIGHT OUT
AND DROPPED ONTO
THE COUCH BESIDE
ME LIKE NOTHING
HAPPENED.
I ASKED,
CALMLY AT
FIRST, IF
SHE WAS GOING TO
WASH HER HANDS.
SHE LEFT
IT OFF AND SAID
SHE WASN'T WASTING
DRINKING WATER
ON THAT. I
SUGGESTED HAND
SANITIZER INSTEAD.
THAT'S WHEN
SHE CASUALLY
TOLD ME
SHE DIDN'T NEED
IT.
BECAUSE, ACCORDING
TO HER, SHE
DOESN'T WASH HER
HANDS EVERY
TIME SHE USES
THE TOILET. SHE
SAID AS LONG
AS SHE DOESN'T
SEE ANYTHING ON
HER HANDS. SHE
CONSIDERS THEM
CLEAN.
SOMETHING IN
ME SNAPPED. I
TOLD HER THAT WAS
GROSS AND AN
AWFUL HYGIENE
HABIT.
NOT SCREAMED
JUST BLUNT
I POINTED
OUT THAT EVEN
IF YOU'RE CAREFUL
YOU'RE
STILL TOUCHING
THE TOILET A
HANDLE THE
DOOR SHE
ROLLED HER EYES
AND SAID I WAS
BEING DRAMATIC
AND DIGITAL FOR
CONTEXT WE
DO HAVE A BIDET
WHICH
SHE INSISTS MAKES
THIS WHOLE THING
A NON-ISSUE
TO
ME IT
REALLY DOESN'T
NOW SHE'S
COMPLETELY SHUT
DOWN WON'T
SPEAK TO ME
AND SAYS
I OWE HER AN
APOLOGY FOR
SHAMING HER
MEANWHILE I'M
SITTING THERE WONDERING
HOW LONG THIS
HAS BEEN GOING
ON AND HOW
MANY SHARED SURFACES
OF TOUCH
WITHOUT KNOWING.
I'M NOT
TRYING TO CONTROL
HER.
I'M NOT
DEMANDING PERFECTION.
I JUST
CAN'T WRAP MY
HEAD AROUND BEING
TOLD THAT BASIC
HANDWASHING
IS OPTIONAL AND
BEING EXPECTED
TO PRETEND
THAT'S NORMAL.