I'M
IN MY MID
-TWENTIES AND
CURRENTLY LIVING
WITH MY GRANDPARENTS
WHILE FINISHING
SCHOOL AND
WORKING PART
-TIME, ALL
WHILE MANAGING
A LONG -TERM
ILLNESS THAT
ALREADY TAKES
UP MOST OF
MY
ENERGY.
THE
ORIGINAL PLAN
WAS THAT I
WOULD BE THE ONLY
ADULT GRANDCHILD
LIVING THERE,
WHICH IS WHY
I HAVE MY OWN
ROOM, WHILE
THE YOUNGER KIDS
SHARE
SPACE.
THAT BALANCE
WAS ALREADY
FRAGILE,
BUT EVERYTHING
GOT WORSE
WHEN MY YOUNGER
COUSIN, WHO
IS STILL A
TEENAGER, MOVED
BACK IN
AFTER REPEATEDLY
BURNING
BRIDGES
ELSEWHERE.
ELSEWHERE, SHE
HAS A LONG
HISTORY OF
CHAOS, REFUSES
TO TAKE
RESPONSIBILITY
FOR
HER ACTIONS,
AND REGULARLY
PLAYS
THE VICTIM
WHENEVER SHE'S
CONFRONTED.
OVER THE
YEARS, SHE'S
TAKEN MONEY
FROM BOTH
ME AND OUR
GRANDPARENTS, IGNORED
HOUSE RULES,
AND BROUGHT
CONSTANT
TENSION INTO
A HOME THAT
WAS ALREADY
STRETCHED
THIN.
HER
RELATIONSHIP
SITUATION HAS
ALWAYS BEEN
VOLATILE, BUT
RECENTLY IT
ESCALATED
WHEN SHE BECAME
PREGNANT BY
A PARTNER OUR
GRANDPARENTS HAD
EXPLICITLY BANNED
FROM THE HOUSE
DUE TO ONGOING
DISRESPECT
AND
CONFLICT.
EVEN
BEFORE THE
PREGNANCY, SHE
WOULD SNEAK HIM
IN LATE AT
NIGHT, DIRECTLY
VIOLATING
THEIR
RULES.
AFTER THE
PREGNANCY, HER
BEHAVIOR ONLY
INTENSIFIED.
EVERY OUTBURST,
EVERY INSULT,
EVERY RULE
BROKEN WAS
SUDDENLY EXCUSED
AS HORMONES,
AND ANY
ATTEMPT TO
HOLD HER ACCOUNTABLE
TURNED INTO
A DRAMATIC
MELTDOWN.
EVENTUALLY,
OUR GRANDPARENTS
WARNED
HER THAT IF THE
DISRESPECT CONTINUED,
SHE WOULD
BE ASKED TO
LEAVE.
THAT'S
WHEN SHE TURNED
HER ANGER TOWARD
ME.
IN THE
MIDDLE OF A HEATED
ARGUMENT, SHE
POINTED OUT
THAT I WAS OLDER
AND STILL LIVING
THERE, IMPLYING
THAT I SHOULD BE
THE ONE FORCED
OUT
INSTEAD.
SHE
KNEW FULL
WELL THAT
I SPEND MOST
OF MY TIME
EITHER IN
CLASS AT
WORK
OR AT
MEDICAL APPOINTMENTS
YET
SHE USED
THAT AGAINST ME
TOO SAYING
MY ROOM
WAS WASTED
SPACE THEN
SHE CROSSED
A LINE
AND SAID SHE
DESERVED MY
ROOM INSTEAD
BECAUSE SHE
WOULD NEED
IT MORE ONCE
THE BABY ARRIVED
IN
THAT MOMENT
YEARS
OF SWALLOWED
FRUSTRATION BOILED
OVER I
SNAPPED I
UNLOADED
EVERYTHING I
HAD BEEN HOLDING
BACK POINTING
OUT THAT
SHE HAD CHOSEN
TO LEAVE SCHOOL
COULDN'T
KEEP A JOB
BECAUSE SHE PRIORITIZED
PARTYING AND
WAS NOW DEMANDING
ACCOMMODATIONS
FROM
THE VERY PEOPLE
SHE REPEATEDLY
DISRESPECTED.
I
TOLD HER SHE
WAS ONLY STILL
UNDER THIS
ROOF BECAUSE
EVERYONE ELSE
HAD KEPT CLEANING
UP AFTER
HER.
MISTAKES.
THE ROOM
WENT
SILENT.
SHE IMMEDIATELY
BROKE DOWN,
ACCUSED ME
OF BEING HEARTLESS,
AND CLAIMED
I DIDN'T CARE
ABOUT HER
OR HER
CHILD.
EXHAUSTED
AND OVERWHELMED,
I TOLD HER
TO LEAVE ME
OUT OF HER LIFE
ENTIRELY AND
SHUT MYSELF IN
MY
ROOM.
SHAKING
WITH ANGER
AND
ADRENALINE.
WITHIN MINUTES,
I COULD HEAR
HER CRYING ON
THE PHONE TO
FRIENDS, PAINTING
ME AS A
MONSTER WHO
ATTACKED HER AT
HER LOWEST
POINT.
LATER,
ONE OF
THE YOUNGER KIDS
SAID MY WORDS
WERE HARSH,
BUT ALL
I COULD THINK
WAS HOW MANY
YEARS I
HAD TRIED TO
STAY CALM,
STAY
QUIET,
AND KEEP
THE PEACE WHILE
BEING CONSTANTLY
DISRESPECTED.
NOW THE
HOUSE FEELS
SPLIT, EMOTIONS
ARE RUNNING
HIGH, AND
I'M LEFT WONDERING
WHETHER FINALLY
SAYING EVERYTHING
OUT LOUD
SAVED MY
SANITY OR
BURNED A BRIDGE
BEYOND
REPAIR.