I'M TAKING
AN ONLINE
BIOLOGY COURSE
AT A SMALL
COMMUNITY COLLEGE,
AND OUR
FINAL LAB
ASSIGNMENT WAS
A GROUP
PROJECT.
WE WERE
SUPPOSED TO
FORM TEAMS
OF THREE,
PICK AN
EXPERIMENT
TO ANALYZE,
AND
PUT TOGETHER
A DIGITAL
PRESENTATION.
THE INSTRUCTOR
OPENED THE
SIGN -UPS ALMOST
FIVE WEEKS
BEFORE THE
DEADLINE, AND
I CONTACTED
MY GROUP
RIGHT
AWAY.
ONE OF
THE MEMBERS,
WHOM I'LL
CALL LENA,
BARELY RESPONDED
TO
ANYTHING.
SHE
CANCELED OUR
FIRST PLANNING
CALL TEN
MINUTES AFTER
IT WAS SUPPOSED
TO START
AND KEPT DISAPPEARING
FOR DAYS AT
A
TIME.
I UNDERSTAND
PEOPLE
HAVE BUSY
LIVES.
BUT SENDING
A QUICK UPDATE
ISN'T
HARD.
TWO WEEKS
BEFORE THE
PRESENTATION WAS
DUE.
THE OTHER
TEAMMATE AND
I HAD ALREADY
FINISHED OUR
SECTIONS.
ALL THAT
WAS LEFT
WAS LENA'S
SMALL
PORTION.
JUST TWO
SLIDES OUT
OF THE WHOLE
PROJECT.
I MESSAGED
HER
REPEATEDLY.
REMINDING
HER TO FINISH
HER PART SO
WE'D HAVE TIME
TO REVIEW
EVERYTHING.
NOTHING.
EVENTUALLY.
I SENT
A FINAL NOTE
SAYING I COULD
COMPLETE HER
SECTION
MYSELF.
BUT
IF I
DID.
I'D BE LEAVING
HER NAME
OFF.
MAGICALLY.
SHE
FINALLY
REPLIED.
PROMISING SHE'D
GET IT DONE THE
NEXT
EVENING.
SHE
DIDN'T.
AT THAT POINT,
WITH THREE
DAYS LEFT,
I FINISHED
HER SLIDES
MYSELF, REMOVED
HER NAME
FROM THE PRESENTATION,
AND SUBMITTED
IT
EARLY.
BEFORE DOING
SO, I
EXPLAINED THE
SITUATION TO
OUR INSTRUCTOR,
WHO SAID
SHE APPRECIATED
KNOWING ABOUT
GROUP MEMBERS
WHO DIDN'T
CONTRIBUTE.
SHE FORMALLY
REMOVED LENA
FROM THE TEAM
ROSTER SO
THE GRADE WOULD
ONLY REFLECT
THE WORK
ACTUALLY.
DONE.
NOW,
AFTER WEEKS
OF SILENCE,
LENA SUDDENLY
MESSAGED
OUR GROUP ASKING
WHETHER I ACCIDENTALLY
SUBMITTED
HER SLIDES
BLANK.
IT
BECAME OBVIOUS
SHE NEVER
SO MUCH
AS OPENED THE
DOCUMENT.
SHE DIDN'T
EVEN HAVE EDIT
ACCESS.
SHE
STILL HASN'T
ASKED WHY HER
NAME IS IT
ON THE SUBMISSION
AND SEEMS
COMPLETELY UNAWARE
SHE'LL
BE GETTING
A
ZERO.
I CAN'T
HELP FEELING
GUILTY.
THE ASSIGNMENT
WASN'T
HARD FOR ME
AND
I FINISHED
IT
QUICKLY.
LOSING
THESE POINTS
MIGHT SERIOUSLY
HURT
HER FINAL GRADE
BUT
AT THE SAME
TIME SHE
HAD ALMOST
A MONTH
IGNORED
EVERY REMINDER
AND
LEFT US HANGING
RIGHT UP
UNTIL THE
DEADLINE.
I'M
STUCK WONDERING
IF I WAS
TOO HARSH
OR
IF I SIMPLY
FOLLOWED THROUGH
ON A BOUNDARY
SHE CHOSE
TO
IGNORE.