I'VE BEEN
CLOSE FRIENDS
WITH THIS WOMAN
SINCE HIGH
SCHOOL.
ABOUT FIVE
YEARS
NOW.
ABOUT A YEAR
AGO, SHE
MET A GUY
WHILE WORKING HER
JOB AT A
CAFE.
HE WORKS
IN COMMUNITY THEATER
AND PICKS UP
PERFORMANCE -RELATED
SIDE
GIGS.
AND THEY
TALKED A HANDFUL
OF TIMES BEFORE
THEY HOOKED UP
ONCE.
AFTER THAT,
HE STOPPED MAKING
TIME FOR
HER AND KEPT GIVING
VAGUE
EXCUSES.
EVEN SO,
SHE BECAME
FIXATED
ON
HIM.
MY OTHER
FRIENDS AND
I KEPT TELLING
HER HE CLEARLY
WASN'T INTERESTED
AND THAT HER
ENERGY WAS
BETTER.
HER.
SPENT ON PEOPLE
WHO ACTUALLY SHOW
UP FOR
HER.
A COUPLE
WEEKS LATER,
SHE STARTED
SEEING ANOTHER
GUY WHO TREATS
HER REALLY
WELL.
STEADY JOB,
PATIENT PERSONALITY,
GENUINELY RESPECTFUL,
SHE TOLD ME
HE MADE HER FEEL
SECURE IN
A WAY SHE'D ALWAYS
WANTED.
EVERYTHING SEEMED
TO BE GOING WELL,
UNTIL THE
ACTOR REACHED
OUT
AGAIN.
THE MOMENT
HE MESSAGED
HER, SHE
FELL RIGHT BACK
INTO OLD FEELINGS
AND SAID SHE
FELT GUILTY
FOR LIKING THE
NEW GUY BECAUSE
HE JUST
ISN'T LIKE THE
FIRST
ONE.
I TRIED
EXPLAINING, AGAIN,
THAT THE
ACTOR HAS NEVER
SHOWN CONSISTENT
INTEREST AND
KEEPS MESSING WITH
HER
HEAD.
THEN SHE TOLD
ME SHE WENT TO
A CARD READER
WHO SAID SHE
AND THE ACTOR
WERE SPIRITUALLY
LINKED.
AND SHE'S
BEEN CLINGING TO
THAT.
I DIDN'T
JUDGE HER FOR USING
TAROT FOR
GUIDANCE.
I DO IT
OCCASIONALLY
MYSELF.
BUT SHE WAS
TREATING IT LIKE
DIVINE INSTRUCTIONS
RATHER THAN
PERSPECTIVE.
WHEN SHE
INSISTED THIS
MAN WAS DESTINED
FOR
HER.
I FINALLY
LOST
PATIENCE.
I TOLD HER
THAT THE IDEA
OF THIS ACTOR
ENDING UP WITH
SOMEONE HE BARELY
KNOWS FROM A
CAFE IS THE
KIND
OF STORYLINE
YOU SEE IN
DRAMAS.
NOT REAL
LIFE.
SHE WENT
QUIET SAID
NOTHING AND
HUNG UP I
DIDN'T MEAN IT
TO BE CRUEL I
WAS FRUSTRATED
WATCHING HER
GET HURT OVER
AND OVER BUT
NOW I'M WONDERING
IF I CROSSED
A LINE WAS
I WRONG FOR
SAYING SOMETHING
THAT BLUNT