I'M
STILL RATTLED
BY THIS,
AND THE
MORE I REPLAY
IT, THE
WORSE IT
FEELS.
MY SPOUSE'S
COUSIN, HER
PARTNER, AND
THEIR SON DECIDED
TO TAKE A
LAST -MINUTE
GETAWAY TO
A POSTAL RESORT
IN ANOTHER
COUNTRY.
WHAT THEY
DIDN'T BOTHER
TO DO WAS
TELL ANYONE
THEY WERE LEAVING
BEHIND HER
GREAT
-AUNT.
AN
88 -YEAR
-OLD WOMAN
WHO LIVES ALONE
IN THEIR DUPLEX
AND RELIES ON
A WALKER,
MEDICATION
REMINDERS,
AND DAILY
CHECK -INS
TO GET THROUGH
THE
DAY.
NO NEIGHBOR
WAS NOTIFIED,
NO SUPPORT
WAS ARRANGED,
AND NO
ONE IN THE EXTENDED
FAMILY WAS
WARNED.
LESS
THAN 12
HOURS AFTER
THEY LEFT,
SHE REALIZED
SHE COULDN'T
GET OUT OF
BED.
HER PHONE
WAS BARELY
WITHIN
REACH.
SHE STAYED
TRAPPED THERE
THROUGH AN ENTIRE
NIGHT AND
MOST OF THE
FOLLOWING
DAY.
TERRIFIED
AND DEHYDRATED,
WHEN SHE
FINALLY MANAGED
TO CALL, MY
SPOUSE SAID
I DROPPED EVERYTHING,
MISSED
OUR SHIFTS,
AND DROVE
NEARLY 8
HOURS THROUGH
WINTER WEATHER
TO REACH
HER.
BY THE TIME
WE ARRIVED, SHE
HAD BEEN IMMOBILIZED
FOR CLOSE TO
HOURS.
SHE WAS
HUMILIATED,
IN PAIN,
AND COVERED
IN SORES
FROM BEING
UNABLE TO
MOVE.
SEEING
SOMEONE
THAT FRAGILE
APOLOGIZING
FOR BEING
A BURDEN NEARLY
BROKE ME
WHAT
MAKES THIS
UNBEARABLE
IS THAT THE
COUSIN ABSOLUTELY
KNEW WE
WERE THE CLOSEST
FAMILY AND
HAD HELPED
BEFORE WE'VE
ALWAYS SAID
WE WOULD SHE
JUST DIDN'T
WANT TO DEAL WITH
IT BEFORE LEAVING
WHEN
CONFRONTED LATER
HER
RESPONSE WAS
COLD AND
DISMISSIVE
INSISTING
IT WAS ONLY
A FEW DAYS
AND CLAIMING
SHE ASSUMED
EVERYTHING WOULD
BE FINE NO
CONCERN NO
ACCOUNTABILITY
JUST
EXCUSES I
KEPT THINKING
ABOUT WHAT
WOULD HAVE HAPPENED
IF THE PHONE
HAD SLIPPED OFF
THE
BED.
WHEN
THE FAMILY FINALLY
ADDRESSED IT
ON A GROUP CALL
AFTER THEY
RETURNED.
SHE
TALKED OVER
ME, REFRAMED
EVERYTHING I
SAID, AND
DOWNPLAYED
THE
DAMAGE.
THAT'S WHEN I
SNAPPED.
I SAID
HER BEHAVIOR
TOWARD A
VULNERABLE RELATIVE
WAS SHAMEFUL
AND THAT I
COULD NOT
IMAGINE.
ABANDONING
SOMEONE WHO
DEPENDED ON
ME LIKE
THAT.
THE CALL
ENDED
ABRUPTLY.
SINCE THEN,
SEVERAL
RELATIVES HAVE
TURNED AGAINST
ME.
SAYING
MY WORDS
WERE TOO HARSH
AND THAT I OWE
HER AN APOLOGY
FOR BEING
DISRESPECTFUL.
WHAT
NO ONE SEEMS
WILLING TO
CONFRONT IS
THAT AN ELDERLY
WOMAN AND
WAS LEFT HELPLESS,
INJURED,
AND FRIGHTENED
BECAUSE SOMEONE
CHOSE CONVENIENCE
OVER RESPONSIBILITY
INSTEAD
OF OUTRAGE
OVER WHAT
HAPPENED TO
HER.
THE FOCUS
HAS SHIFTED
TO MY REACTION,
AS
IF THE REAL
PROBLEM IS
THAT I SPOKE UP
TOO LOUDLY RATHER
THAN THAT THIS
EVER HAPPENED
AT
ALL.