I'M
A WOMAN IN MY EARLY
40S,
AND MY
RELATIONSHIP WITH
MY YOUNGER BROTHER,
EVAN, HAS
ALWAYS BEEN DISTANT
RATHER THAN
OPENLY HOSTILE.
WE DIDN'T
HAVE A DRAMATIC
FALLING OUT,
WE JUST
GREW INTO COMPLETELY
DIFFERENT LIVES.
WE LIVE
IN DIFFERENT COUNTRIES
NOW, RARELY
TALK OUTSIDE
OF OBLIGATORY
HOLIDAY CHECK-INS,
AND I
HAVEN'T SEEN HIM.
HIS WIFE
MARINA, ARE
THEIR CHILDREN IN
PERSON IN ALMOST
10 YEARS.
I DON'T
HAVE KIDS, I
DON'T CELEBRATE
CHRISTMAS IN
A TRADITIONAL WAY,
AND MY
LIFE LOOKS NOTHING
LIKE THEIRS.
EVAN, ON
THE OTHER HAND,
ALWAYS WANTED
A LOUD, CHAOTIC
HOUSEHOLD, AND
HE GOT IT. BETWEEN
HIM AND MARINA,
THERE ARE EIGHT
CHILDREN, RANGING
FROM TODDLERS
TO TEENAGERS, SOME
OF WHOM I GENUINELY
WOULDN'T RECOGNIZE
IF I PASSED
THEM ON THE STREET.
YEARS AGO,
ONCE THE
NUMBER OF KIDS
PASSED THREE,
I MADE
A DELIBERATE CHOICE
ABOUT CHRISTMAS
GIFTS.
INSTEAD OF
TRYING TO KEEP UP
WITH INDIVIDUAL PRESENTS,
I STARTED
SENDING ONE
LARGE SHARED
GIFT FOR THE
WHOLE FAMILY.
SOME YEARS
IT WAS A BIG
BOARD GAME BUNDLE,
OTHER YEARS
IT WAS A SHARED
ENTERTAINMENT ITEM
MY
REASONING WAS
SIMPLE ONE
MEANINGFUL HIGHER
QUALITY GIFT
FELT MORE SINCERE
THAN SENDING
A PILE OF
CHEAP ITEMS THAT
WOULD BE FORGOTTEN
BY NEW
YEAR'S EVAN
NEVER COMPLAINED
OUTRIGHT SO
I ASSUMED
IT WAS FINE
THAT
CHANGED LAST
WEEK EVAN
CALLED ME OUT
OF THE BLUE SOUNDING
FRANTIC AND
EXHAUSTED HE
EXPLAINED THAT
MONEY WAS TIGHTER
THAN EVER THIS
YEAR AND SAID THE
KIDS WERE ALREADY
ANXIOUS ABOUT
CHRISTMAS
THEN
HE DROPPED THE
BOMBSHELL HE
WANTED ME TO
BUY INDIVIDUAL GIFTS
GIFTS FOR EACH CHILD
SO THEY
WOULD ALL HAVE SOMETHING
TO UNWRAP
WANTING
TO AT LEAST
CONSIDER IT
I ASKED
HIM TO SEND ME
THEIR WISH LISTS
WHEN
I OPENED THE
EMAIL MY
STOMACH DROPPED
NEARLY
EVERY CHILD
HAD REQUESTED
EXPENSIVE ELECTRONICS
SPECIALTY
GAMING GEAR
OR BRAND
NAME ITEMS
THAT WERE WELL
OVER 120
EACH
EVEN
CHOOSING THE
CHEAPEST OPTION
PER CHILD
WOULD HAVE PUSHED
THE TOTAL CLOSE
TO 1400
I
STARED
AT THE SCREEN
IN DISBELIEF
I'M
NOT WEALTHY
I'M NOT
CLOSE TO THESE
KIDS AND
I DON'T EVEN PARTICIPATE
IN CHRISTMAS
TRADITIONS MYSELF.
THE IDEA
THAT I WAS SUDDENLY
EXPECTED TO
BANKROLL AN
ENTIRE HOLIDAY
FELT UNREAL.
I CALLED
EVAN BACK
AND TRIED TO
BE GENTLE BUT
FIRM.
I TOLD
HIM I UNDERSTOOD
THEY WERE STRUGGLING,
BUT I SIMPLY
COULD NOT AFFORD
TO SPEND THAT
KIND OF MONEY.
I SUGGESTED
CHEAPER ALTERNATIVES
OR STICKING
WITH THE SHARED
GIFT TRADITION.
THAT'S WHEN
EVERYTHING BLEW
UP.
HE ACCUSED
ME OF BEING COLD,
SAID I
DIDN'T UNDERSTAND
WHAT IT'S LIKE TO
SEE YOUR KIDS DISAPPOINTED
ON CHRISTMAS
MORNING, AND
IMPLIED THAT
BECAUSE I DON'T
HAVE CHILDREN, I
HOARD MY
MONEY WHEN
I REPEATED
THAT MY FINANCES
WERE LIMITLESS
HE
SNAPPED CALLED
ME SELFISH
AND
HUNG UP ON
ME WE
HAVEN'T SPOKEN
SINCE NOW
I'M SITTING WITH
THIS HEAVY MIX
OF GUILT ANGER
AND
DISBELIEF
I FEEL
FOR HIS SITUATION
BUT
I ALSO FEEL
LIKE I'VE BEEN REDUCED
TO A DISTANT
RELATIVE WHOSE
ONLY ROLE IS
TO COVER WHAT
THEY CAN'T
AFFORD I
CAN'T SHAKE THE
FEELING THAT NO
MATTER WHAT I
GIVE IT
WILL NEVER BE
ENOUGH AND
THAT THIS YEAR
I WAS EXPECTED
TO SACRIFICE
MY OWN
FINANCIAL STABILITY
ABILITY TO KEEP
THE PEACE. SO
AM I REALLY THE
VILLAIN HERE FOR
REFUSING TO
SPEND A SMALL
FORTUNE TO
RESCUE SOMEONE
ELSE'S CHRISTMAS?