I'M IN
MY EARLY 30S
AND EXPECTING MY
FIRST CHILD WITH
MY PARTNER. WE
LIVE IN A COASTAL
CITY IN
ANOTHER COUNTRY
NOW, FAR
FROM MOST
OF OUR RELATIVES,
AND WHAT
SHOULD BE A JOYFUL
TIME HAS
BEEN COMPLICATED
BY LOSS.
MY PARTNER'S
STEPFATHER, WHO
HELPED RAISE HIM,
PASSED AWAY
ABOUT THREE
YEARS AGO. AS
MY PARTNER GETS
READY TO BECOME
A PARENT HIMSELF,
THAT ABSENCE
HAS BEEN HITTING
HIM HARD, AND
IT'S SHAPED ALMOST
EVERY CONVERSATION
ABOUT OUR
FUTURE.
I'M ABOUT
SEVEN MONTHS
ALONG, AND
WE'VE CHOSEN
NOT TO LEARN
THE BABY'S SEX
AHEAD OF TIME.
I STILL
WANTED US TO PREPARE
A SHORT LIST
OF NAMES SO
WE AREN'T SCRAMBLING
IN THE HOSPITAL.
THAT'S WHERE
THE CONFLICT
STARTED.
MY PARTNER
IS SET ON NAMING
THE BABY AFTER
HIS STEPFATHER.
IF THE BABY
IS A BOY, HE
WANTS TO USE
THE EXACT FULL
NAME.
FIRST AND
MIDDLE.
IF IT'S A GIRL,
HE WANTS
A FORCED, AWKWARD
VERSION OF
THAT SAME NAME.
EVEN THOUGH
IT ISN'T A REAL
OR COMMONLY USED
NAME, HE
WON'T CONSIDER
SIMILAR NAMES,
NICKNAMES, OR
VARIATIONS, AND
HE WON'T AGREE
TO USING IT
AS A MIDDLE NAME.
WHAT COMPLICATES
THINGS FURTHER
IS THAT HIS
STEPFATHER OPENLY
DISLIKED
HIS OWN NAME AND
COMPLAINED ABOUT
IT OFTEN BEYOND
THAT I
JUST DON'T LIKE
THE NAME AT ALL
AND I
HAD HOPED WE
COULD HONOR SOMEONE
FROM MY SIDE
OF THE FAMILY TOO
I
SUGGESTED A
COMPROMISE WHERE
WE USE HIS STEPFATHER'S
NAME AS A MIDDLE
NAME REGARDLESS
OF THE BABY'S
SEX BUT
MY PARTNER SHUT
THAT DOWN COMPLETELY
TO HIM ANYTHING
LESS THAN
A FIRST NAME
FEELS LIKE ERASING
HIS STEPFATHER'S
MEMORY HE'S
TOLD ME THAT IF
I DON'T AGREE HE'LL
CARRY RESENTMENT
FOR A LONG
TIME WHICH
FEELS LIKE A
LOT OF EMOTIONAL
WEIGHT TO PUT
ON ONE DECISION.
I UNDERSTAND
HE'S GRIEVING,
AND I DON'T
WANT TO BE CRUEL
OR DISMISSIVE
OF THAT. AT
THE SAME TIME,
I FEEL STRONGLY
THAT NAMING OUR
CHILD SHOULD BE
A SHARED DECISION.
NOT A
MEMORIAL THAT
OVERRIDES MY
FEELINGS ENTIRELY.
I'VE EVEN
THOUGHT ABOUT GIVING
IN NOW AND
ASKING FOR FULL
NAMING RIGHTS
IF WE EVER HAVE
ANOTHER CHILD,
BUT THAT IDEA
ALREADY MAKES
ME FEEL BITTER
AND SIDELINED.
I'M STUCK
BETWEEN WANTING
TO BE COMPASSIONATE
ABOUT HIS
GRIEF AND
WANTING TO PROTECT
MY OWN VOICE.
IN A
DECISION THAT
WILL FOLLOW OUR
CHILD FOR LIFE,
WOULD I BE
WRONG IF I REFUSE
TO USE HIS
STEPFATHER'S
NAME AS OUR BABY'S
FIRST NAME AND
INSISTED ON
A
COMPROMISE INSTEAD?