COMING HOME
FOR THE HOLIDAYS
WAS SUPPOSED TO
FEEL SAFE. I
JUST MOVED AWAY
FOR UNIVERSITY
A FEW MONTHS
AGO, AND
THIS WAS MY FIRST
TIME BACK SINCE
GAINING REAL
INDEPENDENCE.
I WAS
EXCITED, SLEEPING
IN MY OLD
ROOM, SEEING
FAMILY, RECONNECTING
WITH FRIENDS, SLIPPING
BACK INTO SOMETHING
FAMILIAR.
AND FOR
THE MOST PART,
IT WAS GOOD,
UNTIL CHRISTMAS
DINNER TURNED
INTO SOMETHING I
CAN'T STOP REPLAYING
IN MY HEAD. I
WAS ALREADY DRESSED
AND HEADING DOWNSTAIRS
WHEN MY DAD
STOPPED ME IN
THE HALLWAY. HE
DIDN'T SMILE.
HE DIDN'T
JOKE.
HE JUST
LOOKED AT ME. SLOWLY.
CRITICALLY.
AND SAID. YOU'RE
NOT WEARING THAT
TO DINNER. GO
CHANGE INTO SOMETHING
APPROPRIATE.
THE WORD
APPROPRIATE HIT
ME LIKE A SLAP.
I ASKED
WHAT HE MEANT. MY
OUTFIT WASN'T
REVEALING IN
ANY EXTREME WAY.
A FITTED TOP
AND A SKIRT
THAT HIT MID-THIGH.
BUT THE WAY
HE LOOKED AT ME
MADE MY SKIN
CRAWL.
HE DIDN'T
EXPLAIN.
DIDN'T JUSTIFY
IT.
DIDN'T EVEN PRETEND
THIS WAS ABOUT
ETIQUETTE OR
GUESTS.
HE JUST
SAID.
COLDLY.
THIS IS MY
HOUSE.
MY RULES.
THAT'S WHEN
IT CLICKED. IT
WASN'T ABOUT
DINNER.
IT WAS ABOUT
CONTROL.
I NEVER WOULD
HAVE WORN A SKIRT
THIS SHORT WHEN
I LIVED AT HOME.
I DIDN'T
FEEL ALLOWED TO.
STANDING THERE,
SUDDENLY AWARE
OF MY LEGS.
MY BODY.
MY ADULTHOOD.
I FELT EMBARRASSED
AND FURIOUS
ALL AT ONCE.
I FELT
LIKE I'D SHRUNK
BACK INTO A
TEENAGER WHO
NEEDED PERMISSION
TO EXIST COMFORTABLY
IN HER OWN
SKIN.
I TOLD
HIM IT WAS SEXIST
TO POLICE WHAT
I WEAR. I
SAID IT WAS HURTFUL
TO REDUCE ME
TO THE LENGTH OF
MY SKIRT INSTEAD
OF SEEING ME
AS HIS DAUGHTER.
A GUEST.
AN ADULT WHO
HAD COME HOME
EXCITED TO
BE WITH HER FAMILY.
I
TOLD HIM
LIVING ON MY OWN
HAD CHANGED ME.
THAT I WASN'T
WILLING TO BLINDLY
OBEY RULES
THAT FELT
ROOTED IN SHAME
ANYMORE.
HE DIDN'T
ARGUE.
YELL.
HE JUST STARED
AT ME. CLEARLY
OFFENDED.
CLEARLY UNMOVED.
SO I DIDN'T
CHANGE.
DINNER WAS
EXCRUCIATING.
THE ROOM FELT
TIGHT.
HEAVY.
LIKE EVERYONE
WAS HOLDING THEIR
BREATH.
CONVERSATION WAS
FORCED.
EVERY TIME I
SHIFTED IN MY
CHAIR.
I FELT
HYPER AWARE OF
MYSELF.
OF WHETHER
HE WAS STILL
ANGRY.
OF WHETHER
EVERYONE ELSE
THOUGHT I'D CROSSED
A LINE. I
KEPT MY HEAD HIGH.
BUT INSIDE
I WAS SHAKING.
SHAKING LATER
THAT NIGHT ALONE
IN MY CHILDHOOD
BEDROOM THE
ADRENALINE FADED
AND DOUBT CREPT
IN I'D
STOOD UP FOR MYSELF
YES
BUT
AT WHAT COST
MY DAD
AND I HAVE NEVER
BEEN ESPECIALLY CLOSE
AND
I CAN'T SHAKE
THE FEAR THAT
I MIGHT HAVE WIDENED
THAT DISTANCE PERMANENTLY
OVER A SKIRT
I
DON'T REGRET REFUSING
TO CHANGE
I REGRET
THAT IT CAME
TO THIS AT ALL
SO
NOW I'M STUCK
WONDERING WAS
THIS A NECESSARY
ACT OF INDEPENDENCE
OR
DID I CHOOSE THE
MOST PAINFUL POSSIBLE
MOMENT TO
DRAW A LINE