I WENT
OUT FOR LUNCH YESTERDAY
WITH MY OLDER
SISTER, A
CLOSE FRIEND OF
MINE, AND
HIS YOUNGER BROTHER,
WHO'S
12.
MY FRIEND
PICKED THE RESTAURANT
AND INSISTED WE
ALL SHARE A
GIANT BARBECUE
PLATTER.
EVEN THOUGH
MY SISTER AND
I BOTH WANTED
SOMETHING TOTALLY
DIFFERENT, HE
BRUSHED OFF WHAT
WE SAID AND ORDERED
THE BIG SHARED
MEAL
ANYWAY.
WHEN THE
BILL CAME, I
DIVIDED IT
BY FOUR AND
SAID HE SHOULD COVER
BOTH HIMSELF
AND HIS
BROTHER.
WHILE
MY SISTER
AND I COVERED
OUR OWN MEALS
HE
IMMEDIATELY GOT
IRRITATED AND
SAID THAT ALL ADULTS
SHOULD SPLIT THE
BILL INTO THIRDS
BECAUSE OBVIOUSLY
HIS LITTLE
BROTHER COULDN'T
CONTRIBUTE THIS
ISN'T THE FIRST
TIME HE'S TRIED
TO GET OTHERS TO
COVER THE KIDS
PORTION EITHER
MY
SISTER REMINDED
HIM THAT SHE
NEVER ASKED ANYONE
TO HELP PAY
FOR MY MEALS
WHEN I WAS YOUNGER
BUT
HE KEPT INSISTING
I ENDED
UP PAYING EXTRA
JUST TO AVOID
MAKING A SCENE
BUT
I WAS ANNOYED
ESPECIALLY
SINCE I
SPENT MORE THAN
I WANTED ON
SOMETHING I DIDN'T
EVEN CHOOSE
SHOES.
AFTER WE
LEFT, I
TOLD MY SISTER
I DIDN'T WANT
TO EAT OUT WITH HIM
ANYMORE.
I'VE SAID
THIS BEFORE, AND
I ONLY AGREED
THIS TIME BECAUSE
HE ORIGINALLY SUGGESTED
A BUDGET
-FRIENDLY
PLACE.
THEN CHANGED
THE PLAN AT
THE LAST MINUTE
TO SOMEWHERE MUCH
PRICIER.
HE OVERHEARD
ME, SAID
HE'D GIVE US
THE MONEY BACK,
THEN CALLED
US SELFISH
FOR EXPECTING
HIM TO PAY
FOR HIS OWN
BROTHER.
FOR CONTEXT,
I WORK IN
RETAIL, SO
MY INCOME ISN'T
EXACTLY
HIGH.
BOTH MY SISTER
AND MY FRIEND
ARE IN BETTER FINANCIAL
POSITIONS
THAN I
AM.
NOT WEALTHY,
BUT DEFINITELY
BETTER
OFF.
HE ABSOLUTELY COULD
HAVE COVERED HIS
BROTHER'S MEAL
WITHOUT ANY
TROUBLE.
WAS I WRONG
TO THINK HE SHOULD
PAY FOR THE KID
HE
BROUGHT?
ESPECIALLY SINCE
HE CHOSE THE
RESTAURANT AND
INSISTED ON
THE SHARED
MEAL?