I'M A TEENAGE
GIRL LIVING
BETWEEN TWO
VERY DIFFERENT
WORLDS, AND
THE TENSION IN
ONE OF THEM HAS
STARTED TO FEEL
UNBEARABLE.
MY DAD
MARRIED MY
STEPMOTHER YEARS
AGO, AND
AT FIRST SHE
SEEMED GENTLE,
ALMOST OVERLY
POLITE, LIKE
SHE WAS TRYING
HARD TO FIT
INTO OUR FAMILY.
BUT OVER TIME,
THAT SOFTNESS
HARDENED INTO
SOMETHING SHARP
AND WATCHFUL,
AND NOW EVERY
DAY AROUND HER
FEELS LIKE WALKING
THROUGH A ROOM
FULL OF TRIPWIRES.
THE CONTROL
CREPT IN
QUIETLY.
SHE STARTED
MONITORING MY
FOOD IN A
WAY THAT FELT OBSESSIVE,
INSISTING
I MEASURE EVERY
SPOONFUL OF
YOGURT OR CEREAL
BECAUSE MY
PORTIONS WERE
TOO GENEROUS
SHE
WOULD HOVER
WHILE I DID
IT CALM
VOICE TIGHT
SMILE ALWAYS
CAREFUL TO
STOP THE MOMENT
MY DAD WALKED
INTO THE ROOM
I
TRIED TO RATIONALIZE
IT SHE
TALKS CONSTANTLY
ABOUT DIETS
ABOUT
DOCTORS ABOUT
NEEDING TO
LOSE WEIGHT SO
I TOLD MYSELF
IT WASN'T REALLY
ABOUT ME STILL
IT WAS
HUMILIATING
ESPECIALLY
SINCE I'M
ACTIVE HEALTHY
AND
HAVE NEVER HAD
ISSUES WITH MY
WEIGHT IT
DIDN'T FEEL LIKE
CONCERN.
IT FELT
LIKE SURVEILLANCE.
WHAT MAKES
IT WORSE IS
HOW SHE COMMUNICATES.
MY MOM
IS DIRECT. IF
THERE'S A PROBLEM,
WE TALK.
SOMETIMES ARGUE,
BUT IT ENDS
WITH CLARITY.
MY STEPMOTHER
DOES THE OPPOSITE.
SHE'LL SAY
SOMETHING CUTTING
IN THE CALMEST
TONE IMAGINABLE,
THEN RETREAT
INTO HER BEDROOM
LIKE NOTHING HAPPENED.
THE NEXT
DAY, I'LL
WAKE UP TO A
LONG, PERFECTLY
STRUCTURED MESSAGE
DETAILING EVERYTHING
I DID WRONG
AND HOW IT MADE
HER FEEL. NO
DISCUSSION.
NO CHANCE
TO RESPOND. JUST
A VERDICT. THERE'VE
BEEN SO MANY
SMALL MOMENTS
THAT PILED
UP INTO SOMETHING
HEAVY.
PUPPY.
SHE ONCE DECIDED
MY YOUNGER
BROTHER AND
I WEREN'T NEEDED
WHEN MY DAD
WENT TO PICK UP
A NEW PUPPY. EVEN
THOUGH I WAS COUNTING
DOWN THE DAYS
AND COULD BARELY SLEEP
FROM EXCITEMENT. SHE
REGULARLY CHECKS
MY SCHOOL RECORDS
AND MY DAD'S
EMAILS ABOUT ME.
THEN PROMPTS
HIM TO HAVE
A TALK WITH
ME.
EVEN THOUGH
MY GRADES ARE
STRONG AND THERE'S
NOTHING TO HIDE.
IT FEELS
LIKE SHE'S CONSTANTLY
LOOKING FOR
SOMETHING TO FIX.
SOMETHING TO
CORRECT.
TIGHTEN HER GRIP
AROUND.
THE EXPLOSION
HAPPENED IN
A CAR RIDE THAT
SHOULD HAVE BEEN ORDINARY.
SHE STARTED
IN AGAIN ABOUT
MY LUNCH. SAYING
I PACKED TOO
MUCH FOOD
AND NEEDED TO BE
MORE MINDFUL
SOMETHING
INSIDE ME
FINALLY BROKE
I TOLD
HER OUT
LOUD THAT
I WAS GLAD SHE
WASN'T MY PARENT
AND THAT SHE NEVER
WOULD BE THE
WORDS FELT HARSH
BUT ALSO
LIKE THE TRUTH
RIPPING ITS WAY
OUT AFTER BEING
SWALLOWED FOR
TOO LONG SINCE
THEN MY
DAD SAYS SHE'S
BACKING OFF BUT
IT DOESN'T FEEL
THAT WAY SHE
STILL MONITORS
FROM THE SHADOWS
STILL
COMMENTS WHEN
HE'S NOT AROUND
STILL
ACTS LIKE SHE
HAS AUTHORITY OVER
MY BODY MY
SCHOOL MY
LIFE I
FEEL BOXED
IN JUDGED
AND
CONSTANTLY BRACING
MYSELF IN
MY OWN HOME
I KEEP ASKING
MYSELF IF
I WENT TOO FAR,
IF I
SHOULD HAVE BEEN GENTLER,
IF THIS
IS JUST TEENAGE
EMOTION COLLIDING
WITH A DIFFICULT
FAMILY DYNAMIC.
BUT HOW
LONG AM I SUPPOSED
TO STAY QUIET
WHILE SOMEONE INSISTS
ON PARENTING
ME WITHOUT EVER
MAKING ME
FEEL SAFE
OR RESPECTED?
AND WAS
I REALLY WRONG
FOR FINALLY SAYING
IT OUT LOUD?