EVERY DECEMBER,
MY MOTHER
TURNS OUR HOUSE
INTO A SHRINE
TO TOGETHERNESS.
GARLANDS ON
THE STAIRS, CANDLES
IN EVERY WINDOW,
THE SAME OLD
RECORDS PLAYING
ON REPEAT. CHRISTMAS
IS HER SACRED
SEASON.
THE TIME
WHEN SHE BELIEVES
ALL WOUNDS
SHOULD MAGICALLY
CLOSE IF
WE JUST SIT AT
THE SAME TABLE
AND SMILE
HARD ENOUGH.
FOR YEARS,
I WENT ALONG
WITH IT. EVEN
WHEN IT MEANT SWALLOWING
COMMENTS AND
INSULTS FROM
A CLOSE RELATIVE
AND HER SPOUSE
WHO HAVE NEVER
APPROVED OF
MY LIFE. THEY
MADE IT CLEAR
THEY DESPISED
THAT I WAS DIVORCED.
THAT I WAS RAISING
MY CHILD ALONE.
AND THAT I
DIDN'T FIT THEIR
IDEA OF WHAT
A PROPER FAMILY
SHOULD LOOK LIKE.
STILL, EVERY
CHRISTMAS, I
SHOWED UP WITH
GIFTS AND GOOD
MANNERS.
TELLING MYSELF
IT WAS FOR MY
MOM.
A BREAKING
POINT CAME
AFTER MY FATHER
DIED.
RIGHT IN
THE MIDDLE OF WINTER.
WHEN GRIEF
WAS ALREADY HANGING
OVER EVERYTHING
LIKE COLD
FOG.
INSTEAD OF
PULLING TOGETHER, THAT
SAME RELATIVE
AND HER PARTNER
SPREAD UGLY
STORIES ABOUT
ME AND QUESTIONED
MY PARENTING
BEHIND MY
BACK.
ALL WHILE CHRISTMAS
DECORATIONS WERE
STILL UP. AFTER
THAT, THEY
STOPPED SPEAKING
TO ME ENTIRELY
UNLESS IT
WAS UNAVOIDABLE.
MONTHS PASSED,
HOLIDAYS CAME
AND WENT, I
SPENT MORE TIME
IN THERAPY
THAN SHOPPING MALLS,
TRYING
TO UNDO THE
DAMAGE THEY'D
CAUSED.
EVENTUALLY, I
ACCEPTED THAT
PEACE DIDN'T
EXIST WITH THEM
IN MY LIFE,
AND I STEPPED
AWAY FROM
MY OWN SANITY,
EVEN IF
IT DISAPPOINTED MY
MOTHER.
THIS CHRISTMAS
WAS THE FIRST
TIME I RETURNED
TO MY MOM'S
HOUSE IN NEARLY
A YEAR. I
TOLD MYSELF I'D
KEEP IT QUIET,
JUST LIGHTS,
FOOD, AND
TIME WITH HER
AND MY CHILD.
WITHIN HOURS
OF ARRIVING,
THE RELATIVE'S
SPOUSE SHOWED UP
UNEXPECTEDLY, UNEXPECTEDLY. DROPPING
OFF THEIR KIDS
LIKE NOTHING WAS
WRONG.
NO GREETING.
NO APOLOGY.
JUST TENSION
THICK ENOUGH
TO CUT THROUGH
THE TINSEL. I
LATER FOUND
OUT THEY'D LEFT
A WRAPPED PRESENT
FOR ME UNDER THE
TREE.
MY NAME
WRITTEN NEATLY AS
IF NONE OF THE PAST
HAD HAPPENED. I
DIDN'T TOUCH IT.
TO ME, IT
FELT LIKE A
PERFORMANCE.
NOT PEACE.
WHEN MY MOTHER
ASKED IF I
HAD BOUGHT A GIFT
FOR THAT RELATIVE.
I SAID
NO.
I WASN'T
GOING TO SPEND MONEY,
ENERGY,
OR EMOTION
PRETENDING
CHRISTMAS HAD
ERASED YEARS OF
CRUELTY.
MY MOTHER'S
FACE FELL. SHE
SAID I WAS
RUINING THE HOLIDAY
SPIRIT.
THAT CHRISTMAS
IS ABOUT FORGIVENESS.
THAT I
WAS BEING STUBBORN
AND DRAMATIC. BUT
STANDING IN
THAT GLOWING LIVING
ROOM.
SURROUNDED BY
LIGHTS AND ORNAMENTS
MEANT TO SYMBOLIZE
LOVE.
ALL I COULD
THINK WAS HOW TIRED
I WAS OF BEING
THE ONLY ONE
EXPECTED TO
MAKE THINGS NICE
FOR THE SAKE
OF THE SEASON.