MY
SON, LUCA,
16,
WAS IN
A DEVASTATING
CRASH LAST
WEEK WHEN
ANOTHER DRIVER
VEERED INTO
HIS LANE
AND CRUSHED
THE SIDE
OF
HIS TINY
HATCHBACK.
THE DOCTOR
SAID MORE
THAN ONCE
THAT THE OUTCOME
COULD HAVE BEEN
FAR
WORSE.
HE
ENDED UP
IN A HOSPITAL
BED WITH
CASTS, STITCHES,
BRUISES
EVERYWHERE, AND
A LOOK IN HIS
EYES I
HADN'T SEEN
SINCE HE WAS
A
CHILD.
FRIGHTENED,
EXHAUSTED, AND
BARELY HOLDING
HIMSELF
TOGETHER.
MY
PARTNER, MARA,
47,
OUR YOUNGER
CHILD ELISE,
13.
AND I
ARRIVED AS
SOON AS WE
COULD.
THE ROOM
WAS BUZZING
WITH
NURSES.
EPING
MONITORS.
AND THE SMELL
OF
ANTISEPTIC.
LUCA TRIED
TO PUT ON
A BRAVE
FACE.
BUT EVERY
TINY MOVEMENT
MADE HIM
WINCE.
WE WERE
TALKING QUIETLY
TO HIM WHEN
HIS GIRLFRIEND
MIRA SHOWED
UP.
STILL
IN HER WORK
CLOTHES.
OUT OF
BREATH.
CLEARLY
SHAKEN.
THE MOMENT
SHE SAW
HIM.
SHE DIDN'T
HESITATE.
SHE RUSHED
TO HIS
BED.
PUFFED HIS
FACE.
KISSED
HIS
CHEEKS.
FOREHEAD.
HAIR.
AND FINALLY
HIS
LIPS.
TEARS
STREAMING DOWN
HER FACE
AS SHE WHISPERED
HOW SCARED SHE
HAD
BEEN.
IN.
LUCAS'
WHOLE BODY LOOSENED,
LIKE HE HAD
JUST BEEN GIVEN
THE ONE THING
THAT MADE HIM
FEEL
SAFE.
SHE STAYED
THERE FOR
HOURS.
HOLDING
HIS HAND,
SMOOTHING
HIS HAIR,
HELPING ADJUST
HIS PILLOWS,
ALMOST
AS IF SHE
REFUSED
TO LET HIM DRIFT
BACK INTO
FEAR.
WHEN
WE DROVE HOME
THAT NIGHT,
THE ATMOSPHERE
IN THE CAR
CHANGED
INSTANTLY.
MARA
SAT RIGID,
STARING
STRAIGHT AHEAD
BEFORE FINALLY
SAYING THAT
THE ENTIRE SCENE
HAD MADE HER
UNCOMFORTABLE.
SHE
SAID IT FELT
STRANGE WATCHING
THAT LEVEL
OF
AFFECTION.
THAT IT
LOOKED TOO INTIMATE,
TOO
EMOTIONAL, TOO
MUCH IN FRONT
OF
FAMILY.
I TOLD
HER THAT LUCA
HAD NEARLY
DIED THAT
NIGHT.
THAT MIRA
SEEMED TO
BE THE ONLY THING
THAT GROUNDED
HIM.
THAT THE WAY
HE CLUNG TO
HER HAND TOLD
ME EVERYTHING I
NEEDED TO KNOW
ABOUT WHAT COMFORT
LOOKED LIKE
FOR HIM RIGHT
NOW.
MARA'S TONE
SHIFTED FROM
UNEASY TO
FURIOUS.
SHE
SAID I SHOULD
HAVE STEPPED
IN.
THAT I
SHOULD HAVE TOLD
MIRA TO
GIVE HIM
SPACE.
OR EVEN
SENT HER HOME
ALTOGETHER.
SHE INSISTED
IT WAS
INAPPROPRIATE.
TOO MUCH
AND THAT I
WAS LETTING THINGS
GET OUT OF
CONTROL.
I
TOLD HER I
WOULDN'T TAKE
AWAY SOMETHING
THAT WAS
CLEARLY HELPING
OUR SON BREATHE
AGAIN AFTER
THE MOST
TERRIFYING NIGHT
OF HIS LIFE
SHE
SAID I WASN'T
DOING MY JOB
AS A PARENT
I
SAID MY JOB
WAS TO LET
MY INJURED SON
FEEL SAFE
NEITHER
OF US BUDGED
NOW THE
HOUSE FEELS
STRANGELY QUIET
LUCA
KEEPS ASKING
WHEN MIRA
CAN VISIT
AGAIN MARA
AVOIDS THE
TOPIC ENTIRELY
AND
I'M STUCK REPLAYING
THE NIGHT IN MY
HEAD WONDERING
IF SHOWING COMPASSION
CAN REALLY
BE THE WRONG
CHOICE OR
IF THIS WAS
ABOUT SOMETHING
DEEPER
THAN NEITHER OF
US WANTED TO
NAME