I'M A
38-YEAR-OLD
MAN WHO HOSTS
OUR EXTENDED FAMILY'S
CHRISTMAS EVE GATHERING
EVERY YEAR.
IT'S A
BIG, LOUD
TRADITION WITH
LOTS OF RELATIVES,
FOOD,
KIDS RUNNING
AROUND, AND
PEOPLE COMING
AND GOING ALL
NIGHT.
I HOST
BECAUSE MY HOUSE
IS THE LARGEST.
IT'S CENTRALLY
LOCATED, AND
FOR YEARS IT'S
JUST BEEN UNDERSTOOD
THAT CHRISTMAS
HAPPENS HERE.
IT'S STRESSFUL,
EXPENSIVE, AND
EXHAUSTING, BUT
I DO IT BECAUSE
IT MATTERS TO
MY FAMILY. LAST
YEAR, A
RELATIVE OF
MINE SHOWED UP
WITH A SERVICE DOG
IN TRAINING. I
WAS TOLD THE
DOG WAS STILL
VERY YOUNG
BARELY
OVER A YEAR
OLD AND
I DIDN'T REALLY
KNOW WHAT TO EXPECT
I'VE
NEVER OWNED DOGS
AND DON'T HAVE MUCH
EXPERIENCE WITH
THEM, ESPECIALLY
NOT IN
A CROWDED HOUSE
FULL OF CHILDREN
FOOD
AND NOISE
UNFORTUNATELY,
IT DIDN'T
GO WELL THE
DOG HAD MULTIPLE
ACCIDENTS IN
MY HOUSE CAUSED
DISRUPTIONS
AND THERE
WAS ONE INCIDENT
INVOLVING MY
CHILD THAT
REALLY CROSSED A
LINE FOR ME I
LATER FOUND OUT
I WASN'T THE ONLY
ONE UNCOMFORTABLE
ANOTHER
FAMILY MEMBER
QUIETLY COMPLAINED
TO ME AS WELL
AFTER
THAT HOLIDAY
DAY, I DECIDED
I DIDN'T WANNA
REPEAT.
A FEW WEEKS
AGO, WHILE
PLANNING THIS
YEAR'S PARTY, I
CASUALLY ASKED
AROUND WHETHER
THAT SAME RELATIVE
WOULD BE ATTENDING.
I WAS
TOLD BY MULTIPLE
PEOPLE THAT
SHE WOULDN'T BE THERE,
SO I ASSUMED
THE ISSUE HAD
RESOLVED ITSELF.
THEN, JUST
DAYS AGO, I
WAS SUDDENLY INFORMED
THAT SHE WAS
COMING AFTER ALL.
REALIZING I
NEEDED TO ADDRESS
IT IMMEDIATELY, I
CALLED HER AND
TOLD HER SHE WAS
ABSOLUTELY WELCOME
TO ATTEND. BUT
THE DOG WAS NOT.
I EXPLAINED
THAT LAST YEAR'S
EXPERIENCE WASN'T
SOMETHING I WAS
WILLING TO REPEAT
IN MY OWN HOME.
ESPECIALLY
WITH KIDS
AND A LARGE CROWD.
I TRIED TO
BE CALM AND
STRAIGHTFORWARD.
NOT CRUEL.
THAT SINGLE
CONVERSATION
DETONATED
THE ENTIRE HOLIDAY.
HER PARENTS
AND SIBLINGS IMMEDIATELY
THREATENED
TO BOYCOTT CHRISTMAS
ALTOGETHER.
I WAS ACCUSED
OF BEING HEARTLESS,
DISCRIMINATORY,
AND SELFISH,
IN AN ATTEMPT
TO COMPROMISE.
I EVEN
OFFERED TO LET
THE DOG STAY OUTSIDE
DURING THE
EVENT.
BUT
I WAS TOLD THAT
SUGGESTION WAS
OFFENSIVE AND
COMPLETELY UNREASONABLE.
REASONABLE.
NOW THE
FAMILY GROUP CHATS
ARE EXPLODING,
PEOPLE ARE
TAKING SIDES,
AND I'M BEING
BLAMED FOR POTENTIALLY
CANCELLING
CHRISTMAS EVE
ALTOGETHER.
I FEEL
LIKE I'M BEING PUNISHED
FOR SETTING A
BOUNDARY IN
MY OWN HOME
AFTER A GENUINELY
BAD EXPERIENCE
LAST YEAR.
I'M EXHAUSTED,
FRUSTRATED, AND
HONESTLY SHOCKED
AT HOW FAST
THIS SPIRALED.
SO AM
I REALLY THE VILLAIN
FOR NOT WANTING
AN UNTRAINED
SERVICE DOG INSIDE
MY HOUSE DURING
CHRISTMAS?