I SHARE
AN APARTMENT WITH
TWO ROOMMATES.
AND ONE
NIGHT ONE OF
THEM STAGGERED
IN LATE, DRAMATIC
AND ANNOYED,
ANNOUNCING THEY
HAD FORGOTTEN THEIR
WALLET AT WORK.
THEY IMMEDIATELY
ASKED IF
THEY COULD EAT MY FOOD
JUST THIS ONCE
AS IF IT WERE
A TINY FAVOR
AND NOT
THE MEALS I
HAD CAREFULLY PLANNED
FOR THE ENTIRE
WEEK.
I SHOP
INTENTIONALLY, BUYING
SPECIFIC ITEMS
FROM PLACES
LIKE FRESHWAY
MARKET AND
MEALCRAFT FOODS.
AND I
RELY ON THAT
FOOD TO GET
ME THROUGH BUSY DAYS.
FACE.
WHEN I
SAID NO, THE
AIR IN THE ROOM
SHIFTED INSTANTLY.
LIKE I'D
COMMITTED SOME KIND
OF PERSONAL BETRAYAL
INSTEAD OF
SETTING A BOUNDARY.
THEY SNAPPED BACK
THAT I WAS PETTY
AND ACCUSED ME
OF BEING A BAD
FRIEND.
THEN SULKED
LOUDLY WHILE SCROLLING
ON THEIR PHONE.
I EVEN
POINTED OUT THAT
THERE WAS BREAD
AND BASIC SANDWICH
STUFF AVAILABLE.
PERFECTLY FINE
FOR ONE NIGHT.
BUT THAT APPARENTLY
WASN'T GOOD
ENOUGH.
INSTEAD, THEY
ORDERED OVERPRICED
TAKEOUT FROM
A PLACE CALLED
RED BOWL KITCHEN
AND MADE SURE
I KNEW HOW OFFENDED
THEY WERE THE ENTIRE
TIME IT ARRIVED.
THE TENSION
LINGERED LONG
AFTER THE FOOD
WAS GONE THICK
AND UNCOMFORTABLE
THE
NEXT DAY THINGS
ESCALATED
I FOUND
OUT THEY'D COMPLAIN
TO OUR OTHER
ROOMMATE FRAMING
THE STORY
AS IF I'D HEARTLESSLY
REFUSED TO
HELP SOMEONE IN
NEED SINCE
THEN I'VE
BEEN MET WITH SIDE
EYES AWKWARD
SILENCE
AND
AN UNSPOKEN
VERDICT HANGING
OVER THE APARTMENT
WHAT
MAKES THIS THING
MORE IS THAT
EVERY TIME I
GO GROCERY SHOPPING
I
ALWAYS ASK
IF ANYONE WANTS
ME TO PICK SOMETHING
UP FOR THEM
AS
LONG AS THEY PAY
ME BACK AND
THEY ALWAYS SAY
NO SUDDENLY
THOUGH
MY
FRIDGE BECAME
FAIR GAME
THE MOMENT IT
WAS CONVENIENT FOR
THEM I
DON'T MIND HELPING
IN A REAL EMERGENCY
BUT
FORGETTING YOUR
WALLET AND
REJECTING PERFECTLY
REASONABLE
FOOD OPTIONS
DOESN'T FEEL
LIKE ONE STILL
WITH
THE WAY EVERYONE'S
REACTING I'M
LEFT WONDERING
IF STANDING MY
GROUND MADE
ME THE VILLAIN IN
MY OWN HOME