I CREATE
COMMISSIONED ARTWORK
AND ACCEPT PROJECTS
FROM A WIDE
VARIETY OF
CLIENTS.
AS
LONG AS THE SUBJECT
ISN'T HATEFUL,
DISCRIMINATORY,
OR SEXUALLY
EXPLICIT.
RECENTLY,
I COMPLETED
A COMMISSIONED PIECE
FEATURING CHRISTIAN
IMAGERY, AN
ORNATE CROSS,
A SAINT,
AND CALLIGRAPHED
SCRIPTURE.
THE CLIENT
WAS PLEASED WITH
THE WORK AND PAID
ME, BUT
THEN ASKED WHAT
MY FAVORITE SCRIPTURE
WAS.
I HONESTLY
SAID THAT I
DON'T REALLY HAVE
ONE, BECAUSE
I'M NOT CHRISTIAN
AND DON'T PERSONALLY
FOLLOW THE
FAITH.
THE
CLIENT BECAME
UPSET, SAYING
HE FELT MISLED
BECAUSE HE HAD
SEEN OTHER EXAMPLES
OF MY CHRISTIAN
-THEMED ARTWORK
AND ASSUMED
I
WAS A
BELIEVER.
HE ARGUED
THAT THE SPIRITUAL
VALUE OF
THE PIECE WAS DIMINISHED
SINCE IT WASN'T
CREATED WITH
FAITHFUL
INTENTION.
I EXPLAINED
THAT I CREATE
ART FOR ANYONE
REGARDLESS OF
MY PERSONAL BELIEFS
AND
THAT I'M
HAPPY TO PRODUCE
CHRISTIAN -THEMED
ARTWORK EVEN
IF I DON'T PRACTICE
THE RELIGION
MYSELF.
THIS
LEFT ME WONDERING
WHETHER I SHOULD
BE DISCLOSING
MY PERSONAL BELIEFS
WHEN COMMISSIONED
FOR RELIGIOUS
ART.
IS IT
NECESSARY TO
SHARE MY FAITH
IN THESE
SITUATIONS?
OR IS
IT REASONABLE FOR
ME TO FOCUS ON
THE CLIENT'S VISION
WITHOUT REVEALING
MY PERSONAL
CONVICTIONS?