I'M A
WOMAN IN MY MID-THIRTIES
LIVING IN A LARGE
RUST-BELT CITY.
AND ONE
OF THE WAYS I'VE
STAYED ANCHORED
SINCE GETTING SOBER
HAS BEEN COLLECTING
HIGH-END PERFUMES.
WITH CERTAIN
BOTTLES MARKING
MAJOR MILESTONES
IN MY RECOVERY.
A FEW YEARS
AGO, I
BECAME CLOSE
WITH A WOMAN
I MET THROUGH A
SOBRIETY SUPPORT
GROUP.
AND WE
BONDED OVER
FRAGRANCE INSTEAD
OF ALCOHOL.
TALKING ENDLESSLY
ABOUT BRANDS
LIKE BYREDO,
MAISON
FRANCIS KIRKJOHN,
AND DEPTIQUE.
OVER TIME,
SHE STARTED
ASKING IF
I COULD DECANT
SMALL AMOUNTS
OF MY PERFUMES
FOR HER. AND
MOST OF THE TIME
I DIDN'T MIND
AT ALL, SINCE
FRAGRANCE EXPIRES
AND I HAD MORE
THAN I COULD EVER
REASONABLY USE.
THE ONE
EXCEPTION WAS
A BOTTLE OF
MAISON MARGIELA
REPLICA JAZZ
CLUB, WHICH
I BOUGHT TO CELEBRATE
MY
FIRST FULL YEAR
SOBER AND
WHICH, FOR
ME, IS
INSEPARABLE FROM
SURVIVING WITHDRAWAL,
REBUILDING MY
LIFE, AND
LEARNING HOW TO
EXIST WITHOUT
ALCOHOL.
WHEN SHE
ASKED FOR THAT
ONE, I
GENTLY DECLINED
AND SUGGESTED
SHE GRAB A
FREE SAMPLE FROM
SEPHORA OR
NORDSTROM, WHICH
SOMEHOW TURNED
INTO ACCUSATIONS
THAT I
WAS BEING CONTROLLING,
ELITIST, AND
AFRAID OF ANYONE
ELSE SMELLING
LIKE ME, DESPITE
THE FACT
THAT I'D SHARED NEARLY
EVERY OTHER
SCENT I OWNED.
SHE EVENTUALLY
APOLOGIZED
AND I ACCEPTED,
BUT AFTER
THAT I BEGAN NOTICING
THE WARM,
SMOKY
SCENT LINGERING
IN MY BEDROOM
AFTER SHE VISITED,
AND LATER
UNMISTAKABLY
ON HER CLOTHES
WHEN WE MET,
EVEN THOUGH
SHE INSISTED
IT CAME FROM
A SAMPLE. I
SLOWLY DISTANCED
MYSELF, BUT
MONTHS LATER,
DURING A
CROWDED AUTUMN GATHERING
AT MY APARTMENT,
SHE DISAPPEARED
INTO THE BATHROOM
ROOM FOR AN UNUSUALLY
LONG TIME
AND WHEN
I FOLLOWED THE
SMELL I
REALIZED MY
JAZZ CLUB
BOTTLE WAS
GONE FROM MY
DRESSER WHAT
FOLLOWED WAS
A PUBLIC HUMILIATING
CONFRONTATION THAT
ENDED WITH HER ADMITTING
SHE'D BEEN SECRETLY
FILLING TRAVEL
ATOMIZERS
FROM MY BOTTLE
BECAUSE SHE WAS
STRESSED STRUGGLING
AND
FOUND THE SCENT
COMFORTING MINIMIZING
IT AS
JUST PERFUME
WHILE THE
BOTTLE IN HER BAG
WAS VISIBLY
EMPTIER NOW
OUR MUTUAL FRIENDS
KEEP URGING ME
TO FORGIVE HER
FRAMING
IT AS A TRAUMA-DRIVEN
LAPSE TIED
TO ADDICTION AND
INSISTING I'M
BEING HARSH IF
I DON'T LET IT
GO BUT
I CAN'T
SHAKE THE FEELING
THAT SHE CHOSE
THAT SPECIFIC BOTTLE
PRECISELY BECAUSE
OF WHAT IT MEANT
TO ME, LEAVING
ME WONDERING WHETHER
STANDING MY
GROUND MAKES
ME HEARTLESS
OR WHETHER FORGIVENESS
STOPS BEING
AUTOMATIC WHEN
SOMEONE KNOWINGLY
STEALS A SYMBOL
OF YOUR SURVIVAL.