IN MY
EARLY 30S
AND PREPARING FOR
A 2029
WEDDING
IN A SMALL
COASTAL TOWN
IN NEW ZEALAND,
MY
FIANCÉ
AND I HAVE KEPT
A STEADY PEACE
WITH BOTH
OF OUR
FAMILIES.
EXCEPT
FOR ONE
CORNER OF
IT.
MY OLDER
SISTER, MARA,
FIVE YEARS
MY SENIOR,
HAS A
HISTORY OF
UNDERMINING
THE VERY PEOPLE
WHO HELP HER,
AND THERE
ARE MORE EXAMPLES
THAN I CAN
COUNT.
AT OUR
ENGAGEMENT GATHERING
THIS PAST
SPRING, SHE
AND HER PARTNER,
LEO, MADE
A SPECTACLE
OF TOSSING
AROUND COMMENTS
ABOUT HOW
MARRIAGE IS
A FINANCIAL
TRAP,
INSISTING
WE WE
SHOULD JUST
LIVE TOGETHER
INDEFINITELY
INSTEAD OF
SIGNING
ANYTHING.
THEIR ONLY
GIFT,
WHICH WE
DIDN'T EXPECT
GIFTS ANYWAY,
WAS A
COMPILATION OF
BREAKUP
BALLADS.
IT WAS
MEANT AS A
JOKE, APPARENTLY,
THOUGH IT
FELT MORE LIKE
A PERFORMANCE FOR
OUR
PARENTS.
MONTHS
LATER, WHILE
PLANNING THE
HOLIDAY VISIT,
MARA,
WHO HASN'T
JOINED A FAMILY
HOLIDAY IN
NEARLY A DECADE,
ANNOUNCED
SHE WANTED
FINANCIAL HELP
AND REMARKED
THAT ANYONE WHO
CAN THROW MONEY
AT A WEDDING
SHOULD
BE GRATEFUL
TO SUPPORT
US.
SHE ALSO
INSISTED
THAT EVERYONE
START ADDRESSING
HER BY
LEO'S
LAST
NAME EVEN
THOUGH THEIR COUNTRY
DOESN'T RECOGNIZE
INFORMAL PARTNERSHIPS
AND SHE
HASN'T CHANGED
ANYTHING LEGALLY
SHE
USES HIS
NAME ON SOCIAL
PLATFORMS
AT
HER OFFICE
AND
EVEN SIGNS
EMAILS WITH
IT SO
ONE WOULD ASSUME
SHE HAD EVERYTHING
LINED UP
BEHIND THE
SCENES TRYING
TO BE GENEROUS
ESPECIALLY
BECAUSE
SOME OF THE
MONEY WOULD SUPPORT
MY NIECE'S
SWIM LESSONS
I
SENT HER A
CHECK ADDRESSED
EXACTLY
AS SHE
REQUESTED USING
LEO'S
SURNAME RATHER
THAN HER LEGAL
ONE.
PREDICTABLY,
A BANK
REJECTED IT,
APPARENTLY.
FINANCIAL
INSTITUTIONS
STILL
REQUIRE ACTUAL
LEGAL NAMES
TO PROCESS
CHECKS.
NOW
SHE'S FURIOUS,
CLAIMING
I DID IT
INTENTIONALLY TO
HUMILIATE
HER.
I DIDN'T,
I TRULY
THOUGHT I
WAS RESPECTING
HER
PREFERENCE.
OF COURSE,
I'LL RESEND
THE MONEY USING
HER REAL
NAME.
I CARE
ABOUT MY
NIECE, AND
I'M NOT INTERESTED
IN NEEDLESS
CONFLICT.
BUT I
CAN'T HELP WONDERING,
WAS I
WRONG FOR
FOLLOWING HER
INSTRUCTIONS TO
THE LETTER, EVEN
WHEN HER OWN
STORY DIDN'T
MATCH
REALITY?