I'M
A WOMAN IN
MY EARLY 20S,
AND
FOR MY MILESTONE
BIRTHDAY THIS
YEAR, MY
MOTHER PROMISED
ME A
TRIP.
WE STARTED
TALKING ABOUT
IT MONTHS IN
ADVANCE, TOSSING
AROUND IDEAS
AND DATES,
AND
EVENTUALLY SETTLED
ON A WINTER
GETAWAY TO
A SOUTHERN STATE
RIGHT BEFORE
THE
HOLIDAYS.
SHE
PUSHED FOR IT
TO FALL DURING
CHRISTMAS ITSELF,
CALLING
IT A SPECIAL
HOLIDAY
EXPERIENCE,
SO I AGREED,
EVEN
THOUGH IT MEANT
REARRANGING
WORK WORK AND
PLANS.
BY
THAT POINT,
I HAD ALREADY
MOVED OUT
AND WAS LIVING
WITH MY
PARTNER.
WE BOTH
WORK FULL
TIME, AND
FOR WEEKS WE
PUSHED OURSELVES
HARD.
EXTRA SIDE
JOBS, LATE
NIGHTS, NO
DAYS OFF,
SPECIFICALLY
TO AFFORD
THIS
TRIP.
I REQUESTED
THE TIME
OFF WELL IN
ADVANCE, COUNTED
DOWN THE DAYS,
AND TALKED
ABOUT IT
CONSTANTLY.
MY MOTHER
KNEW HOW IMPORTANT
IT WAS TO
ME AND HOW
MUCH EFFORT I
WAS PUTTING
IN.
THE
PLANS SHIFTED
REPEATEDLY OVER
THE MONTHS,
ALWAYS
AT HER DIRECTION,
BUT I STAYED
FLEXIBLE.
THEN, OUT
OF NOWHERE, I
GOT A CALL
FROM A SIBLING
ASKING IF
I KNEW THE TRIP
WAS
OFF.
I
DIDN'T.
THAT'S HOW
I FOUND
OUT.
MY MOTHER
HADN'T CALLED
ME.
SHE TOLD
ONE SIBLING,
WHO TOLD
ANOTHER, AND
IT SOMEHOW MADE
ITS WAY TO
ME
LAST.
WHEN I
CONFRONTED HER,
SHE SAID
EVERYTHING WAS
UP IN THE
AIR BECAUSE
OF FAMILY
STRESS, RELATIONSHIP
PROBLEMS,
MONEY ISSUES,
AND THE FACT
THAT NOT EVERYONE
COULD
ATTEND.
SOME
RELATIVES LIVE
OUT OF STATE
NOW, AND
SUDDENLY THAT
MEANT THE ENTIRE
TRIP NO
LONGER MADE
SENSE TO
HER.
NO
APOLOGY,
NO DIRECT
CONVERSATION,
JUST A
QUIET CANCELLATION
THAT SOMEHOW
SKIPPED THE
ONE PERSON
THE TRIP WAS
SUPPOSEDLY
FOR.
BY
THEN, I'D
ALREADY TAKEN
THE TIME OFF,
SAVED
THE MONEY, AND
EMOTIONALLY
COMMITTED
TO
GOING.
SO I
MADE A
DECISION.
I WENT
ANYWAY, JUST
NOT WITH
HER.
I WENT
WITH MY
PARTNER.
NOW
MY MOTHER
IS FURIOUS,
ACCUSING
ME OF
ABANDONING
THE FAMILY AND
CHOOSING A
TRIP OVER CHRISTMAS,
EVEN THOUGH
SHE WAS THE
ONE
WHO PULLED THE
RUG OUT WITHOUT
TELLING
ME.
WHAT
MAKES THIS
HARDER IS
THAT THIS ISN'T
THE FIRST TIME
SOMETHING MEANT
TO CELEBRATE
ME QUIETLY
UNRAVELED
AND TURNED INTO
SOMETHING ELSE
ENTIRELY.
I'M
LEFT FEELING
GUILTY, EXCITED,
ANGRY, AND
EXHAUSTED ALL
AT
ONCE.
WONDERING
IF I WAS SELFISH
FOR STILL
GOING, OR
IF I FINALLY
JUST STOPPED
LETTING MY
PLANS DISAPPEAR
FOR EVERYONE
ELSE'S
COMFORT.