MY
SPOUSE AND I
RECENTLY GOT
MARRIED AND
ARE BOTH CAREFUL
PLANNERS WHEN
IT COMES TO MONEY.
WE
WORK STABLE JOBS,
LIVE BELOW
OUR MEANS,
AND SAVE
AGGRESSIVELY BECAUSE
WE WANT LONG-TERM
SECURITY, ESPECIALLY
BEFORE STARTING
A FAMILY. ONE
MAJOR CHALLENGE
WE'RE FACING IS
MY SPOUSE'S
SIGNIFICANT EDUCATION
DEBT, WELL
OVER SIX FIGURES,
WHICH HAS
BECOME URGENT
NOW THAT SHE'S
BEGINNING AN INTENSIVE
TRAINING PROGRAM
IN LARGE PRIVATE.
LOAN
PAYMENTS HAVE
OFFICIALLY STARTED
ARRIVING.
SEVERAL
YEARS
AGO WHEN
HER GRANDFATHER PASSED
AWAY HE
LEFT A HOME
SPLIT EVENLY
BETWEEN MY
SPOUSE AND
HER OLDER SIBLING
AT
THE TIME MY
SPOUSE WAS
LIVING HOURS AWAY
FOR SCHOOL DURING
THAT PERIOD
HER SIBLING
AND THEIR PARTNER
EFFECTIVELY TOOK
CONTROL OF
THE HOUSE THEY
REMODELED SHARED
SPACES UPGRADED
APPLIANCES
CONVERTED
ROOMS FOR
PERSONAL USE
CLAIMED
THE LARGEST BEDROOM
AND
USED ADDITIONAL
AREAS FOR
STORAGE ALL
WITHOUT MEANINGFUL
DISCUSSION WHEN
MY SPOUSE EVENTUALLY
MOVED IN
SHE WAS
GIVEN A SMALL
BEDROOM AND
SHARED ACCESS TO
A SINGLE BATHROOM.
DESPITE
OWNING HALF
THE PROPERTY, ONCE
WE BECAME SERIOUS,
WE TALKED
OPENLY ABOUT
FINANCES
AND AGREED THAT
SINCE MY SPOUSE
WOULD BE MOVING
OUT TO LIVE WITH
ME, THE
MOST REASONABLE
SOLUTION WAS
FOR HER SIBLING
TO BUY OUT
HER SHARE OF THE HOUSE.
WE
COMMUNICATED THIS
CLEARLY LAST
SUMMER AND
GAVE THEM SEVERAL
MONTHS TO PREPARE
FINANCIALLY.
THEY
ACKNOWLEDGED THE
REQUEST AND
SAID THEY NEEDED TIME.
SHORTLY AFTER,
THEY CHOSE
TO PURCHASE A
NEWER VEHICLE
THEY DIDN'T
STRICTLY NEED,
WHICH MADE
US QUESTION
HOW SERIOUSLY
THEY WERE TAKING
THE SITUATION.
SIX MONTHS HAVE
PASSED, AND
WITH LOAN BILLS
NOW DUE, WE
REACHED OUT AGAIN
TO PUSH THE
PROCESS FORWARD.
INSTEAD OF
PROGRESS, HER
SIBLINGS SUGGESTED
THIS SHOULD
BE HANDLED PRIVATELY
BETWEEN SISTERS,
EXCLUDING SPOUSES
ENTIRELY.
THAT DIDN'T
SIT RIGHT WITH EITHER
OF US. SINCE
THE FINANCIAL CONSEQUENCES
DIRECTLY AFFECT
OUR HOUSEHOLD,
WE'RE COMPLETELY
ALIGNED ON
THIS AND FEEL
IT'S UNREASONABLE TO
SHUT ONE OF US
OUT.
GIVEN THE
LACK OF MOVEMENT
AND THE DISMISSIVE
TONE OF RECENT
MESSAGES, WE'RE
NOW CONSIDERING
TAKING FORMAL
STEPS.
THAT COULD
INCLUDE GIVING PROPER
PROPER NOTICE UNDER
LOCAL LAW
AND, IF
NECESSARY, FORCING
A SALE THROUGH
LEGAL CHANNELS.
IF IT
COMES TO THAT,
WE WOULD ALSO
PURSUE COMPENSATION
TIED
TO EXCLUSIVE USE
OF THE SHARED PROPERTY,
WHICH
COULD SIGNIFICANTLY
REDUCE OR
EVEN ELIMINATE
THE MOST PRESSING
DEBTS WE'RE FACING.
WE DON'T
WANT TO DISRUPT ANYONE'S
LIFE UNNECESSARILY,
BUT WE ALSO
FEEL WE'VE BEEN
PATIENT, CLEAR,
AND FAIR.
AT THIS POINT,
PROTECTING
OUR FINANCIAL
STABILITY FEELS
UNAVOIDABLE
IF NOTHING CHANGES.
WOULD WE BE
WRONG FOR MOVING
FORWARD WITH
THIS, EVEN
IF IT FORCES
A MAJOR CHANGE
FOR THEM?