I'M LOOKING
FOR A QUICK JUDGMENT
ON WHETHER MY
REACTION WAS
UNREASONABLE.
THIS MIGHT
SOUND SMALL,
BUT IT REALLY
BOTHERED
ME.
FOR YEARS,
BASICALLY SINCE
WE STARTED DATING,
I'VE BEEN RECOMMENDING
A SHOW I
LOVE, WHICH
I'LL CALL RIDGEWOOD
SISTERS, TO
MY
HUSBAND.
I EVEN
SHOWED HIM
CLIPS.
AND EVERY
TIME HE'D POLITELY
DECLINE.
THAT WAS
FINE WITH
ME.
I KNOW NOT
EVERYONE ENJOYS
THE SAME
THINGS.
I'VE WATCHED
THE SERIES TWICE
DURING OUR
RELATIONSHIP.
ALWAYS ON
MY OWN BECAUSE
HE WAS NEVER
INTERESTED.
INTERESTED LAST
NIGHT WE WERE
AT A FAMILY GATHERING
WITH A LOT OF
HIS RELATIVES INCLUDING
A COUSIN
HE'S REALLY CLOSE
TO TODAY
WHILE
WE WERE WATCHING
TV HE
OPENED OUR STREAMING
APP SEARCHED
FOR RIDGEWOOD
SISTERS AND
SAID HIS COUSIN
TOLD HIM THAT
HIS PARTNER GOT
HIM HOOKED ON
THE SHOW AND NOW
IT'S HIS GUILTY
PLEASURE
I
HONESTLY THOUGHT
MY HUSBAND WAS
JOKING I
POINTED OUT
THAT I HAD RECOMMENDED
THE SHOW SO
MANY TIMES
AND HE NEVER CARED
BUT
SUDDENLY HIS
COUSIN MENTIONING
IT MADE IT WORTH
CRYING HE
LOOKED CONFUSED
AND ASKED
ARE YOU
SURE THIS IS
THE SAME SHOW
WHICH
MADE ME EVEN
MORE
FRUSTRATED.
I REMINDED
HIM I HAD WATCHED
IT TWICE SINCE
WE'D BEEN TOGETHER
AND THAT HE NEVER
WANTED TO JOIN
ME.
I TOLD
HIM HE COULD WATCH
IT ON HIS OWN
NOW AND WENT
TO OUR
ROOM.
I HEARD
HIM PLAY THE SHOW
FOR ABOUT A MINUTE
BEFORE SWITCHING
TO SOMETHING
ELSE.
I KNOW
IT'S A SMALL SITUATION,
BUT I STILL
FEEL
STUNG.
WAS MY
REACTION
UNREASONABLE?