I'M 39,
MY WIFE
IS 38, AND
WE'VE LIVED IN
OUR CURRENT NEIGHBORHOOD
FOR ALMOST
A
DECADE.
WE'RE CLOSE
WITH THE PEOPLE ON
OUR STREET, ESPECIALLY
THE COUPLE
NEXT DOOR,
WHO TREAT
OUR TWO KIDS,
AND 2, LIKE
EXTENDED FAMILY,
FOR
YEARS.
THEY'VE JOINED
US FOR CHRISTMAS
DINNER BECAUSE
THEY DON'T HAVE
RELATIVES
NEARBY.
AND IT'S
ALWAYS BEEN A
COMFORTABLE
TRADITION.
UNTIL RECENTLY,
OUR NEIGHBOR,
WHO I'LL
CALL CAROL, HAS
A HABIT OF
GOING OVERBOARD
WITH HOLIDAY
GIFTS.
SHE ASKS
EVERYONE WHAT
THEY WANT AND
THEN IGNORES
IT COMPLETELY, CONVINCED
SHE KNOWS PEOPLE
BETTER THAN
THEY KNOW
THEMSELVES.
SHE ALSO
TENDS TO FIXATE
ON ONE IDEA
AND
REPEAT IT
ENDLESSLY.
ONE YEAR MY
WIFE CASUALLY
MENTIONED LIKING
SCENTED CANDLES,
AND CAROL
HAS GIVEN HER
A MOUNTAIN OF THEM
EVERY CHRISTMAS
SINCE.
DESPITE
MY WIFE DONATING
MOST OF
THEM BECAUSE THE
SMELL GIVES HER
HEADACHES.
THAT
KIND OF THING WAS
HARMLESS ENOUGH,
BUT CAROL
GETS STRANGELY
COMPETITIVE WITH
GIFT
GIVING.
IF SOMEONE
RECEIVES SOMETHING
THEY'RE EXCITED
ABOUT.
SHE IMMEDIATELY
SWOOPS
IN WITH A BIGGER,
BETTER ITEM
TO OUTSHINE
IT.
IT BECAME
A RUNNING JOKE
BETWEEN SOME
OF THE NEIGHBORS, BUT
IT STOPPED BEING
FUNNY WHEN
IT STARTED AFFECTING
OUR
KIDS.
WE ALWAYS
KEEP CHRISTMAS MORNING
JUST FOR OUR
LITTLE FAMILY,
AND THEN
WE HAVE PEOPLE
OVER
LATER.
TWO YEARS AGO,
OUR SON WAS
UNBELIEVABLY HAPPY
ABOUT THE TRAIN
SET HE GOT FROM
SANTA.
WHEN CAROL
CAME OVER THAT
EVENING,
SHE SEEMED
BOTHERED THAT HE
WASN'T INSTANTLY
PLAYING WITH
THE TOYS SHE
BROUGHT.
SHE KEPT
INTERRUPTING HIM
AND NUDGING HER
GIFTS IN FRONT
OF
HIM.
AND
AT ONE POINT
I FOUND THE TRAIN
CONTROLLER TUCKED
BEHIND HER COAT
ON A
CHAIR.
I HONESTLY
DON'T KNOW IF
SHE HID IT ON
PURPOSE OR
SET IT DOWN
ABSENTMINDEDLY.
BUT IT
WAS WEIRD, LAST
YEAR, WHEN
WE TOLD OUR SON
THAT CAROL AND
HER HUSBAND WERE
ON THEIR
WAY.
HE QUIETLY
PUT AWAY ALL
HIS NEW TOYS
IN HIS
CLOSET.
WHEN I ASKED
HIM WHY, HE
WHISPERED,
I DON'T WANT
HER TO TAKE
THEM.
THAT WAS
THE MOMENT MY
WIFE AND I
REALIZED SOMETHING
NEEDED TO
CHANGE.
THIS YEAR,
WE DECIDED
IT WOULD BE BEST
IF CAROL AND
HER HUSBAND CAME
FOR DINNER AND
TIME WITH THE
KIDS.
BUT
WITHOUT BRINGING
GIFTS WE
WANT OUR KIDS
TO ENJOY THEIR
THINGS WITHOUT
FEELING RUSHED
JUDGED
OR OVERWHELMED
WE
TOLD THEM THIS
DURING A CASUAL
VISIT A
FEW WEEKS AGO
CAROL
IMMEDIATELY GOT
UPSET SAYING
WE WERE ROBBING
HER OF THE JOY
OF GIVING AND
EXCLUDING HER
FROM CHRISTMAS
SHE
EVEN SAID MAYBE
THEY JUST SHOULDN'T
COME AT ALL WE
TRIED TO EXPLAIN
IT WASN'T ABOUT
EXCLUDING HER
IT
WAS ABOUT KEEPING
THE DAY PEACEFUL
FOR OUR KIDS
BUT
SHE SHUT DOWN
AND BARELY SPOKE
TO US ON HER
WAY OUT NOW
MY WIFE IS
FEELING GUILTY
AND
THE WHOLE SITUATION
HAS GOTTEN
TENSE I
DON'T THINK WE WERE
UNREASONABLE BUT
CAROL CLEARLY
THINKS WE
WERE OUT OF LINE
WERE
WE WRONG TO
SET THAT BOUNDARY