I'M
IN MY MID
-TWENTIES,
WORKING
LONG, EXHAUSTING
SHIFTS,
AND FOOD
IS ALREADY A
STRUGGLE FOR
ME.
I ONLY
HAVE A HANDFUL
OF MEALS
I CAN RELIABLY
EAT,
AND WHEN
I FIND ONE
THAT FEELS RIGHT,
I PLAN MY
ENTIRE DAY
AROUND
IT.
I'VE
MADE THIS CLEAR
TO MY HOUSEMATE
BEFORE.
I EVEN
SET A VERY
CLEAR
RULE.
IF SOMETHING
HAS BEEN SITTING
IN THE FRIDGE
FOR ALMOST
A WEEK,
IT'S
FAIR
GAME.
ANYTHING NEWER
THAN THAT IS
OFF
-LIMITS.
ON
THIS PARTICULAR
DAY, I
WENT COMPLETELY
OUT OF MY
WAY BETWEEN
SHIFTS TO
GRAB A LEMON
CHICKEN DISH
FROM MY FAVORITE
SPOT ACROSS
TOWN
IT
WASN'T
CHEAP.
IT WASN'T
CONVENIENT AND
I WAS ALREADY
EXHAUSTED,
BUT
I WAS GENUINELY
EXCITED TO
EAT IT LATER
I
ATE A SMALL
PORTION
PACKED
UP MORE THAN
HALF LABELED
IT AND
PUT IT IN
THE FRIDGE BEFORE
RUSHING BACK
TO WORK
I
SPENT THE REST
OF MY SHIFT
THINKING ABOUT
COMING HOME
TO THAT MEAL
WHEN
I FINALLY
GOT BACK LATE
THAT NIGHT,
I IMMEDIATELY
NOTICED
SOMETHING WAS
OFF ONE
OF MY TWO
-DAY -OLD SNACKS
WAS SITTING
OUT ON MY
HOUSEMATE'S
DESK HALF
EATEN
I
SAID SOMETHING
REMINDING
THEM I
WAS PLANNING TO
EAT IT THE NEXT
DAY AND
THEY BRUSHED ME
OFF SAYING
IT WAS OLD
ANYWAY THAT'S
WHEN I OPENED
THE FRIDGE AND
REALIZED THE
LEMON CHICKEN
WAS COMPLETELY
GONE WHEN
I ASKED ABOUT
IT THEY
CASUALLY TOLD
ME THEY ATE
IT NO
WARNING NO
MESSAGE NO
HESITATION THIS
WAS DESPITE
THE FACT
THAT THERE WAS
STILL PLENTY
OF OTHER FOOD
IN THE FRIDGE
THEY'D ALREADY
HELPED
THEMSELVES EARLIER
I
TRIED EXPLAINING
THAT I HAD
JUST BOUGHT THAT
MEAL THAT
I'D BEEN SAVING
IT AFTER A
BRUTAL SHIFT
AND
THAT I NOW DIDN'T
HAVE DINNER AT
ALL I
WAS MET WITH
A SHRUG
LATER
AFTER
I STEPPED
OUT TO COOL
DOWN I
GOT A TEXT
SAYING THEY'D
REPLACE IT
SOMETIME NO
APOLOGY
NO
ACKNOWLEDGEMENT
OF HOW UPSETTING
IT WAS
JUST
A VAGUE PROMISE
WHILE
I STOOD THERE
HUNGRY TIRED
AND
FURIOUS STARING
AT AN EMPTY
FRIDGE WHERE
THE ONE THING
I COULD ACTUALLY
EAT HAD BEEN
NOW
THE HOUSE FEELS
TENSE AND
I'M BEING TREATED
LIKE I OVERREACTED
BUT
I GENUINELY
FEEL LIKE
SOMETHING IMPORTANT
WAS
CROSSED.