I SHARE
PARENTING DUTIES
WITH MY PARTNER.
AND WE
ALTERNATE MORNINGS
GETTING OUR
CHILD READY FOR
SCHOOL.
INCLUDING PACKING
LUNCHES.
ON THE DAYS
IT'S MY TURN.
I SOMETIMES
SLIP A
SMALL HANDWRITTEN
NOTE INTO THE
LUNCH BAG. THEY'RE
NOTHING ELABORATE.
JUST QUIET
LITTLE MESSAGES
ABOUT A BOOK
WE'RE READING TOGETHER.
A PLAN
FOR THE WEEKEND.
OR A SIMPLE
REMINDER THAT
I'M PROUD AND
THINKING ABOUT THEM.
IT'S BECOME
A SOFT,
PRIVATE RITUAL
THAT FEELS VERY
MINE.
SOMETHING TENDER
I DO WITHOUT
ANNOUNCEMENT OR
EXPECTATION.
ONE MORNING,
MY PARTNER
HAPPENED TO WALK
IN WHILE I WAS
WRITING ONE OF
THESE NOTES. HE
PAUSED, WATCHED
FOR A SECOND,
AND THEN ASKED
IF I COULD START
SIGNING THEM
FROM BOTH OF
US INSTEAD OF
JUST ME. I
TOLD HIM, GENTLY,
THAT I'D RATHER
NOT.
I EXPLAINED
THAT THIS WASN'T
MEANT TO BE A SHARED
STATEMENT OR
A FAMILY ANNOUNCEMENT.
IT WAS
JUST A PERSONAL
MESSAGE.
I ADDED
THAT IF HE WANTED
TO WRITE HIS OWN
NOTES ON HIS
DAYS.
I THOUGHT
THAT WOULD BE LOVELY.
I EVEN
SLID A SCRAP
OF PAPER ACROSS
THE COUNTER TO
MAKE THE POINT
THAT I WASN'T STOPPING
HIM FROM DOING
ANYTHING SIMILAR.
THAT'S WHEN THINGS
SHIFTED.
EAST DIFFIN
SAID HE
SHOULDN'T HAVE TO
WRITE HIS OWN NOTE
AND ACCUSED
ME OF SHUTTING
HIM OUT. HE
COMPARED IT
TO EXCLUDING HIM
FROM SIGNING HOLIDAY
CARDS OR
CLAIMING GIFTS
AS MINE ALONE.
HIS VOICE
ROSE, FRUSTRATION
SPILLING
OUT AS HE INSISTED
IT WAS THE SAME
THING.
TO ME,
IT DIDN'T
FEEL THE SAME AT
ALL.
THIS WASN'T
A PUBLIC GESTURE
OR A SHARED
MILESTONE, JUST
A QUIET MOMENT
OF CONNECTION. THE
ARGUMENT LINGERED
IN THE AIR LONG
AFTER BREAKFAST
WAS OVER.
I WAS LEFT
WONDERING WHETHER
PROTECTING THIS
TINY, PERSONAL
TRADITION MADE
ME SELFISH.
OR WHETHER
IT'S OKAY FOR
EACH PARENT TO
HAVE THEIR OWN WAYS
OF SHOWING LOVE
INSTEAD OF
MERGING EVERYTHING
INTO A
SINGLE SIGNATURE.